<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 15:48:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 15:48:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AI%202%20copy%20(002).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Technology Can Reflect Human Bias—And Resources to Understand It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With each technological advancement, more decisions in our daily lives are made by algorithms. They increasingly determine what advertisements we see, whether we’re considered for a job, or which books and movies are recommended to us—and how and where law enforcement is deployed in our communities. The ongoing protests to draw attention to, and eradicate, systemic racism in the United States, and in other parts of the world, have made clear something we already knew—humans are biased. Because we are biased, the technology we create is biased, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next several months DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration will explore this topic by trying to answer the following questions (and more) in a new series: How pervasive is algorithmic bias, and which platforms are the worst offenders? (b) How does algorithmic bias work, and how we can tackle it at a technological level? (c) What other responses—policy, digital literacy, and so on—exist to tackle this phenomenon? (d) What are the effects of algorithmic bias on the broader digital development sector?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 08:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Center for Digital Acceleration Staff
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/understanding-algorithmic-bias.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/understanding-algorithmic-bias.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/lock.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Importance of Personal Digital Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the current climate of data collection and data harvesting by every website, company, government or official body that has access to your browser traffic, usage history, and location, your data is always at risk and vulnerable. To add to this, nothing is absolutely, unequivocally, 100 percent secure. Even air-gapped computers that have no connection to the internet, as demonstrated with the CIA-infected Iranian centrifuges with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/11/countdown-to-zero-day-stuxnet/&quot;&gt;Stuxnet&lt;/a&gt; are vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did that sound alarmist? Well, it was meant to be. The good thing is there are simple measures that anyone from web and software developers to computer laypersons can take to protect themselves from the inevitable breach of their data. The more aware we are and the more precautions we take to avoid exposing our “IRL”-selves to the ever-present threats, the better our chances are of staying secure.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/personal-digital-security-the-beginning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/personal-digital-security-the-beginning.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/COVID%20blog%20image.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 6: Insights from Forecasting COVID-19 Transmission Rates In Mexico with Google Mobility Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This analysis is Part 6 of a series on COVID-19, with a specific focus on Mexico. The analysis will be updated as we receive additional data and the code for all related analysis will be made available shortly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two months, COVID-19 has made its way beyond the borders of the United States and into other countries of the Americas, namely the second and third largest countries of the region: Brazil and Mexico. While the United States’ daily incidence of deaths slowly declines, Mexico reported its largest daily incidence yet with 1,092 deaths on June 4.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 14:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/forecasting-covid-19-transmission-using-google-mobility.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/forecasting-covid-19-transmission-using-google-mobility.html</guid>
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com" medium="image" /> 
        <title>This Week</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear friends and colleagues: we had a lighthearted blog post ready to go this week, but in light of recent events, we’re sure it can wait. Instead, we’re using this time to pause and reflect about the killing of George Floyd and the years of structural racism and inequities that his story represents, both in the U.S. and across the countries where DAI works. We’re also thinking about cities and communities reeling from a combination of a global pandemic and widespread unrest. In the meantime, take care and stay strong.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 20:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Center for Digital Acceleration Staff
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/this-week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/this-week.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Talia-blog-CDAteam.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Collaboration: Recommendations from a Six-Week Veteran</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I have been reading article after article about how to run a successful virtual workshop, training, event, and so on, all of which provided useful advice. But, as I have run my fair share of virtual meetings these days, and because I am often described as “direct” by my peers and colleagues, I thought I would take a stab at making my own list of to-the-point recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/hosting-virtual-meetings-recommendations-from-a-six-week-veteran.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/hosting-virtual-meetings-recommendations-from-a-six-week-veteran.html</guid>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>Virtual Workshops</category>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1200px-Yunsup_Lee_holding_RISC_V_prototype_chip.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Castles Made of Sand: Digital Transformation From the Silicon Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Silicon chips are literally black boxes to most of us. We understand that transistors are somehow etched in tiny patterns on these silicon wafers, and that these patterns make possible the computers, phones, and other electronic devices that run our modern world. Digital solutions are built on a foundation of silicon, and the landscape of silicon chip production is changing in ways that could have far-reaching impact on how that foundation is laid, and by whom.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/castles-made-of-sand-digital-transformation-from-the-silicon-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/castles-made-of-sand-digital-transformation-from-the-silicon-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>Makerspace</category>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Capture-df7c9a.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Interview: Talking Financial Inclusion with MIX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We recently spoke with Nikhil Gehani, Director of Communications at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themix.org/&quot;&gt;MIX&lt;/a&gt;, a global data resource for socially responsible investors and businesses, about inclusive finance and what it means for low-income countries. This is an excerpt of that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 14:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Digital@DAI Team
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-interview-talking-financial-inclusion-with-mix.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-interview-talking-financial-inclusion-with-mix.html</guid>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/photo-1585411241969-9ac0c565451b-a68beb.webp" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Privacy: How COVID-19 Has Sped Up the Debate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As many countries struggle to manage the COVID-19 crisis, governments globally are looking to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-30/the-world-embraces-contact-tracing-technology-to-fight-covid-19?utm_campaign=The%20Interface&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue%20newsletter&quot;&gt;data-driven technologies&lt;/a&gt; to minimize cases or to help facilitate a transition out of lockdown. The technologies being claimed to protect, prevent, and track include &lt;a href=&quot;corona.asan.gov.af&quot;&gt;symptom tracking apps&lt;/a&gt; that help us understand the disease, digital contact tracing apps that alert us to our interaction with the virus, quarantine enforcement apps that monitor people’s compliance (such as those in Hong Kong, Poland, and Kazakhstan; proposed in Russia and Egypt), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ukauthority.com/articles/open-university-develops-digital-certificate-for-covid-19-immunity/&quot;&gt;immunity certification&lt;/a&gt; that identify individuals who have had COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In more developed nations such as the United Kingdom and United States, conversations around data privacy are rife. For example, the UK National Health Service (NHS) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-52441428&quot;&gt;negotiating&lt;/a&gt; with Google and Apple about the efficacy of its proposed contact-tracing app in light of the two tech giants’ stringent adherence to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the face of serious threats, many of us might say we have a reasonable expectation that our government will use technology to track and pre-empt risks. In the same way we might expect protection from terrorist attacks, we may also accept such measures to be employed during a public health crisis like the current pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the vital question is: how can we ensure that the deployment of these digital tools are effective and do not set a dangerous precedent of digital surveillance?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 05:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/privacy-how-much-should-we-be-willing-to-give-up-in-a-covid-19-era.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/privacy-how-much-should-we-be-willing-to-give-up-in-a-covid-19-era.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fig8_cfr-0d2f6a.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 5: Different Models of Infection Rates in Mexico and What they Tell Us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenges of measuring the infection rates of COVID-19 are enormous for even the most prepared countries, given the need for testing to reach a significant enough amount of the population to accurately detect its spread. While the total number of recorded cases in the world thus far have mostly been in the United States, Europe, and East Asia, many low- and middle-income countries have begun to see increases in reported cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mexico, the number of cases has slowly risen. Public health experts have &lt;a href=&quot;https://mexiconewsdaily.com/news/coronavirus/experts-say-mexico-hasnt-done-enough-virus-testing/&quot;&gt;urgently suggested&lt;/a&gt; that testing needs to be dramatically increased to appropriately track the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic. As the graph below shows, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/#countries&quot;&gt;numbers reported from Worldometer&lt;/a&gt; corroborate this testing deficit, as Mexico has one of the lowest rates of testing per 1 million people in the region, even among countries of similar size and income per capita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fig1_testingpercap-c8bcbb.png&quot; alt=&quot;fig1_testingpercap-c8bcbb.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-part-5-different-methods-to-model-infection-rates-in-mexico-and-what-they-tell-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-part-5-different-methods-to-model-infection-rates-in-mexico-and-what-they-tell-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>5 Ways Entrepreneurship Ecosystems are Using Technology to Adapt to the COVID-19 Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During this unprecedented global economic downturn caused by COVID-19, accelerators, incubators, and other entrepreneurship support organizations have a valuable role to play in helping entrepreneurs and small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in emerging and frontier markets. Over the past two months supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-shell-livewire-global-consultancy&quot;&gt;Shell LiveWIRE&lt;/a&gt; global entrepreneurship program and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/ghana-kosmos-innovation-center-kic&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt;, DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/sustainable-business&quot;&gt;Sustainable Business Group&lt;/a&gt; has worked closely with the Global Accelerator Network (&lt;a href=&quot;C:\\Users\\ZRaheem\\Documents\\DAI\\Sustainable Business Group (SBG)\\Brown Bag Presentations\\10 Trends Changing Entrepreneurship Ecosystems\\Blog on Entrepreneurship Trends\\gan.co&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt;) and the Aspen Network of Development Entrepreneurs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://andeglobal.org/&quot;&gt;ANDE&lt;/a&gt;) to leverage technology in support of global entrepreneurship in emerging economies. For corporates, foundations, donors, and development banks that support similar entrepreneurship ecosystems, we offer some learning here from our projects and global networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo by Oscar Nilsson on Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/zaki-raheem">Zaki Raheem</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/doug-mclean">Doug McLean</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-ways-entrepreneurship-ecosystems-are-using-technology-to-adapt-to-the-covid-19-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-ways-entrepreneurship-ecosystems-are-using-technology-to-adapt-to-the-covid-19-crisis.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
