<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 13:24:50 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 13:24:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ICTforAg%20By%20the%20Numbers.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Implement the Next ICTforAg Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictforag.com/&quot;&gt;ICTforAg 2020&lt;/a&gt; engaged a global audience of 1,502 participants across 26 sessions over the course of one day. The conference examined digital solutions in agriculture as a means of fostering resilience in the wake of disruptions, from climate-related disasters to COVID-19, and the intersections between them. Building on the momentum of this global event, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; team is supporting the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-resilience-and-food-security&quot;&gt;Bureau for Resilience and Food Security&lt;/a&gt; in the next ICTforAg conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ICTforAg%20By%20the%20Numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;ICTforAg By the Numbers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-implement-the-next-ictforag-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-implement-the-next-ictforag-conference.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>RFP</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/mx_fco_6_22_fig_4.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Job Postings from Mexico's Energy Sector Reveal About the State of Clean Energy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A significant challenge to achieving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sustainable_Development_Goals&quot;&gt;Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/a&gt; has been measuring country progress in the transition to renewable and clean energy sources. While expert surveys or legislation enacted may provide some insight into how countries are progressing on the whole, they lack the granularity to inform us about subnational trends, skills in-demand, and the presence of firms and subsectors within each country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One useful way to explore these factors is by analyzing data available from job search engines and using keywords related to the energy sector. These can provide insights on how jobs in key sectors and subsectors evolve over time, what the demand for labor among firms in the energy sector is, where these openings and firms are located, and how they differ in terms of skills sought in the labor market.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/jamie-parr/">Jamie Parr</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-larios-v%C3%A1zquez-/">Andrea Guadalupe Larios Vázquez</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-p%C3%A9rez-barn%C3%A9s-2b810a1a/">Javier Pérez Barnés</a>, <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/estera-barbarasa">Estera Barbarasa</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramon-olivas/?originalSubdomain=mx">Ramon Olivas</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-can-we-learn-from-job-postings-in-the-energy-sector-evidence-from-mexico.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-can-we-learn-from-job-postings-in-the-energy-sector-evidence-from-mexico.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Environment &amp; Energy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/solomon.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Advances in ICT Connectivity Highlight Need for Digital Safety Preparedness in Pacific Communities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Pacific Islands have the lowest rate of mobile &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pacificislandtimes.com/post/2020/01/04/the-connectivity-gap-in-the-pacific&quot;&gt;internet penetration&lt;/a&gt; in the world and fixed broadband connection levels far below that of their neighbors. Recent and planned investments in building out undersea fiber optic cable and satellite services—including those financed by the United Nations, World Bank, and Asian Development Bank—are striving to change this, boosting internet speeds and expanding access to citizens, governments, and businesses across the region. In recent weeks I’ve spoken with a number of experts in the Pacific Islands about their concerns and priorities around this topic. Below are a few common themes that resonated throughout my conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Addie Ryan Tadavarthy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/ICT-Connectivity-Highlights-Need-for-Pacific-Digital-Safety-Preparedness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/ICT-Connectivity-Highlights-Need-for-Pacific-Digital-Safety-Preparedness.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Gratiana%202.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Are We Reading about Technology and Ethics?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tech ethics have continued to claim the public spotlight as more accounts of bias and harm due to technology and artificial intelligence (AI) have appeared in the media. Stories from racial bias in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-03228-6&quot;&gt;health care algorithms&lt;/a&gt; to gender bias in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/article/amazon-sexist-recruiting-algorithm-gender-bias-ai/&quot;&gt;hiring algorithms&lt;/a&gt; have uncovered the lack of neutrality in technology that has previously been assumed to be completely objective and neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-are-we-reading-about-technology-and-ethics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-are-we-reading-about-technology-and-ethics.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Satellite Imagery and ‘Light at Night’ Helps Development Practitioners Estimate GDP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sure many of you have come across a map like the one below. I find that images of our planet are always awe-inspiring and this image is certainly not an exception. I can easily get lost in satellite imagery for hours if I am not careful. Most of those images are based on visual spectrum optical technology (LandSAT, Sentinel, etc.), thus requiring daylight for the powerful digital cameras to “see.” Remote sensing satellites such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ncc.nesdis.noaa.gov/VIIRS/&quot;&gt;VIIRS&lt;/a&gt;—which DAI uses for its analysis—are equipped with special infrared equipment and able to capture beautiful images of the earth at night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o-df5bef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o-df5bef.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: NASA and DMSP.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lights-at-night-wheres-the-gdp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lights-at-night-wheres-the-gdp.html</guid>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Satellite</category>
        
        <category>Imagery</category>
        
        <category>Imagery Analysis</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Data Analysis</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Chapter%20Ambassador%20Voneat%20Pen.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking Girls in Tech with Voneat Pen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kate Heuisler recently spoke with Voneat Pen, the Chapter Ambassador for &lt;a href=&quot;https://technovationcambodia.com/&quot;&gt;Technovation&lt;/a&gt; in Cambodia, about her work growing the successful all-girl tech entrepreneurship education program for the seventh year in a row. While juggling her roles as the co-founder of the tech startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/606Digital/&quot;&gt;606&lt;/a&gt;, a programmer, and STEM advocate, Voneat has been instrumental to Technovation’s success during its most challenging years. When COVID-19 pushed the program online overnight, the Technovation community (and its partners) were still able to successfully engage new all-girl teams, mentors, schools, and provinces across the country. To date, Technovation has helped connect more than 2,000 Cambodian girls to essential 21st-century tech creator skills.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-girls-in-tech-with-voneat-pen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-girls-in-tech-with-voneat-pen.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator Series</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Krista.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Fast Company's World Changing Ideas Awards Highlight Opportunities for Digital Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fast Company magazine has been around for decades…but is it relevant for digital development work? The publication was founded in 1995 at a time when business was changing the world in new ways. Today, 26 years later, we are still coming to terms with the ways that technologies are transforming the ways we work and live—especially during the COVID-19 global pandemic. As I work with clients and projects focused on digital development, the businesses and organizations featured in Fast Company offer new ideas, inspiration, and out-of-the-box thinking to those of us heads down in global development projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I wanted to share some of the winners of Fast Company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90623897&quot;&gt;2021 World-Changing Ideas Awards&lt;/a&gt;—and how these innovations could apply to our work. World Changing Ideas is one of Fast Company’s major annual awards programs and is focused on social good, seeking to elevate finished products and brave concepts that make the world better.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/world-changing-ideas-direct-from-fast-company.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/world-changing-ideas-direct-from-fast-company.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>E-Commerce</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Inta.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New Research Explores Digital Technologies and Their Impact on Social Accountability in Southeast Asia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ian Cocroft, Karen Lee, and Connor MacKenzie are second-year master’s students in the international development program at the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS). The SAIS International Development (IDEV) practicum allows students to work directly with public, private, and nongovernmental organizations as a capstone to their graduate studies. Ian, Karen, and Connor worked with the Center for Digital Acceleration at DAI. The students conducted virtual research in Burma, Cambodia, Thailand, and Vietnam during the 2020-21 academic year to better understand how civil society organizations (CSOs) use digital technologies to support social accountability in public service delivery. The team’s final report provides DAI with considerations on how CSOs can better integrate digital technologies into their operations and highlights regional examples of digital tools for social accountability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our practicum team worked with DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration on a regional study about how CSOs in Burma, Thailand, and Vietnam use digital technologies for social accountability in public service delivery, providing a series of recommendations for the U.S. Agency for International Development-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fhi360.org/projects/innovations-social-accountability-cambodia-isac&quot;&gt;Innovations for Social Accountability in Cambodia (ISAC) program&lt;/a&gt;. As part of our research, we undertook an extensive literature review and held Zoom interviews with country representatives from CSOs, tech organizations, and multilateral institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-cocroft/">Ian Cocroft</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connor-mackenzie/">Connor Mackenzie</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karen-lee-187934123/">Karen Lee</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/idev-practicum-2021-exploring-digital-technologies-and-their-impact-on-social-accountability-in-southeast-asia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/idev-practicum-2021-exploring-digital-technologies-and-their-impact-on-social-accountability-in-southeast-asia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018-04-11-image-6.webp" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Right to Repair is a Development Issue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Who owns the device you are reading this blog post on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem like a straightforward question until a power surge fries a key circuit or a stray elbow knocks a unit to the floor. At this point, the process of repairing what you thought was your (or your employer’s) property is likely to get a bit more complicated: The device turns out to be held together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_screw_drives#Proprietary_head&quot;&gt;proprietary screws&lt;/a&gt;, contains deliberately unobtainable spare parts, has software locks that cannot be overridden without the manufacturer’s express permission, or other random features included specifically to seal you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018-04-11-image-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;2018-04-11-image-6.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: TechSpot.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</guid>
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Alana.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Support USAID Missions through Digital Agriculture Ecosystem Assessments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the incredible progress made over the last decade by the U.S. Government’s global hunger and food security &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feedthefuture.gov/&quot;&gt;Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt; program, continued shocks, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-resilience-and-food-security/responding-to-covid-19-impact-on-resilience-and-food-security&quot;&gt;COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, make the work towards a more resilient global population and improved food security more relevant than ever. COVID’s impact on food security continues to be revealed but it’s estimated that 124 million more people experienced long-lasting poverty and hunger in 2020 and that 2.6 million more children will face stunting due to the pandemic. Across the globe, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) is working to address these impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-missions-through-digital-agriculture-ecosystem-assessments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-missions-through-digital-agriculture-ecosystem-assessments.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>RFP</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
