<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 09:24:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 09:24:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Connect.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Makes This Wireless Technology (5G) Different From All Other Wireless Technologies?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When thinking about the internet in an ideal world, I often think of an independent platform that provides a mechanism for free expression, commerce, and the exchange of ideas. Yet, as more and more of the global population comes online, the internet has become a reflection of global dynamics and geopolitical undercurrents. Today, this reality is manifesting itself around the impending roll out of 5G.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-makes-this-wireless-technology-5g-different-than-all-other-wireless-technologies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-makes-this-wireless-technology-5g-different-than-all-other-wireless-technologies.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CambodiaDI_Adam.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>5 Tips for Doing International Design Research</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) relies heavily on ethnographic design research in our work. By focusing our efforts on people &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the institutions around them, we:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define the problem in their terms, not ours;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn of, and about, previous attempts to solve the problem;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop our understanding of local culture and history, as well as how people seek and share information and use mobile technology so we can meet them where they are;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitigate the risks inherent to spending limited resources developing software or building digital tools, given the costs of doing so;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build ownership of the solution among the population; and…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enlist those who participate as promoters of the solution among their personal and professional networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/New1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The author teaching design research in Phnom Penh with the USAID Cambodia Development Innovations project.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-tips-for-doing-international-design-research.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-tips-for-doing-international-design-research.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Qual360Rach.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>From One Qualie to Another: Insights from Qual360 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make: I am a bonafide, card-carrying qualie. For those of you who aren’t familiar with this term, it’s a (nerdy) colloquialism to define people who are really into qualitative research. I swear, it’s a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, I am a qualie. I have been involved in conducting qualitative, ethnographic research in some way or another throughout the course of my sinuous career. I get jazzed by learning about people’s lived experiences—the barriers they encounter when attempting to improve their health and well being; the things that make changing behavior a snap; all of it. Throw some neuroscience in there to understand what’s happening in the brain and the ways in which emotional responses catalyze behavior change? Yes. Yes, please. I am in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rachel Clad
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/from-one-qualie-to-another-insights-from-qual360-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/from-one-qualie-to-another-insights-from-qual360-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/adam%20blog%20pic%202-2754dc.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Game Mechanics—Great Tool for Designing Digital Development Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;📱 Smartphone connections continue to rise and people, globally, love to game. The Global Systems for Mobile Communications Association (GSMA) estimates that by 2025 78 percent of all developing market mobile connections &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/r/mobileeconomy/sub-saharan-africa/&quot;&gt;will be smart&lt;/a&gt;. By that time GSMA predicts that India will be the second-largest smartphone market by adoption globally (ahead of the United States), with 1 billion smartphone connections. Interestingly, India is already among the top five mobile gaming countries globally, expected to surge to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mmaglobal.com/files/casestudies/kantar_imrb_x_mma_x_pokkt_india_market_study.pdf&quot;&gt;368 million gamers in 2022&lt;/a&gt;. If this is a bellwether for developing markets, we can expect gaming to be a significant force across the global south.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adjwills/">Adam Wills</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/game-mechanics-maize-pests-and-prize-inspiration.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/game-mechanics-maize-pests-and-prize-inspiration.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID1-e80035.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Identity Series Part 1: Digital Identity and Informed Consent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital ID1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;This post marks the launch of a Digital Identity series here on Digital@DAI. It is a pivotal topic to many of our technical areas: from health service provision, to cash transfers, and voter registration. It is also a topic garnering increased attention with the debate over privacy and data security—and the global refugee crisis reinforcing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/213581486378184357/pdf/112614-REVISED-English-ID4D-IdentificationPrinciples-Folder-web-English-ID4D-IdentificationPrinciples.pdf&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; that there is “no single factor that affects a person’s ability to share in the gains of global development as much as having an official identity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, we will look at some of the issues and opportunities around Digital ID in the development space. Today, we look at informed consent: what it means to the development sector, the difficulty of getting it, and what we can do to make sure we aren’t leaving people behind, while respecting their privacy and the security of their data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 05:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-1-digital-identity-and-informed-consent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-1-digital-identity-and-informed-consent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Digital Identity Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/computers.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Nobody Cares What Tech You Use</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technologists and developers love to talk about the best tools for building new technology. MERN or MEAN stack, functional vs. object-oriented programming, vanilla development or frameworks. The internet is ripe with these discussions and attend any tech meetup and you’ll easily find multiple discussions comparing one tool to another. The performance and usability of one over the other, as if that is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fzachary-diehl-7b466b174&amp;data=01%7C01%7CGalia_Nurko%40dai.com%7Cf67a56aa590843a77e1b08d6a72fbf8e%7C7107113de20b4c20a4ce553cabbf686d%7C0&amp;sdata=AzUi%2BFO6MhNA7fBkVFoMVM%2F8vH8tuOQ1S38SioYFncc%3D&amp;reserved=0">Zach Diehl</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/nobody-cares-what-tech-you-use.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/nobody-cares-what-tech-you-use.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1_KiGsfO6WD6_sn1Qx70w3vA.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Is Your Data in a Lake or Water Treatment Plant?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They say to write about what you know. For the first part of my career and through my formal education, my work was all based in the world of water and sanitation. Glamorous stuff—pipes and pumps, fecal coli-forms and treatment options, toilets and activated sludge. It made for great dinner conversation (or so says my wife). At some point, I made the transition from a water guy who worked with a lot of data to a data scientist who knows about water. And as I dive deeper into the analogies and lingo of modern data systems and tools, I lean on my engineering training to make sense of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-mann-13012513/">Ben Mann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/is-your-data-in-a-lake-or-water-treatment-plant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/is-your-data-in-a-lake-or-water-treatment-plant.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CABI%20Group%20photo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Support Digital Tools and Approaches for USAID’s Bureau for Food Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rapidly changing access to digital tools such as basic mobile phones is changing the landscape for how we can address the challenges to ending global hunger, undernutrition, and extreme poverty. “Despite our collective progress in global food security and nutrition over recent years, a projected 702 million people still live in extreme poverty; nearly 800 million people around the world are chronically undernourished; and 159 million children under five are stunted. Food security is not just an economic and humanitarian issue; it is also a matter of security, as growing concentrations of poverty and hunger leave countries and communities vulnerable to increased instability, conflict, and violence.” (U.S. Government Global Food Security Strategy 2017-2021).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-digital-tools-and-approaches-for-usaids-bureau-for-food-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-digital-tools-and-approaches-for-usaids-bureau-for-food-security.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KIC-Mauritiana.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>KIC Mauritania: Winners Announced!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, DAI has provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;support to the Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC), which got its start in Ghana and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html&quot;&gt;expanded its work Mauritania in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, KIC Mauritania’s 2018 cohort of young entrepreneurs pitched concepts to a panel of judges, competing for more than $85,000 in total seed funding. Unlike KIC Ghana, which focuses solely on support to agritech startups, KIC’s Mauritanian startups have built a wide range of solutions across various sectors, from waste recycling to healthcare. Here’s an overview of this year’s finalists, their business concepts, and the final winners of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3%20USAID%20Development%20Innovations%20project.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building a Culture of Innovation in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many in international development want to be “innovative,” but how do workplaces develop cultures that promote useful innovation? The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) launched Development Innovations (DI) in 2013 to help Cambodian civil society organizations and tech companies leverage technology to address social needs. This objective would &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; new ways of thinking to create new ways for solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tiffany-tsang-05b33241/">Tiffany Tsang</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
