<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 14:30:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 14:30:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ict4drinks2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>September 2018 ICT4D Happy Hour Roundup: Were You There?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy hours are the sinew of the ICT4D community: They are how we connect. For a few hours each month, we put aside the titles, affiliations, competition, and enjoy each other’s company over a few drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September was a particularly busy month on the ICT4D happy hour calendar, so let’s take a quick look back on what happened. Hopefully, you’ll join us for the next one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ict4drinks&quot;&gt;ICT4Drinks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the general concept?&lt;/strong&gt; ICT4Drinks is the Facebook of the Washington, D.C., ICT4D community; everyone’s there! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techchange.org/&quot;&gt;TechChange’s&lt;/a&gt; Nick Martin and Chris Neu play host, greeting at the door and passing out drink tickets over the din of a crowd that generally reaches 100+. ICT4Drinks is the place to find out who’s hiring, who’s funding what and why, and what’s coming next in ICT4D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was this one about?&lt;/strong&gt; TechChange and DAI co-hosted the September event, which focused on next generation development professionals, as per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.devex.com/news/what-it-will-take-to-be-a-next-generation-development-professional-92764&quot;&gt;recent research&lt;/a&gt; by DAI, the U.S. Agency for International Development, and Devex on the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who was there?&lt;/strong&gt; A broad cross section of folks representing implementers, donors, ICT4D specialists, aspiring ICT4D professionals, students, and this all-star crew:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ict4drinks2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ict4drinks2.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Talia Dweck, from left, your humble author, Krista Baptista, Karim Bin-Humam, and Greg Maly, all from DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the next one:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ict4drinks.com/&quot;&gt;Join the email list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology-for-democracy-tech4dem&quot;&gt;Technology for Democracy (Tech4Dem)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the general concept?&lt;/strong&gt; Tech4Dem is a bi-monthly gathering of technologists who work with governments, activists, businesses, and multilaterals to improve the quality of representative government around the world. It’s a more niche audience than the ICT4Drinks crew, and is centered around a brief technical presentation from an expert, as well as a brief Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was this one about?&lt;/strong&gt; Tech4Dem hosted Julio Herrera, the Director of &lt;a href=&quot;http://redciudadana.org/&quot;&gt;Red Ciudadana&lt;/a&gt; (Human Network), a Guatemalan nonprofit that uses open data and web apps to engage the public around critical issues of governance, transparency, and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who was there?&lt;/strong&gt; Tech4Dem is popular with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ned.org/&quot;&gt;National Endowment for Democracy&lt;/a&gt; organizations, which include the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ndi.org/&quot;&gt;National Democratic Institute&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iri.org/&quot;&gt;International Republican Institute&lt;/a&gt; (both co-sponsors), the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cipe.org/&quot;&gt;Center for International Private Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cima.ned.org/&quot;&gt;Center for International Media Assistance&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irex.org/&quot;&gt;IREX&lt;/a&gt; and DAI (the other two sponsoring organizations). Beyond that, a wide range of free press and good governance-oriented organizations, consultants, and experts are regulars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/tech4dem.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;tech4dem.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Julio Herrera presents on Red Ciudadana’s open data work in Guatemala.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the next one:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/tech4dem-list&quot;&gt;Join the email list&lt;/a&gt; and check out Tech4Dem on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Facebook.com/tech4dem&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-centered-design-for-development-hcd4d&quot;&gt;Human-Centered Design for Development (HCD4D)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the general concept?&lt;/strong&gt; HCD4D is the newest ICT4D happy hour. It’s run by a group of designers and aims to elevate the practice of human-centered design in the international development space. The founders believe that for technology to facilitate impact, it must be well-designed, and that good design hinges on a deep understanding of how a specific population uses technology, sees itself, and sees its social context. The happy hour is focused on sharing best practices and elevating the discussion about design among global development implementers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was this one about?&lt;/strong&gt; The inaugural event was a discussion of the distinctions between designing for domestic or commercial clients and designing for international development programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who was there?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.souktel.org/&quot;&gt;Souktel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creativeassociatesinternational.com/&quot;&gt;Creative Associates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dalberg.com/&quot;&gt;Dalberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://forumone.com/&quot;&gt;Forum One&lt;/a&gt;, IREX, DAI, as well as designers from a variety of tech companies and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Image%20from%20iOS%20(14).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image from iOS (14).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gina Assaf from Souktel, from left, Priyanka Pathak from Dalberg, and Ayan Kishore from Creative Associates presenting.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the next one:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/HCD4D-Designing-Tech-for-International-Aid-Development/&quot;&gt;Join the Meet-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did I miss your favorite ICT4D happy hour? Is there an amazing ICT4D happy hour outside of D.C.? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:adam_fivenson@dai.com&quot;&gt;Let me know!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 18:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/september-2018-ict4d-happy-hour-roundup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/september-2018-ict4d-happy-hour-roundup.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202018-09-12%20at%202.58.24%20PM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Americas’ Effort to Integrate, Distribute, and Use Open Data to Make Decisions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was happy to represent DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amerigeoss.org/amerigeoss-events/amerigeoss-week-2018/index_html&quot;&gt;AmeriGEOSS week&lt;/a&gt; recently in Brazil, sharing experiences of how DAI has developed platforms and tools for decision-making in Central America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202018-09-12%20at%202.14.19%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-09-12 at 2.14.19 PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 08:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-americas-effort-to-integrate-distribute-and-use-open-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-americas-effort-to-integrate-distribute-and-use-open-data.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/concordia.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Kosmos Innovation Center wins 2018 P3 Impact Award</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re so excited that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/ghana-kosmos-innovation-center-kic&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt;—the Kosmos Energy-funded project DAI helps implement in Ghana—was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/r/pa/prs/ps/2018/09/286218.htm&quot;&gt;announced the winner&lt;/a&gt; of the 2018 P3 Impact Award at the annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.concordia.net/annualsummit/2018annualsummit/&quot;&gt;Concordia Summit&lt;/a&gt; in New York, that takes place alongside the United Nations General Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Cybersecurity.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cyber Security Series Part 1: Trust is Why Cyber Security Matters to Digital Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re launching one of our final series for 2018 on cyber security with this post on why it matters to international development. Stay tuned and &lt;a href=&quot;https://confirmsubscription.com/h/r/066AFBA15492935C&quot;&gt;subscribe to our newsletter&lt;/a&gt; if this topic interests you!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-series-part-1-trust-is-why-cyber-security-matters-to-digital-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-series-part-1-trust-is-why-cyber-security-matters-to-digital-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber Security</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ux_ui.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Thinking About the User Part I: Design Considerations for Mobile Apps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Think back to the last time you used a mobile app(lication) with unwieldy menu placement, indecipherable icons, and inconvenient user-configurable options. These may seem like minor nuisances in the everyday life of app interaction, and frankly, most users probably never notice (or maybe don’t realize that they notice) or hardly care. But user experience in application design is critical to ease of use, efficient navigation, and longevity of mobile-based application technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 09:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/app-ui.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/app-ui.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>UI/UX series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fortnite-superhero-art-01-ps4-us-27apr18.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Fortnite for International Development?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fortnite—a free, online multiplayer video game—has amassed more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/announcing-2018-2019-fortnite-competitive-season&quot;&gt;125 million players&lt;/a&gt; worldwide during the mere 14 months since it debuted in July 2017. The game features a fast-paced, &lt;em&gt;Hunger Games&lt;/em&gt;-inspired format mixed with community, celebrity, and story, and so far it’s working. Everyone from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ftw.usatoday.com/2018/03/fortnite-is-taking-over-the-sports-world&quot;&gt;athletes&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/15/17123424/ninja-drake-fortnite-twitch-stream-record-travis-scott-juju&quot;&gt;musicians&lt;/a&gt; are going public with their fandom and some parents are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfgate.com/technology/businessinsider/article/Parents-are-paying-as-much-as-35-an-hour-for-13123982.php&quot;&gt;shelling out $35/hour&lt;/a&gt; for a Fortnite coach for their kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fortnite-superhero-art-01-ps4-us-27apr18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fortnite-superhero-art-01-ps4-us-27apr18.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image © 2018, Epic Games.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/fortnite-for-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/fortnite-for-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/summer-reads1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>August Roundup: Leapfrogging Technology, ICT4E in Conflict, and Facebook in Myanmar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog_days&quot;&gt;dog days&lt;/a&gt; of summer. Usually a slow time for work, that means there’s extra time to sit at your computer looking for good stuff to read, struggling with either being uncomfortably warm from the summer heat or excruciatingly cold from over-aggressive office air-conditioning. We get it. We got you. Fresh ICT4D reads from our August Roundup below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/summer-reads1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;summer-reads1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/august-round-up-top-number-ict4d-reads-you-may-have-missed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/august-round-up-top-number-ict4d-reads-you-may-have-missed.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/top%205-6b4a86.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>5 Top Resources for Digital Access Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/top%205-ed0419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;top 5-ed0419.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global community has recognized the importance of digital equality—affordable, universal internet access as one of the Sustainable Development Goals. When we are implementing digital programs, access and inclusion are key concerns: We don’t want to leave anyone behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-top-resources-for-digital-access-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-top-resources-for-digital-access-data.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Ray.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Rising Tide of ICTs for Accountability</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A tectonic shift is taking place in commerce, and we’re all a part of it. At its core, it boils down to one concept: accountability. The accelerating movement toward web-based management tools, data analytics, and automation among businesses—coupled with the rapid growth in mobile phone technology—has reduced the cost of doing business, slashed barriers to entry, and reduced the time elapsed from concept to market-ready solution. The result is increased competition, more customer choice, greater accountability to the customer, and the sound of the sledgehammer falling upon formerly protected industries. Customers in the many business-to-consumer verticals (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/theworldpost/wp/2018/08/13/middle-class/?hpid=hp_no-name_opinion-card-f-2%3Ahomepage%2Fstory&quot;&gt;admittedly not all&lt;/a&gt;) have more bargaining power than ever before, and can hold businesses accountable for poor performance by downloading a competitor’s solution with a few simple clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 16:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/rising-tide-icts-for-accountability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/rising-tide-icts-for-accountability.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/RStudio-59a8d9.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Getting Started with RStudio, Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part 2 of a series exploring the basics of importing and analyzing data in RStudio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-started-with-rstudio.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; we introduced the R programming language, RStudio as a development environment, and examined rainfall data for May. The data we analyzed was stored in Google Docs. We used some functions to pull the data into our work environment, and displayed the data over time using a line graph. In this post, we’re going to make an improvement to this analysis. Specifically, we’re going to streamline the way we access weather data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-started-with-rstudio-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-started-with-rstudio-part-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
