<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 11:03:34 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 11:03:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AKS%20Blog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Location-Based Platform Work Presents Benefits—and Risks—to Workers in the Global South, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the wonders of the digital age is that if at 11 pm I suddenly crave a pizza (Hawaiian preferably—no shame!), all I have to do is click a few buttons on my phone, and &lt;em&gt;voila!&lt;/em&gt; pizza is delivered to my door. While it may feel like the pizza arrived by magic, especially given the “no-contact” options made available since the start of COVID-19, the satisfaction of my late-night craving is made possible by the work of independent contractors hired by digital platforms such as Uber and DoorDash to deliver products in cities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 08:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/location-based-platform-work-presents-benefits-and-increasing-risks-to-workers-in-the-global-south-part-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/location-based-platform-work-presents-benefits-and-increasing-risks-to-workers-in-the-global-south-part-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>gig economy</category>
        
        <category>gig work</category>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CoverPhoto-9180c8.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID and the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation on an Assessment of Farmer-Centric Models of Data Governance and Ownership</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the number of digitally enabled agricultural products and services continues to grow in regions across the globe, most of the data collected by the digital service providers developing these tools remain locked within each entity’s systems. Due to incomplete, fragmented, or non-existent data sets on agri-food system stakeholders, such as farmers, digital service providers often take on the cost burden of collecting the information they need to develop products and services for their target users. This results in multiple actors holding fragments of information on agri-food system actors, decreasing incentives for data sharing across organizations and increasing the burden placed on food system actors to repeatedly provide their data to numerous researchers, companies, and development organizations. This dynamic has led to several missed opportunities for all stakeholders, including government agencies, the private sector, and the development community, to have a common and complete picture of the state of agricultural communities and the needs of individual actors therein.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-and-the-bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-on-an-assessment-on-farmer-centric-models-of-data-governance-and-ownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-and-the-bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-on-an-assessment-on-farmer-centric-models-of-data-governance-and-ownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3168212588_cd7d304161_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Future is Looking Up: Satellites for Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When predicting which technologies might have an impact on international development in the coming years, shifts in the economics of a technology are often more indicative of impending transformation than improvements in its capabilities. Particularly in emerging markets, even older technologies can suddenly become disruptive once their cost drops, enabling wider application. With that lens in our spyglass as we scan the horizon for coming opportunities, then, we should not forget to look up, because satellites are getting radically cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3168212588_cd7d304161_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3168212588_cd7d304161_o.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Flickr, Paul Keller.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-is-looking-up-satellites-for-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-is-looking-up-satellites-for-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Internet of Things</category>
        
        <category>Satellite</category>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Study Shows Most Costa Rican Companies Depend on U.S.-Based Tech Platforms to Sell Goods or Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Like much of the developing world, Costa Rica has limited availability of digital technologies compared to industrialized nations. Due to this lag in digital transformation, when the COVID-19 pandemic hit, commerce in Costa Rica was highly affected, leading to business disruption and unemployment. As of June, the country’s unemployment rate was 17.4 percent, which is an improvement upon the initial losses in 2020, however, still higher than the average for high-income countries (6.4 percent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As COVID-19 stretches into its second year, formal companies, both big and small, are jumping into the digital world to find efficient and safe ways to offer their services and products online. Informal businesses are following suit, using online platforms to reach customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 11:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Eduardo Gonzalez
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/study-reveals-that-most-costa-rican-companies-depend-on-us-based-tech-platforms-to-sell-their-goods-or-services-online.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/study-reveals-that-most-costa-rican-companies-depend-on-us-based-tech-platforms-to-sell-their-goods-or-services-online.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Economy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Barriers_simplified%20graphic%20(002).png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Barriers to Digital Inclusion: What is Different for Children?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this past summer, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has been working with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sesameworkshop.org/what-we-do/refugee-response&quot;&gt;Sesame Workshop&lt;/a&gt; on its Play to Learn program to explore the possibilities for using digital tools to provide education services among children, ages 3 to 8, living in crisis-affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/talia-dweck-92966758/">Talia Dweck</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chloemessenger/?originalSubdomain=uk">Chloe Messenger</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/barriers-to-digital-inclusion-what-is-different-for-children.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/barriers-to-digital-inclusion-what-is-different-for-children.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/426b550f-165c-478a-8b44-1b1709b25c87.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights Yemen: Understanding Children’s Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this past summer, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has been working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sesameworkshop.org/what-we-do/refugee-response&quot;&gt;Sesame Workshop&lt;/a&gt; to explore the possibilities for using digital tools to provide education services to young children living in crisis-affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights™&lt;/a&gt; methodology, our researchers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-colombia-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;Colombia&lt;/a&gt;, Yemen, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-south-sudan-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;South Sudan&lt;/a&gt; talked to children and their parents and caregivers to understand communities’ barriers to connectivity and their technology habits. Through this research, we sought to understand how technology might be leveraged to improve access to educational video content. In this &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, we share our findings and interesting insights into the digital lives of children in these contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/02269ab6-17f2-4e23-a708-3d5339e17677.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;02269ab6-17f2-4e23-a708-3d5339e17677.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 11:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/talia-dweck-92966758">Talia Dweck</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/chloe-messenger">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anne-hand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-yemen-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-yemen-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/IMG20210726143829-3fb1dc.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights South Sudan: Understanding Children's Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the summer, the DAI Center for Digital Acceleration has been working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sesameworkshop.org/what-we-do/refugee-response&quot;&gt;Sesame Workshop&lt;/a&gt; to explore the possibilities for using digital tools to provide education services to young children in crisis-affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights™&lt;/a&gt; methodology, our researchers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-colombia-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;Colombia&lt;/a&gt;, Yemen, and South Sudan talked to children and their parents and caregivers to understand communities’ barriers to connectivity and their technology usage habits. Through this research, we sought to understand how technology might be leveraged to improve access to educational video content. In this series, we share our findings and interesting insights into the digital lives of children in these contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/IMG20210726143829.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG20210726143829.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/talia-dweck-92966758/">Talia Dweck</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chloemessenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-south-sudan-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-south-sudan-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Colombia1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights Colombia: Understanding Children’s Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the summer, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has been working with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sesameworkshop.org/what-we-do/refugee-response&quot;&gt;Sesame Workshop&lt;/a&gt; exploring the use of digital education tools for young children in crisis-affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights™&lt;/a&gt; methodology, our researchers in Colombia, South Sudan, and Yemen spoke with children and their parents and caregivers to understand their communities’ barriers to connectivity and tech habits. Through this research, we sought to understand how technology might be leveraged to improve access to educational content. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;In this series&lt;/a&gt;, we share our insights into the digital lives of children in these countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Colombia1-8eaed6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Colombia1-8eaed6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 04:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/talia-dweck-92966758/">Talia Dweck</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chloemessenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-colombia-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-colombia-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Colombia</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Banglore_LandUse.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Bangalore and the Hidden Costs of ‘Silicon Cities’</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last 25 years, Bangalore, India, has transformed itself from a relatively sleepy second-tier city into a regional anchor for global technology corporations and a hub for innovative technology-driven startups. The international development community has cheered the growth of similar hubs in low- and middle-income countries—think Nairobi’s Silicon Savannah or Lagos. But Bangalore’s story often obscures the massive environmental and social toll that rapid, tech-driven growth can have on a city.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/bangalore-and-the-hidden-costs-of-silicon-cities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/bangalore-and-the-hidden-costs-of-silicon-cities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Economy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3891388b-1a22-493b-bce0-2847a0ee9ca0.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What is Agile? Part Two: A Primer on Different Frameworks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed in part one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-one-the-story-behind-the-buzzword.html&quot;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, agile is an umbrella term that encapsulates a number of frameworks, strategies, and tools. In this second installment, we dive a bit deeper into what agile is in practice by highlighting some of the most common frameworks used by agile teams. This primer on agile frameworks and methods will by no means be comprehensive (there are entire courses, websites, and certifications dedicated to each), but it can serve as a good starting point for better understanding which flavor of agile might be best suited to your teams’ needs if you are considering adopting agile in your organization. This post will cover two of the most popular types of agile in more depth: Scrum and Kanban. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wrike.com/project-management-guide/faq/what-are-the-different-types-of-agile-methodologies/&quot;&gt;several others&lt;/a&gt; that are widely used as well, but these two have many components that can be flexible and adaptable for use in non-software development contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Samantha Weinberg
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-two-a-primer-on-different-agile-frameworks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-two-a-primer-on-different-agile-frameworks.html</guid>
        
        <category>agile</category>
        
        <category>software development</category>
        
        <category>Agile Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
