<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 11:23:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 11:23:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SpaCreekSocialImage.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Studying River Health through Citizen Science and Data Analysis in Maryland</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 1970, DAI has worked in 160 countries on development issues ranging from good governance to environmental problems. But what about scientific policy-oriented initiatives in our backyard? With a headquarters in Bethesda, Maryland, DAI is surrounded by a vibrant and diverse social and ecological community, and civil society organizations that focus on sustainable development. At the Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA), we’ve had the good fortune of engaging two such organizations— &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacreek.net/&quot;&gt;Spa Creek Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; (SCC) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aacc.edu/about/schools-of-study/science-and-technology/environmental-center/&quot;&gt;Environmental Center&lt;/a&gt; at Anne Arundel Community College (AACC)—that combine formal academic research with citizen science and use data to bring awareness to the health of the Chesapeake Bay watershed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SpaCreekMap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SpaCreekMap.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Water testing locations and test results in Spa and Back Creek.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/studying-river-health-through-citizen-science-and-data-analysis-in-maryland.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/studying-river-health-through-citizen-science-and-data-analysis-in-maryland.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        <category>Environment &amp; Energy</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Blog%20image%20%2312Nov19.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Unearthing Lessons by Revisiting—Not Reinventing—the Wheel by Utilizing Data Science</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we enter what the World Economic Forum refers to as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/focus/fourth-industrial-revolution&quot;&gt;fourth industrial revolution&lt;/a&gt;”—a profound transformation of industries and institutions driven by artificial intelligence, machine learning, robotics, and augmented reality—international development practitioners are shifting toward data-centric business practices that require new systems, more efficient work flows, and modern skill sets. While the promise of newly available data is driving a desire to answer new analytical questions, lessons from more than 50 years of development projects lay dormant in Word and PDF documents stored in disparate folders, databases, and online portals by a wide array of stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mstyslinger/">Matt Styslinger</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/unearthing-lessons-by-revisiting-not-reinventing-the-wheel-with-data-science.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/unearthing-lessons-by-revisiting-not-reinventing-the-wheel-with-data-science.html</guid>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Save%20the%20Children.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in International Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) technologies, although still relatively new concepts, are garnering a vast amount of interest in international development across sectors and geographies. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s Center for Digital Development (CDD)’s Strategy &amp;amp; Research (S&amp;amp;R) team published a report in 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/machine-learning/AI-ML-in-development&quot;&gt;“Reflecting the Past, Shaping the Future: Making AI work for International Development”&lt;/a&gt;, based on extensive research on this rapidly growing field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USAID would like to translate the report’s recommendations into an actionable format so the lessons and good practices are accessible to USAID program staff and implementing partners that may have limited familiarity with, nor time, to devote to the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 09:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-in-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-in-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Chandy%20Photo-No%20Watermark.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons Learned from Development Innovations Team: Adapt, Serve Users, and Tell Your Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As an avid and committed reader of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/&quot;&gt;Digital@DAI&lt;/a&gt;, you have no doubt come across our extensive coverage of the Cambodia &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; (DI) project, funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). My colleagues have chronicled efforts to address flooding by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/civil-society-the-hard-ware-way-maker-lab-experiences-in-cambodia.html&quot;&gt;building hardware&lt;/a&gt; with locally available parts, the project’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia-civil-society-facebook.html&quot;&gt;design research with civil society groups&lt;/a&gt; in Phnom Penh, and everything in between. With a mandate to strengthen Cambodia’s civic tech ecosystem and facilitate connections between civil society and the local tech community, DI was one of the only USAID projects that focused on technology and innovation ecosystems. But alas, all good things must come to an end—especially when the mission has been achieved and staff have worked themselves out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-usaids-development-innovations-adapt-serve-users-and-tell-your-story.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-usaids-development-innovations-adapt-serve-users-and-tell-your-story.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/susannah%20blog%20photo%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Part I: Big Data in Agriculture Conference Download: Building Trust and Fueling Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a data enthusiast with a budding curiosity in digital agriculture, I was excited to attend the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigdata.cgiar.org/hyderabad-2019/&quot;&gt;2019 CGIAR Big Data in Agriculture Convention&lt;/a&gt; in Hyderabad, India. The event brought together attendees from around the globe to connect over the theme of &lt;em&gt;Trust: humans, machines, and ecosystems.&lt;/em&gt; The CGIAR Big Data Platform aims to “use big data approaches to solve agriculture development problems faster, better, and at greater scale than before.” The platform does this by connecting CGIAR-affiliated researchers from around the globe with development practitioners and ag-tech providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did I have the rare opportunity to engage with super smart scientist-types who, unlike me, have job titles like “plant geneticist” and “mycology and plant pathology specialist,” but I also was compelled to consider the definition and role of trust in the application of data and technology to building resilient global food security.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/part-i-big-data-in-agriculture-conference-download-building-trust-and-fueling-innovation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/part-i-big-data-in-agriculture-conference-download-building-trust-and-fueling-innovation.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/India%20Photo5%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Respond Now: USAID Seeks ICT Regulatory Policy Technical Assistance Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is issuing an expression of interest (EOI) to support the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;strong&gt;Promoting American Approaches to ICT Regulatory Policy (ProICT)&lt;/strong&gt; activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 06:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-is-seeking-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-is-seeking-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SLW%20PH%20TOT.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>10 Trends Changing Entrepreneurship Ecosystems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re supporting early stage entrepreneurs in emerging and frontier markets, there’s a lot to be excited about as we approach the start of the third decade of this century! Over the past year supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-shell-livewire-global-consultancy&quot;&gt;Shell LiveWIRE&lt;/a&gt; global entrepreneurship program and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/ghana-kosmos-innovation-center-kic&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center (KIC)&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve had the chance to attend some rather dynamic conferences, ‘un’-conferences, meetups, and pitch events with the Global Accelerator Network (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gan.co/&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt;), the Aspen Network of Development Entrepreneurs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://andeglobal.org/&quot;&gt;ANDE&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techstars.com/&quot;&gt;Techstars&lt;/a&gt;, and the International Business Innovation Association (&lt;a href=&quot;https://inbia.org/&quot;&gt;InBIA&lt;/a&gt;). I’ve observed some trends from the inspiring incubator and accelerator program managers that I’ve gotten to meet from around the world—and will share the best ones below:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/zaki-raheem">Zaki Raheem</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/10-trends-changing-entrepreneurship-ecosystems.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/10-trends-changing-entrepreneurship-ecosystems.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID on the Digital Development Awards and Communications Activities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Global Development Lab, the Center for Digital Development (CDD) addresses gaps in digital access and affordability and advances the use of technology and advanced data analysis in development. DAI’s Digital Frontiers project works closely with the CDD’s Knowledge and Insights (K&amp;amp;I) team, which leads the Center’s work in knowledge management, communications, and training.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-and-insights-rfp-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-and-insights-rfp-blog.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: El contexto digital de la población con discapacidad en Honduras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se estima que el número de personas que viven con algún tipo de discapacidad en América Latina y el Caribe entre 2001 y 2013 fue de más de &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paho.org/hon/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;amp;view=download&amp;amp;alias=383-identificacion-y-caracterizacion-de-las-personas-con-discapacidad-en-francisco-morazan-2017&amp;amp;category_slug=fortalecimiento-de-sistemas-de-salud&amp;amp;Itemid=211&quot;&gt;70 millones&lt;/a&gt; (o 12.5 porciento de la población regional total, el 12.6 porciento de la población de América Latina y el 61 porciento de los países del Caribe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En Honduras los estudios acerca del tema de discapacidad son escasos y limitados. Según los resultados de la Encuesta Permanente de Hogares con Propósitos Múltiples del Instituto Nacional de Estadística (INE) realizada en septiembre 2002, se encontró que en Honduras existían 177,516 personas con discapacidad, lo que representa una prevalencia de 2.65 porciento, con predominio masculino (55 porciento) en comparación de la población femenina (45 porciento). Sin embargo, estudios recientes del [Censo 2013 del INE] indicaron la existencia de 205,423 personas con discapacidad, y &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;otro estudio&lt;/a&gt; de Flores, et al. (2014) encontró una tasa de prevalencia del 4.6 porciento, que significa un total de 381,287 personas que viven con discapacidades asumiendo una población de 8.2 millones.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: How the Disability Community in Honduras Uses Digital Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies on how many disabled people live in Honduras are scarce. Results of a survey by the National Statistics Institute (INE), carried out in September 2002, showed there are 177,516 people with disabilities in the country. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;Academic studies&lt;/a&gt; tell a different story. They estimate that the number of people in Honduras with disabilities is closer to 381,287. These differing reports prevent the government, institutions, and civil society from effectively thinking through how ensure that services are accessible to those with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
