<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 09:30:27 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 09:30:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coffee Cloud: The Digital Project for  Central American Coffee Growers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From 2010 to 2014, the Central American coffee bean suffered from a disease that rocked the economies of the region. Exports declined by 55 percent. From 2012 to 2013 some 374,000 jobs were lost—17 percent of the labor force. &lt;strong&gt;Roya&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20171106-the-disease-that-could-change-how-we-drink-coffee&quot;&gt;coffee rust&lt;/a&gt; threatened the livelihoods of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oxfam.org/sites/www.oxfam.org/files/file_attachments/ib-coffee-rust-employment-collapse-central-america-140814-en.pdf&quot;&gt;nearly 2 million&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee rust is a fungal disease that covers the leaves and prevents photosynthesis, slowly constricting plants’ ability to process sunlight, reducing bean yield and eventually starving the plant to death. The warmer, wetter conditions wrought by climate change creates a better ecosystem for the fungus to grow. Its impact on Central American economies is significant as coffee exports are the region’s largest source of foreign income and coffee supports a vast supply chain, in turn supporting dozens of adjacent industries.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 08:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-the-digital-project-for-central-american-coffee-growers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-the-digital-project-for-central-american-coffee-growers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trends in Digital Health: 4 Takeaways From Our UK Event</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In comparison to other development sectors, health programs have historically been early adopters of digital tools. What have we learned over the last 10 years, and where are we heading? How can we build systems that integrate data from independent actors across the health ecosystem? How can we use lessons learned to support innovation? How can we adapt to expanding digital access and support the growth of local capacity?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anand-varghese/">Anand Varghese</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/trends-in-digital-health-four-take-aways-from-our-second-uk-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/trends-in-digital-health-four-take-aways-from-our-second-uk-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID Missions to Improve Broadband Connectivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid expansion of mobile and internet access in the developing world holds the promise of catalyzing resilient economic and social growth. However, the availability and cost of connectivity is a significant barrier to fully realizing that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help address this challenge, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s Center for Digital Development developed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/Better_Connectivity_Better_Programs_April2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Better Connectivity, Better Programs: How to Implement a Demand Aggregation Program (How-to Guide)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 17:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="mailto:digitalfrontiers@dai.com">Yasmine Williams</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working With Tech Service Providers: It’s About More Than Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a nonprofit focused on improving maternal health outcomes? Or maybe you’re a civic engagement organization that encourages young people to become more involved with their local governments. No matter the objective, technology can both help you be more efficient internally and more impactful externally. The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of tech is often easy: “Oh, we’ll just build an app for that!” But relationships with technical service providers are fraught with pitfalls that can jeopardize outcomes and derail even the best intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/working-with-tech-service-providers-its-about-more-than-tech.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/working-with-tech-service-providers-its-about-more-than-tech.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Recent Reads We Loved (And You May Have Missed!)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/dai-launches-the-center-for-digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration&lt;/a&gt; team grows, we are finding new ways to share knowledge beyond our epic WhatsApp group chat that grows more ridiculous and off-topic by the day. We have some voracious readers on the team, so in prep for this post I took a minute to poll them to find out which recent articles they found fascinating—and I had missed them all! Since I can’t be the only one, I am sharing them with you to ensure these gems get as wide a readership as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/top%205%20news%20podcast%20logo_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;top 5 news podcast logo_0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/recent-reads-we-loved-and-you-may-have-missed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/recent-reads-we-loved-and-you-may-have-missed.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Replicando la App de Transparencia en Guatemala</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nota: Esta publicación también está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/forking-with-design-thinking-in-guatemala.html&quot;&gt;inglés&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El pasado mes de febrero del año en curso, retorné a Guatemala con el fin de dar seguimiento a una iniciativa tecnológica denominada &lt;em&gt;Somos Chiantla,&lt;/em&gt; que promueve la participación ciudadana y la rendición de cuentas en el municipio de Chiantla, en el departamento de Huehuetenango. De igual manera visité los municipios de Sacapulas y San Rafael Pie de la Cuesta, con el fin de replicar esta herramienta en estos dos municipios, con un enfoque eminentemente participativo y colaborativo, considerando propuestas de autoridades de gobierno local y representantes de la sociedad civil para personalizar la aplicación atendiendo a sus gustos y preferencias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/07%20Plenary%20voting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;07 Plenary voting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Un participante en Sacapulas vota por las mejores formas de actualizar Somos Chiantla.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 15:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/replicando-app-transparencia-guatemala.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/replicando-app-transparencia-guatemala.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Guatemala</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started With RStudio, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part 1 of 2, as we explore the basics of importing and analyzing data in RStudio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a data scientist, I spend a lot of my time working in a programming language called R. RStudio is an open source integrated development environment (IDE) for the R programming language, which focuses on programming for statistical analysis. You could arguably do data analysis in almost any computer programming language, but R offers some of the most accessible statistical functions of any language available today. You could also do this work in a business intelligence application such as Tableau or PowerBI, or conduct statistical analysis in STATA, but R and RStudio are free and open source. In this post, I’m going to introduce a few lines of code to get you started on your journey into R.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-started-with-rstudio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-started-with-rstudio.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICT4D Conference: Unpacking the Complexities of Integrated Health Data and Data Ownership</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“We are at an inflection point in digital development!” &lt;a href=&quot;https://nethope.org/staff/lauren-woodman/&quot;&gt;Lauren Woodman&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of NetHope, boomed over the crowd of 750-plus participants the first day of the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ict4dconference.org/&quot;&gt;ICT4D Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Lusaka, Zambia. It may indeed be a critical time for technology, but the means of reaching our collective goals can create healthy disagreements, ones that should be unpacked in exactly the kind of setting the ICT4D Conference creates.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/ict4d-conference-unpacking-the-complexities-of-integrated-health-data-and-data-ownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/ict4d-conference-unpacking-the-complexities-of-integrated-health-data-and-data-ownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Do No Harm Framework for ICT4D: Inspiration from SwitchPoint 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchpointideas.com/2018&quot;&gt;SwitchPoint 2018&lt;/a&gt; was an inspiring, passionate, and delightful indulgence: Spending two days in lush Saxapahaw, North Carolina, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dai-global-developments.com/articles/global-health-and-tech-thinkers-come-together-at-switchpoint/&quot;&gt;thinking about big ideas&lt;/a&gt; and learning from leading experts in small group sessions in between performance art and live music shows felt like such a departure from Conference As Usual. I felt space opening up in my brain to start really processing what the speakers were saying—the real act and action of listening versus the usual ruse of secretly responding to emails on my phone while half paying attention and nodding at key pauses.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 11:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-do-no-harm-framework-for-ict4d-inspiration-from-switchpoint-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-do-no-harm-framework-for-ict4d-inspiration-from-switchpoint-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Insights Malawi: Information and Communication in Rural Communities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, I spent two weeks in Malawi trying to gain a real understanding of technology use and media consumption habits of people in rural and marginalised communities. Along with a team of enumerators, I spoke to 183 women, men, girls and boys (ages 14 to 80) in different traditional authorities (TAs) in Northern, Central and Southern Malawi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/009-MangochiTAMponda_approval.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;009-MangochiTAMponda_approval.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Alice talking tech in Mponda, Mangochi, Southern Malawi.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 06:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-malawi-communication-among-rural-communities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-malawi-communication-among-rural-communities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
