<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:47:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Electonicwaste-5d99e0.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Why Electronic Waste is Relevant for the Digital Development Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently cleaning my house when I came across three old mobile phones: a feature phone, a BlackBerry, and an iPhone. I found myself wondering, “&lt;em&gt;Why did I keep these?&lt;/em&gt;” Immediately, I thought, “&lt;em&gt;the pictures&lt;/em&gt;,” but then quickly remembered that nowadays when everything can be saved to the cloud, that justification makes no sense. When I finished organizing, I found that I had left the three phones on my desk, as if they were patiently waiting for me to do something with them. It quickly dawned on me that I actually did not know what to do with them… not from a sentimental perspective, but rather from a lack of knowledge of how to securely dispose of technology. Shouldn’t many of the pieces and parts be reusable to build new devices or maintain old ones? Is there an equivalent to an electronics recycling bin?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/electronic-waste-is-relevant-for-our-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/electronic-waste-is-relevant-for-our-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Environment &amp; Energy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking About Online Campaigns for Change with Sotheavy AT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We recently spoke with Sotheavy AT, the Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/ThinkPlasticNow/community/&quot;&gt;Think Plastic&lt;/a&gt;, a hugely popular digital environmental advocacy campaign working to reduce plastic waste and inspire action from citizens across Cambodia. (She’s also the former Senior Innovation Program Manager for the DAI-led &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/cambodia-development-innovations&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt;, funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and a consultant on DAI projects across Southeast Asia.) Think Plastic started small, with two- to three-minute videos in 2019, and has grown rapidly to reach more than 4 million Cambodians in just one year—almost 25 percent of the population of the country. As more businesses, organizations, and citizens go online around the world in the COVID-19 era, we have seen evidence of how well-designed and well-executed online campaigns can rapidly advance development outcomes. Think Plastic has been widely recognized for its success by the Royal Government of Cambodia’s Ministry of Environment and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khmertimeskh.com/50814112/at-sotheavy-award-winning-anti-plastic-pioneer/&quot;&gt;Women of the Future Southeast Asia&lt;/a&gt; and is now a well-known brand across the country. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 08:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-about-online-campaigns-for-change-with-sotheavy-at.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-about-online-campaigns-for-change-with-sotheavy-at.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/IMG_7630_resize.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development for Newbies, Part 2: Sophomore Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This month I’ve been reflecting on all that has happened since this time last year, back when we were still blissfully unaware of the trials, trauma, and transformation 2020 would bring. Instead of focusing on the challenges we faced over the last several months, I’d like to highlight some relevant concepts for colleagues who are gaining momentum in understanding and incorporating digital technologies into their international development work. Below are some important topics (upon which my tech-savvy colleagues and others have written extensively, so check out the links!) that can be applied across our development projects and fieldwork. Consider this the sophomore edition of the “Digital Development for Newbies” series, but if you’re brand new to this topic, I encourage you to start with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-1-the-basics.html&quot;&gt;Part 1: The Basics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Addie Ryan
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/EU%20vs%20Disinfo.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Are We Reading about Misinformation and Disinformation?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After the insurrection/uprising/riot/attack/craziness/failed coup attempt (take your pick) at the U.S. Capitol building a few weeks ago, misinformation and disinformation are back in the news with a vengeance. While the bulk of the public’s attention has been on U.S. domestic mis/disinfo related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/article/what-is-qanon.html&quot;&gt;QAnon&lt;/a&gt; and other 2020 presidential &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/presidential-election-2020-conspiracy-theories-debunked/&quot;&gt;election conspiracies&lt;/a&gt;, it got us at the Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) thinking about our favorite websites, blogs, and resources about mis/disinfo in the Global South or specifically for international development practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-cda-reading-about-misinformation-and-disinformation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-cda-reading-about-misinformation-and-disinformation.html</guid>
        
        <category>cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Gratiana%20Blog%201.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Towards Inclusive Machine Translation: A Case for User-Centered Design in Machine Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.masakhane.io/&quot;&gt;Masakhane&lt;/a&gt;, a grassroots natural language process (NLP) community whose “mission is to strengthen and spur NLP in African languages, for Africans, by Africans,” published a paper titled “Participatory Research for Low-resourced Machine Translation: A Case Study in African Languages.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation&quot;&gt;Machine translation&lt;/a&gt; refers to the use of software to translate digital and nondigital text and speech from one language into another. Google Translate is one of the more common examples of machine translation. Most of us have experienced issues translating text, especially sentences and phrases, as Google Translate often has difficulty detecting meaning and context. Due to these challenges, it can often give users incorrect word-for-word translations. (In your free time, search for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23GoogleTranslateFail%20&amp;amp;src=typed_query&quot;&gt;#GoogleTranslateFail&lt;/a&gt; hashtag on Twitter for a whole host of mistranslated content and a good laugh.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Translate, and other mainstream machine translation tools, are also limited in the number of languages they are able to translate. As of today, Google Translate offers support for only 108 of the more than 7,000 languages spoken across the globe. Many of the languages that are not supported are what machine learning researchers consider to be “low-resourced,” a term used to describe languages that have few digital resources available and, more importantly, that are less commonly taught, endangered, or low density. The Masakhane paper outlines an alternative “participatory” approach for low-resourced languages to standard NLP tasks such as crowd-sourced annotation for training data and evaluation benchmarks. To learn more about the basics of NLP, head to our previous blog post on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/unearthing-lessons-by-revisiting-not-reinventing-the-wheel-with-data-science.html&quot;&gt;importance of NLP&lt;/a&gt; in development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/understanding-user-centered-design-for-machine-learning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/understanding-user-centered-design-for-machine-learning.html</guid>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/agree-1728448_1280.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Consent to Data Processing in Humanitarian and Development Contexts, Part 2: Beyond Consent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is part of a series on the use of management information systems (MIS) in humanitarian crises. In our last piece, we talked about how &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/consent-to-data-processing-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts-part-one.html&quot;&gt;informed consent&lt;/a&gt; can be difficult in humanitarian settings, but that is not an excuse for failing to protect the privacy of beneficiaries. In this blog, we focus on what to do where consent is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachaelsteller/">Rachael Steller</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/beyond-consent-why-seeking-consent-for-data-processing-can-be-problematic-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/beyond-consent-why-seeking-consent-for-data-processing-can-be-problematic-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts.html</guid>
        
        <category>consent</category>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>humanitarian response</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Pulse_oximeter_sensor.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Racist Hardware and What to Do About It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMc2029240&quot;&gt;an astonishing letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor published in the December 17, 2020, edition of the &lt;em&gt;New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/em&gt; (NEJM), a group of five doctors from the University of Michigan Medical School presented findings from their study on adult inpatients receiving supplemental oxygen at the University’s hospital. They found that the variance between blood oxygen levels measured through a pulse oximeter—an optical device that estimates blood oxygen by analyzing the light absorbed in an extremity, usually a finger—and more rigorous (and invasive) analyses of arterial blood gas differed substantially depending on whether the patient was Black or white. Moreover, Black patients tended to get more optimistic readings from the oximeter. Such inaccuracies could quite possibly lead to worse clinical outcomes and could be particularly detrimental when treating COVID-19 as careful monitoring of patients’ blood oxygen levels can trigger lifesaving medical care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against the backdrop of the ongoing global conversation about racism and bias, one might ask whether the pulse oximeters in this study are racist. Can a piece of hardware even be racist?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/racist-hardware-and-what-to-do-about-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/racist-hardware-and-what-to-do-about-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        <category>Makerspace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2021.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we (happily) say farewell to 2020, we at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) feel stronger and more optimistic than ever before. If 2020 taught us anything, it is that adaptation is paramount. The events of the last year have changed almost every aspect of how we think, work, and live, and we would be naïve to think that our digital toolkit won’t change right along with us. Therefore, heading into 2021, we have high ambitions to continue to analyze and elevate inclusive, ethical, human-focused digital products and services that can help us rise to the occasion and address some of the deeply complex issues that 2020 unveiled. Below are seven areas we look forward to exploring further throughout the year—so stay tuned and check back often.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Year%20in%20Review.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI 2020 Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has been a year like no other. While those of us in the development sector have long anticipated the increased frequency of once-in-a-lifetime events—as our social, environmental, political, and economic systems grow increasingly strained and interconnected—none of us expected these “problems of tomorrow” to arise as quickly, globally, and devastatingly as they did.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-2020-year-in-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-2020-year-in-review.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202020-12-22%20105419.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Addressing Concurrent Crises with Digital Tools: An ICTforAg Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back on 2020, it is still difficult for me to comprehend the many challenges the world faced this year and their implications for agriculture and resilience. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20200806-the-biblical-east-african-locust-plagues-of-2020&quot;&gt;locust outbreak in East Africa&lt;/a&gt;, to wildfires and extreme weather events, and of course, the COVID-19 pandemic, this year has made it clear that in a world increasingly shaped by unpredictability, the digital development community can no longer afford to address one specific challenge at a time. This year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictforag.com/&quot;&gt;ICTforAg&lt;/a&gt; conference invited its speakers and participants to reflect on this reality and discover how digital tools and technologies can help us respond to concurrent—and increasingly frequent—crises worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/addressing-concurrent-crises-with-digital-tools-an-ictforag-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/addressing-concurrent-crises-with-digital-tools-an-ictforag-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Resilience</category>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
