<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:36:55 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 13:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sound%20blog%20photo%203.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Asia Accelerator Cultivates Digital Skills for Cambodia’s Creative Sector</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread digitalization has revolutionized almost every industry, including music and sound production. While rarely the focus of digital development initiatives, creative entrepreneurs like artists and musicians in emerging economies have also found themselves scrambling to adapt to the ever-changing technology and social media landscapes. As such, this year, with funding from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/Digital_Asia_Accelerator_Fact_Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;USAID’s Digital Asia Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; (DAA) initiative and as a part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-connectivity-cybersecurity-partnership&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesoundinitiative.com/&quot;&gt;The Sound Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (TSI) – a vocational program for musicians – launched their “Music 4.0” program to support Cambodian entrepreneurs striving to excel in this dynamical industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sound%20blog%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sound blog 1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: TSI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole/">Kendra Poole</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/irene-hang-81b817194/">Hangveng Horng</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/music-4-dot-0-digital-skills-for-the-creative-sector.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/music-4-dot-0-digital-skills-for-the-creative-sector.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/50267038282_392bac077d_o-843190.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New Report Offers Guidance to Support Agriculture Market Systems Actors During COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital tools and services like short message services (SMS), digitally enabled extension services, and artificial intelligence have helped market system actors in developing countries overcome common challenges in the agriculture sector, such as accessing weather information and diagnosing pest or disease outbreaks. Despite the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openknowledge.worldbank.org/bitstream/handle/10986/35216/9781464816574.pdf?sequence=2&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&quot;&gt;documented value&lt;/a&gt; of these innovations, uptake of digital agriculture technology still is not widespread. A lack of affordable and accessible technologies, poor connectivity, high costs of data, and social stigmas around digital technology can be major barriers to potential users. With COVID-19 making digital connectivity critical to economic activities, development stakeholders have spent the past year and a half assessing the relationship between the pandemic and the adoption and use of digital agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructing a Rapid Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support market system actors as they navigate the opportunities and challenges of digital transformation amidst COVID-19, the U.S Agency for International Development (USAID) Bureau for Resilience and Food Security employed the DAI-managed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project to commission a rapid analysis. The analysis aimed to understand the impacts of digital tools among agricultural market system actors concerning COVID-19. The analysis focused on three key objectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Identifying and analyzing the trends driving the adoption of digital tools in agriculture market systems in response to the global pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing examples of such digital solutions across market system actors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing concrete and actionable recommendations for USAID Missions and implementing partners to ensure that digital tools can be used effectively to increase resilience in the face of future threats.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team focused on eight countries: Bangladesh, Ghana, Guatemala, Kenya, Malawi, Nepal, Niger, and Senegal. Findings demonstrated that market actors increased their use of digital solutions as a result of the pandemic, while digital service providers moved quickly to launch and adapt their existing services to meet the evolving needs of their customers. Researchers also observed that the rapid onset of the pandemic led market system actors to reach for familiar tools or services already available to continue operations. Very few market actors adopted “newly” launched digital solutions in direct response to COVID-19. (The full research findings are discussed in more depth &lt;a href=&quot;https://agrilinks.org/post/digital-solutions-agriculture-market-systems-responding-covid-19&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/16MpY2XpJxE1pZHDgN1bhw_opKuEQYJAt/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; itself.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/50267038282_392bac077d_o-843190.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50267038282_392bac077d_o-843190.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo Credit: Flickr - Sanjoy Chandra Bhattacherjee&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Research to Action&lt;/strong&gt;
The research team developed a group of supplemental guidance documents to help donors and implementing partners support agriculture market actors respond to shocks like COVID-19 and beyond. The documents focus on three digitally enabled solutions—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/E-Commerce_FRMT-dae762.pdf&quot;&gt;E-commerce Marketplaces&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/FarmerManagement_FRMT-53bd30.pdf&quot;&gt;Farmer Management Solutions&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/MobilePhone_FRMT-f14de6.pdf&quot;&gt;Expanding Mobile Phone Access and Ownership&lt;/a&gt;— and highlight how these solutions work, how they’ve been used in different contexts, and how they can be assessed and introduced. While I strongly recommend exploring these guidance documents for helpful tips, I summarized a few of the standard checklist items below. I hope they are helpful for those in the process of supporting market system actors through the ever-changing landscape that COVID-19 has introduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assess the Landscape&lt;/strong&gt;: Before introducing any new digital solution, it is critical first to conduct a landscape or market assessment to determine if it is the right fit for your target population. Determine the size of the potential customer base, whether there is demand for such a solution, what similar solutions are already available in the marketplace, any potential supply- and demand-side constraints, and relevant user information such as the degree to which they already use digital tools, their literacy levels, and barriers to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test and Engage&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not be afraid to test out promising solutions identified during your assessment. The guidance recommends that for publicly accessible services like e-commerce platforms, implementers and donors should set up accounts to log in and explore the platform’s functionality. Pay special attention to the type and quantity of items sold, user-friendliness, and branding. Chances are, if you find a platform challenging or confusing to use, so will others. Reach out to the digital service provider to identify opportunities for collaboration and ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare for Partnerships&lt;/strong&gt;: Strategic partnerships are an essential part of bringing digital solutions to scale. Some partnerships institutions—such as banks, mobile network operators, and wholesale mobile phone vendors—operate outside of the development world, -which can help provide users with digital devices at more affordable costs. Securing such partnerships and making them sustainable requires preparation. Be prepared to discuss the potential market opportunities that further engagement would bring and anticipate the partner’s expectations and risks. Do not forget to provide data, reports, or business case studies to convey how said risks have and can be mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consult Your Stakeholders&lt;/strong&gt;: When considering introducing a new solution, organize stakeholder meetings with key influencers such as farmer groups, agribusinesses, buyers, implementing partners, digital service providers, key digital experts, donors, and other private sector members. Organizing these meetings ensures knowledge collaboration and can help gather consensus around the digital solution’s viability. Stakeholder meetings can serve as opportunities to pause and reflect. If stakeholder consultations deem the tool unsuitable, there is no shame in pursuing other digital or non-digital avenues! However, if the solution is ideal, stakeholder meetings offer a space to discuss the next steps for digital service providers, users, and other potential partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Action and Provide Support&lt;/strong&gt;: If an appropriate digital solution is identified—great! The market system actors your activity is targeting should already be aware of the solution if they attended the stakeholder consultations. If they expressed interest in pursuing it further, there are plenty of ways to provide support to ensure that they can sustainably benefit from the solution long after your project has ceased. Options include providing capacity-building support to users or service providers, and developing action plans, conducting risk assessments, running cost analyses, and offering training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share What You’ve Learned&lt;/strong&gt;: Last but not least, share your findings! Let your colleagues, counterparts, and fellow digital development professionals know how the solution is working and any measurable outcomes. Capturing outcomes—such as an increase in income or improvements in quality or quantity of produce sold—all contribute to the evidence base for digital agricultural solutions to help funders determine scalable or investment-worthy solutions. If and when we face another massive global disruption like COVID-19, knowing which digital solutions lead to measurable outcomes can help make agricultural market systems around the world more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-report-offers-guidance-to-support-agriculture-market-systems-actors-during-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-report-offers-guidance-to-support-agriculture-market-systems-actors-during-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5771025070_bddb7e2ec6_b-0a13fb.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Tools to Foster Creative Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we peel back the planning, strategy design, project management, and technical implementation layers of any creation, we see something more intuitive. More human. And that’s the desire to “create.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terms such as “innovation,” “research and development,” and “discovery” capture the adventure of the creative process. But garnering that same intensity in a workplace, let alone one’s personal life is not always the most accessible trail. In this post, I dive into some tools we employ as a team to foster creative innovation while also making reflections from another part of my life as a musician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a musician, I’ve gone through many periods of creative productivity. “Writer’s block,” as some may relate to, is the most frustrating. A quick online search generates tons of books on how to overcome creative dry spells. Meditation, exercise, and just taking a good ol’ break are some of the well-known remedies. But if there’s one thing I’ve learned from songwriting and performing, it’s that the creative process requires gentle nurturing. And just like music production, technology product development is no stranger to creative dry spells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are some of the tools we employ as a team to foster creative technology product development?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-tools-to-foster-creative-innovation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-tools-to-foster-creative-innovation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AS4-bc3155.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Digital Climate Risk Assessment Tools Help Unclog Climate Finance Flows in Emerging Economies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional lending channels are blocking access to climate finance. The large commercial banks that receive funds from investment banks accredited by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenclimate.fund/&quot;&gt;Green Climate Fund&lt;/a&gt; typically seek smaller financial institutions in local markets to distribute these funds. However, these smaller institutions often lack the tools needed to appraise risk and begin lending, meaning that funds that have been allocated towards climate mitigation, resilience building, and adaptation efforts are not being efficiently disseminated.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/bhairav-raja">Bhairav Raja</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-digital-climate-risk-assessment-tools-can-help-unclog-climate-finance-flows-in-emerging-economies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-digital-climate-risk-assessment-tools-can-help-unclog-climate-finance-flows-in-emerging-economies.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/joshua-sukoff-5DDYHjk_KMU-unsplash_thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Reflecting on the Role of Digital Solutions in Tackling USAID’s Global Priorities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As most people in the international development community know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/samantha-power&quot;&gt;Samantha Power&lt;/a&gt;, former U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations under President Barack Obama, was nominated and officially sworn in as the 19th Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) on May 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During her confirmation hearing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreign.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/032321_Power_Testimony.pdf&quot;&gt;testimony&lt;/a&gt;, she acknowledged the longstanding priorities of USAID that would remain at the fore, such as women’s empowerment, food security, education, and global health, but also cited four particularly pressing and consequential global issues on which USAID would focus in the years ahead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Climate change&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Conflict and state collapse&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Democratic backsliding&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about these priorities and what they mean for development work in the coming years, I thought about how digital solutions fit into this picture. Though not called out specifically in her testimony, digital technologies will serve a critical role in ensuring the success and effectiveness of these efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/reflecting-on-the-role-of-digital-solutions-in-tackling-usaids-global-priorities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/reflecting-on-the-role-of-digital-solutions-in-tackling-usaids-global-priorities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CoverPhoto.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Request for Information: Exploring the Role of AI and Automation on Agrifood Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) applications are rapidly evolving to include more complex and advanced tasks. As a result, the number of meaningful use cases relevant to the development sector are expanding and demonstrate significant potential to solve some of the world’s most prominent challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CoverPhoto.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;CoverPhoto.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 08:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lilyana-gabrielse-8bb40b1bb/">Lilyana Gabrielse</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/request-for-information-exploring-the-role-of-ai-and-automation-on-agri-food-systems.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/request-for-information-exploring-the-role-of-ai-and-automation-on-agri-food-systems.html</guid>
        
        <category>RFI</category>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FAW1-9d6f2d.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What We Learned From a Deep Dive into the World of Prizes and Challenges</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, our colleagues at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/USAID_Digital_Asia_Accelerator_Fact_Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Digital Asia Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; buy-in under the Digital Frontiers project asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alexander-sekhniashvili/&quot;&gt;Alex Sekhniashvili&lt;/a&gt; and I to identify and synthesize lessons learned administering prizes and challenges across the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) portfolio. Given DAI’s long history implementing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-grand-challenges-development-implementation-services&quot;&gt;Grand Challenges for Development Implementation Services&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-center-development-innovation-professional-management-services&quot;&gt;Center for Development Innovation (CDI) Professional Management Services,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; projects on behalf of USAID—there are quite a lot of lessons! So Alex and I dove deep into the world of prizes and challenges, reading project documents and interviewing a number of DAI staff. Read below some of our findings.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-deep-dive-into-prizes-and-challenges-what-has-dai-learned.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-deep-dive-into-prizes-and-challenges-what-has-dai-learned.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Prizes</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Tiffany.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Platform Unites Afghan Activists</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/afghanistan-musharikat&quot;&gt;Promote: Musharikat&lt;/a&gt; program has been promoting the meaningful civic participation of Afghan women. To date, more than 7,000 activists and 370 civil society organizations (CSO), across all 34 of Afghanistan’s provinces, have chosen to join DAI-led Musharikat to advance women’s equality and empowerment. By working through coalitions, Musharikat brings together citizen activists, government officials, religious scholars, and a diverse assemblage of CSOs to bolster both the supply and demand for women’s rights in Afghanistan. Though each coalition has a specific mandate, their shared vision of a peaceful, inclusive, and equitable country provides a common cause for action. This mission includes public awareness campaigns, building the capacity of those championing change, and working with government institutions to vigorously enforce and reform laws to fulfill their duty to the nation’s largest underserved constituency—women.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andyjyates/">Andy Yates</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-platform-unites-afghan-activists.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-platform-unites-afghan-activists.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Afghanistan</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ICTforAg%20By%20the%20Numbers.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Implement the Next ICTforAg Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictforag.com/&quot;&gt;ICTforAg 2020&lt;/a&gt; engaged a global audience of 1,502 participants across 26 sessions over the course of one day. The conference examined digital solutions in agriculture as a means of fostering resilience in the wake of disruptions, from climate-related disasters to COVID-19, and the intersections between them. Building on the momentum of this global event, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; team is supporting the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-resilience-and-food-security&quot;&gt;Bureau for Resilience and Food Security&lt;/a&gt; in the next ICTforAg conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ICTforAg%20By%20the%20Numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;ICTforAg By the Numbers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-implement-the-next-ictforag-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-implement-the-next-ictforag-conference.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>RFP</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/mx_fco_6_22_fig_4.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Job Postings from Mexico's Energy Sector Reveal About the State of Clean Energy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A significant challenge to achieving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sustainable_Development_Goals&quot;&gt;Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/a&gt; has been measuring country progress in the transition to renewable and clean energy sources. While expert surveys or legislation enacted may provide some insight into how countries are progressing on the whole, they lack the granularity to inform us about subnational trends, skills in-demand, and the presence of firms and subsectors within each country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One useful way to explore these factors is by analyzing data available from job search engines and using keywords related to the energy sector. These can provide insights on how jobs in key sectors and subsectors evolve over time, what the demand for labor among firms in the energy sector is, where these openings and firms are located, and how they differ in terms of skills sought in the labor market.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/jamie-parr/">Jamie Parr</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-larios-v%C3%A1zquez-/">Andrea Guadalupe Larios Vázquez</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-p%C3%A9rez-barn%C3%A9s-2b810a1a/">Javier Pérez Barnés</a>, <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/estera-barbarasa">Estera Barbarasa</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramon-olivas/?originalSubdomain=mx">Ramon Olivas</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-can-we-learn-from-job-postings-in-the-energy-sector-evidence-from-mexico.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-can-we-learn-from-job-postings-in-the-energy-sector-evidence-from-mexico.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Environment &amp; Energy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
