<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 16:44:05 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 16:44:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Flagged for Review: A Look at Hate Speech in the International Development Context</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many countries &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globesmart.com/blog/celebrating-lgbt-pride-around-the-world-things-to-know/&quot;&gt;around the world&lt;/a&gt; recognize June as Pride Month—a time to celebrate lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ) people, while reflecting on the community’s history. But this year it’s not just sunshine and rainbows. In cyberspace, the discourse about LGBTQ people and their rights is increasingly crowded with hate speech. On any given day, my own Twitter feed is sprinkled with posts arguing that LGBTQ people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/05/11/1096623939/accusations-grooming-political-attack-homophobic-origins&quot;&gt;“grooming”&lt;/a&gt; children, claiming &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benshapiro/status/1536667667150651392?s=21&quot;&gt;same-sex couples&lt;/a&gt; shouldn’t be represented in Disney movies, or attacking the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/anti-lgbtq-threats-orchestrated-on-internet-shut-down-events-rcna33955&quot;&gt;validity and humanity&lt;/a&gt; of transgender people. While I find these messages deeply distressing, I’m forced to ask myself, “Is this hate speech?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I’m going to use the example of LGBTQ hate speech to lay out what hate speech is, link it to the international development context, and explore what social media platforms and other stakeholders are doing to combat hate speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image: Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 14:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Nancy Haugh
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/flagged-for-review-a-look-at-hate-speech-in-the-international-development-context.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/flagged-for-review-a-look-at-hate-speech-in-the-international-development-context.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Rights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Communications</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Model.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>USAID Launches Digital Government Model</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2021, as people around the world—and their governments—were grappling with a rapid transition to digital technology, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalfrontiersdai.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project began working with the Technology Division of USAID’s Innovation, Technology, and Research (ITR/T) Hub to create a conceptual model of digital government, or e-government. That model is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-government-model&quot;&gt;live&lt;/a&gt; and available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/usaid-launches-its-digital-government-model.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/usaid-launches-its-digital-government-model.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Government</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/mars-sector-6-IgUR1iX0mqM-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Literacy Series: The DigComp Framework</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the onset of the pandemic spurring ever-faster digitalization around the world, we at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration are thinking about the key elements needed to ensure sustainable digital transformation in the countries where we work. One of the primary building blocks needed to achieve sustainability is strengthening digital literacy. As digital development practitioners, digital literacy is a big part of our work. Whether a person is getting online for the first time or is a cyber specialist, we have a responsibility to ensure those we work with have the agency to use the appropriate technology meaningfully: to achieve professional and personal goals, while avoiding digital harm. We also have a responsibility to close the digital divide by supporting novices in developing basic skills, so they are not left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Carrington
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AIGraphic.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Four Awardees Are Paving the Way for a More Equitable AI-Powered Future</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-the-winners-of-usaids-equitable-ai-challenge&quot;&gt;Introducing the Winners of USAID’s Equitable AI Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) tools are a dual-edged sword: they promise tremendous benefits for international development, but have also demonstrated instances of bias and harm, often resulting from inequitable design, use, and impact. Recognizing that AI technologies can cause gender biases, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) urgently looked for innovative and creative approaches to address gender-inequitable outcomes by launching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictworks.org/gender-equitable-artificial-intelligence-outcomes/#.YnPvuejMKUl&quot;&gt;Equitable AI Challenge&lt;/a&gt; in the fall of 2021. This challenge, implemented through DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;, sought to support approaches that increase the accountability and transparency of AI systems in global development contexts. Dozens of competitors submitted approaches related to the prevention, identification, or monitoring of bias and harm against women and gender-nonconforming people—reflecting the larger goals of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/usaid-digital-strategy&quot;&gt;USAID’s Digital Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/oct-26-2021-administrator-samantha-power-first-ever-national-strategy-gender&quot;&gt;National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality&lt;/a&gt;, and the recently launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/artificial-intelligence-action-plan&quot;&gt;USAID AI Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-four-awardees-are-paving-the-way-for-a-more-equitable-ai-powered-future.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-four-awardees-are-paving-the-way-for-a-more-equitable-ai-powered-future.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Broken%20Bridge%20uMlazi.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Drone Mapping Reflects Solid Waste and Ocean Plastic Impact of the Durban Floods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Heavy downpours over only two days in April 2022 caused South Africa’s worst and most deadly natural disaster to date: a flash flood so rare and devastating it has a one in the 300-year probability of recurring. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://erccportal.jrc.ec.europa.eu/ECHO-Products/Echo-Flash#/daily-flash-archive/4474&quot;&gt;European Union&lt;/a&gt;, approximately 435 people died and up to 41,000 people were affected. Rescue and disaster response efforts, which began immediately, are ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/716884061?h=ff95501847&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 13:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-palfreman-wastewash/?originalSubdomain=za">Joshua Palfreman</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/drone-mapping-reflects-solid-waste-and-ocean-plastic-impact-of-the-durban-floods.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/drone-mapping-reflects-solid-waste-and-ocean-plastic-impact-of-the-durban-floods.html</guid>
        
        <category>Environment</category>
        
        <category>Waste Management</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/pexels-sergio-souza-3907943%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Can the Mexican Automotive Industry Capitalize on Data-Driven Global Value Chains?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smart factories could position Mexico as an Industry 4.0 hub and open doors to data-driven global value chains (GVCs).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mexico is embracing Industry 4.0. The digital factory in Puebla, the aerospace corridors in Querétaro, Guanajuato, Baja California, Sonora, Chihuahua, and Nuevo León showcase Industry 4.0 manufacturing throughout the country. Smart factories are facilities that primarily use automated tools and machines, from production robots to transportation devices or 3D printers. Products are equipped with sensors that allow them to connect and exchange data and communicate with each other. They make up a cyber-physical production system (CPPS) connected via the industrial Internet of Things (IoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data are the smart factory’s blood vessels and the key enabler of modern global value chains (GVCs). In the networked smart factory, identities can be assigned to tools, machines, products, and materials. Items at each level of the GVC can thereby be precisely located and tracked. This networked and automated production environment is supplemented with “big data” (huge amounts of data from millions of nodes within a network, including the ability to process and analyze large amounts of data using cloud computing, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning). Data can be handled, processed, and analyzed in real time and passed on through GVCs. Greater customization is possible while retaining speed and efficiency. Individual products are networked and identifiable; customization is possible by drawing on user data, while customer data is directly transferred to machine data. Cloud computing and additive manufacturing enable decentralized production.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mimistankovic/">Miriam Stankovich</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/agustin-filippo-3586814/">Agustin Filippo</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>industry 4.0</category>
        
        <category>Smart Factory</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Main%20Cover%202022%20Digis.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: 2022 USAID Digital Development Awards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you used digital technology to promote locally led development? Have you safeguarded digital ecosystems by facilitating access to digital infrastructure for marginalized populations, securing internet freedom and human rights, exposing violent extremism, countering misinformation and disinformation, or strengthening cybersecurity?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Awards</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Rights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture%20digital%20upskilling%20pwd.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Realizing Inclusive Digital Development Through Boosting the Digital Skills of People Living with Disabilities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five percent of the nearly 1 billion people living with disabilities around the world live at or below the poverty line. Unfortunately, these roughly 250 million people are more likely to face obstacles ranging from finding employment to outright discrimination. However, digital technologies offer the potential to expand employment opportunities for people living with disabilities, allowing them to realize their capabilities, expand their networks, and increase their mobility through digital accessibility. DAI, implementing activities under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP)&lt;/a&gt;, is designing activities that create employment opportunities and support networks for people living with disabilities in countries such as Cambodia and India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its work with the Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) and the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI), DAI recognizes disability as a cross-cutting issue and strives to provide equitable access to digital tools for people with a wide array of abilities, including those who are hard of hearing, have visual impairments, speech impediments, or other learning, developmental, and psychosocial disabilities. DAI’s grantee organizations, consultants, and partners are making significant steps towards digital inclusion through the facilitation of trainings, workshops, and mentoring groups specifically targeted and tailored for people living with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-anderson-2b69391b6/">Jeremy Anderson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/My%20project.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 5—Developing Community Support</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge&lt;/a&gt; is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round of the Challenge, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified five proven strategies for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bihar, India, Mahadalit women are regarded as the poorest, lowest caste and are often isolated due to cultural barriers, social norms, and rural location. Mahadalit women are also at high risk of becoming victims of rape or sexual harassment, often perpetrated by members of upper castes. The looming threat of violence, caste discrimination, and subsequent deprivation of social benefits and entitlements often silence and silo women, hindering their ability to self-advocate or come together to work for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troubled by these injustices, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gramvaani.org/&quot;&gt;Gram Vaani&lt;/a&gt;—the creator of Mobile Vaani, a social media platform specifically designed and adapted for use in rural communities—applied for a grant through the USAID WomenConnect Challenge (WCC), which works to change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. With the help of this USAID funding, Gram Vaani developed a new, free, voice-based media platform called &lt;a href=&quot;http://mobilevaani.in/vaani/#/1/home&quot;&gt;Meri Awaaz Meri Pehchan&lt;/a&gt; (MAMP, translated as “My Voice My Identity”) to help create a safe space for women’s interaction and education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MAMP platform featured content specifically designed for women, including news, community information, inspirational stories, and a 38-episode drama series based on a fictitious character named Munni, a local girl facing social, cultural, and economic pressures with which other women might relate. The platform also incorporated a verbal chat room for women, introducing the desired safe space for information exchange and resource pooling. Women posted comments, questions, or updates on local news and information, encouraging them to voice their opinions and concerns and drive conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1-65d9dd.png&quot; alt=&quot;Picture1-65d9dd.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo Credit: GramVaani, Caption: GramVaani developed a mobile phone-based platform that allows women to learn from their peers and discuss collective solutions to their most pressing challenges.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea of this platform—MAMP—was to drive cross-sharing and peer-learning on several issues and themes around women’s empowerment. Mostly socio-cultural issues like child marriage, dowry, property ownership of women, girl child education, etc.,” explained Sayonee Chatterjee, former Director of Content Operations at Gram Vaani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a sense, the WomenConnect Challenge happened at a very interesting time,” added Ritesh Datta, former Gram Vaani Director for Programs and Partnerships. “Gram Vaani, at that point, traditionally had a strong presence in the communities… And we were already looking for strategies, plans, and of course funding to engage more women.” Serendipitously, USAID selected Gram Vaani as one of its WCC first-round awardees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a sense, the WomenConnect Challenge happened at a very interesting time,” added Ritesh Datta, former Gram Vaani Director for Programs and Partnerships. “Gram Vaani, at that point, traditionally had a strong presence in the communities… And we were already looking for strategies, plans, and of course funding to engage more women.” Serendipitously, USAID selected Gram Vaani as one of its WCC first-round awardees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the communities where Gram Vaani implemented its WCC programming, the barriers to women’s use of technology—and thus the Mobile Vaani platform—were primarily socio-cultural. “It’s not that women do not have access to basic feature phones. They have access,” Chatterjee clarified. “Almost every household, even in the remotest, rural [part of] Bihar, has at least one basic feature phone. But that basic feature phone generally lies with the men of the household… And there’s a huge taboo around women using mobile phones independently. Because that supposedly sheds a light on their ‘bad character.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revi Sterling, Director of the WomenConnect Challenge, reflected on this prevalent taboo around women’s access to new technologies during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLd1A49D9AiwWfqIuMDKK5BJnAnhVwTOgH&quot;&gt;“WomenConnect Challenge Steps to Success” webinar series&lt;/a&gt;. “As we know, empowered women are terrifying to the status quo,” she stated. “We can select Band-Aids to repair the gender digital divide, and we have forever. ‘Here’s a computer training course, subsidized phones, subsidized airtime…’ none of those things are sustainable,” Sterling elaborated. “What the WomenConnect Challenge is really about is understanding exactly the cultural context of the communities that we are trying to engage in and then creating appropriate, sustainable, and gender equitable solutions that have full community support.” Gram Vaani, uniquely situated to understand nuanced social and cultural contexts in the Bihar region, agreed that the most sustainable solutions to the gender digital divide need to be incubated in the communities themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We conducted something we call ‘a content needs assessment’ to understand the local context,” Chatterjee said. “[The] topics, issues, came up from the community. After that, we packaged several studio-generated content modules to excite, stir, encourage the women to share their own opinions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When given a platform of communication such as MAMP, many women choose to champion issues disproportionately affecting women, such as gender-based violence and access to finance or government programs. When such advocates band together as a group, the impact of their efforts expands substantially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many community grievances shared on the platform were then addressed by local officials, further encouraging the women’s civic engagement. “That was the goal,” affirmed Chatterjee. “To engage them through these platforms so that they can then be empowered… to go to the relevant stakeholders, demand their rights, and participate in the political processes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In India, village communities routinely hold a meeting called a “Gram Sabha” to discuss local governance and development issues and negotiate need-based plans for the village. Participation of women in Gram Sabhas was traditionally very low in Bihar, as the meetings were widely considered a man’s duty to attend. “Women who are not elected representatives, they do not go into these kinds of discussions and meetings and forums,” shared Chatterjee. “So, we encouraged a lot of women to participate in a Gram Sabha meeting [for the first time], and many of them actually raised issues pertaining to the development of their own areas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, Mobile Vaani helped empower women not just politically but also interpersonally. “My life has changed because of Mobile Vaani,” shared one user, “Since the time of my marriage I have been emotionally abused by my in-laws. I never felt like raising a voice against that and kept quiet. The programs on MAMP showed me a new way. I shared my pain with one of the Mobile Vaani didis, and she requested me to voice my concerns to my husband. [She also] spoke to my in-laws and explained why their behavior is improper. A lot has changed since then. My in-laws started behaving nicely with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gram Vaani reported not only helping empower individual women but also witnessing a ripple effect. “I recall a story of a specific girl,” reflected Chatterjee, “A girl who herself escaped child marriage through the help of our intervention when she called up the child protection number that we publicized… Her marriage was stopped, and, in turn, she actually helped stop several other child marriages… She herself has stopped around eight to ten child marriages happening in her own family and her own village.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The partnership between Gram Vaani and USAID under the WCC successfully provided thousands of women access to an engaging community media platform, which proved to sustainably catalyze opportunities for empowerment and collective action across the community. Sterling reflected: “Gram Vaani helped isolated, rural women feel empowered to voice their opinions and create meaningful interactions, giving them the confidence to become advocates for their community, for their families, and for themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The WomenConnect Challenge is implemented by DAI’s Digital Frontiers project, a buy-in mechanism that works closely with USAID Missions and Bureaus, the private sector, and international and local development organizations to identify successful and sustainable digital development approaches and scale their impact globally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 12:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole/">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-5-developing-community-support.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-5-developing-community-support.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platform</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/michal-dziekonski-21e67o9NxAA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Technology and Design Podcasts to Explore this Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the weather gets warmer in the Mid-Atlantic region, I’ve been doing my best to get outside more during the day. Podcasts have been a pleasant addition to my walk, runs, and bike rides. Below are five can’t-miss tech podcasts that you should follow—all of which are insightful, engaging, and informative.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
