<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 08:37:36 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 08:37:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ericablog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Information Liberation, Part 2: Bringing the Private Sector into the Movement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open-data sharing can offer huge benefits for development. How do we get the private sector to contribute?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog—&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-what-is-open-data-and-why-does-it-matter.html&quot;&gt;Information Liberation: What is Open Data, and Why Does it Matter?&lt;/a&gt;—posted back in April, I wrote about the Open Data Movement, including its origins, advantages, and relevance to international development. The post referenced Microsoft’s announcement of its support for the movement, vowing to use the company’s resources to address the “data divide” that separates those with access to data and the ability to interpret it, from those without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With data comes power: the power to make better, smarter decisions; to use information to your advantage; to understand trends and predict future ones. No one knows this better than the private sector—experts in collecting, organizing, and interpreting data to improve business decisions and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 17:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-part-2-bringing-the-private-sector-into-the-movement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-part-2-bringing-the-private-sector-into-the-movement.html</guid>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/nepalecommerce.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking E-Commerce in Nepal with Sastodeal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We recently spoke with Amun Thapa, founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sastodeal.com/&quot;&gt;Sastodeal.com&lt;/a&gt; about Nepal’s growing e-commerce sector, the impact of COVID-19, and the company’s inclusive business model. This is an excerpt of that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/susannah-horton/">Susanah Horton</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-magid/">Ariel Magid</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-e-commerce-in-nepal-with-sastodeal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-e-commerce-in-nepal-with-sastodeal.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator</category>
        
        <category>E-Commerce</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/avc%20crops.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Success to Sustainability: Engaging Horticulturalists in Uzbekistan with Digital Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When DAI staff and partners ask us for examples of how our projects have successfully used digital tools, we inevitably describe the U.S. Agency for International Development-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/uzbekistan-usaid-agricultural-value-chain-activity-uzbekistan-uzbekistan-avc&quot;&gt;Uzbekistan Agricultural Value Chains (AVC)&lt;/a&gt; activity as one of the best examples. AVC strengthens agricultural value chains by engaging horticultural producers, processors, input suppliers, and exporters. With that goal in mind, it did not take long for the project to realize they could engage people through digital tools already widely used throughout the country to reach their target audience. They were right. A key part of this approach was understanding their audience and their social media habits—in short, knowing their users. As the project now looks to build on its success in using social media as a tool for development, it is creating a sustainability model based on insights from its target audience: horticulturalists in Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 06:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/talia-dweck/">Talia Dweck</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/gratiana-fu/">Gratiana Fu</a>, Komil Yakubov
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/success-to-sustainability-the-use-of-digital-tools-to-engage-horticulturalists-in-uzbekistan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/success-to-sustainability-the-use-of-digital-tools-to-engage-horticulturalists-in-uzbekistan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018%20MHI%20in%20the%20United%20States.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How the COVID-19 Pandemic is Accentuating the Digital Divide in the United States</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of us who work in digital development internationally, the pervasiveness of the global digital divide is constantly top of mind. The majority of our work requires us to understand the digital ecosystem in which we are operating to reach different segments of the population in a specific country. At home in the United States, COVID-19 and the push for virtual schooling and telemedicine has laid bare, for many Americans, how significant and challenging the digital divide is within the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aleblog.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Transforming In-Person Learning into Digital Collaboration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 pushed people into their homes and brought to light the different options that exist to transform the way we learn from in-person settings to online classrooms. Although online learning is not new, the adoption of these learning platforms by the general population has been slow in comparison to the development of new technology-enabled education solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 06:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/transforming-in-person-learning-into-digital.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/transforming-in-person-learning-into-digital.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/icons.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Are Algorithms and How Are They Biased?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Tech&quot;&gt;Big Tech&lt;/a&gt; and social media, the term &lt;em&gt;algorithm&lt;/em&gt; gets thrown around a lot to describe the unseen mechanism that determines what people see on social media or the suggestions that they receive on Netflix. But what exactly is an algorithm? And can an algorithm be biased?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/algorithms-in-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/algorithms-in-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Algorithmic Bias</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FTF_DF.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Host USAID’s first-ever Digital Development Online Training</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Global Development Lab, the Center for Digital Development (CDD) addresses gaps in digital access and affordability and advances the use of technology and advanced data analysis in development. DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project works closely with the CDD team to roll out and implement USAID’s Agency-wide Digital Strategy, which was released in April 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the Digital Strategy, the Digital Skills Initiative is developing training sessions and resources geared towards USAID staff. These resources will support staff to increase their understanding of–and ability to use–digital tools and skills.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 06:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-magid/">Ariel Magid</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-host-usaids-first-ever-digital-development-online-training.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-host-usaids-first-ever-digital-development-online-training.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Coronavirus-doc-telecom.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking Equitable Access to Healthcare During COVID-19 Pandemic with Vanderbilt Pediatrics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We recently spoke with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childrenshospitalvanderbilt.org/doctors/barkin-shari&quot;&gt;Shari Barkin&lt;/a&gt;, MD, MSHS, William K. Warren Foundation Chair in Medicine; Marian Wright Edelman Professor of Pediatrics; Director, Division of General Pediatrics, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, about how COVID-19 highlights issues around health equity and acts as a forcing mechanism for technology-driven innovation. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 06:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-equitable-access-to-healthcare-during-covid-19-with-vanderbilt-pediatrics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-equitable-access-to-healthcare-during-covid-19-with-vanderbilt-pediatrics.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Online%20Safety%20Campaign%202020.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Staying Safe Online—Cyber Hygiene Skills Strengthen Resilience for Small Business, Even In Times of Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As COVID-19 drives more people online for work, entertainment, and even connection to friends and family, digital and data security issues are increasingly important across the United States and around the world. However, citizen-focused digital and data security discussions are still in early stages in some countries, especially in Southeast Asia, and my home base, Cambodia. So—who really gets left behind? It is often the citizens and small companies that rely on digital tools, but do not all have strong cyber skills to safely do business online.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/staying-safe-online.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/staying-safe-online.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/WhatsApp%20Image%202020-07-04%20at%202.09.44%20PM_resize%20(1)_thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from a School Teacher: 5 Tips for Effective Distance Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the world was catapulted into a socially distant new reality earlier this year, donor-funded development projects have been forced to re-envision what it means to transfer knowledge, build capacity, and implement training for staff, partners, and beneficiaries. As a result, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has experienced a swell in requests to support the digital transformation of activities previously envisaged for in-person learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we work to scale support to meet this rising demand, who better to consult on the topic than school teachers? Teachers and students around the world were thrown into distance teaching with little notice and wildly varied levels of preparation. This disruption sparked newfound—but long deserved—teacher accolades from parents suddenly playing an intimate role in their child’s daily learning. Surely anyone with the ability to command a 6-year old’s attention from 30 miles away is worthy of our discipleship. So how did they do it and what did they learn? I spoke with elementary, middle, and high school teachers to glean their insights into engaging learners at a distance. While they had much to share on the matter, what I’ve highlighted below are those takeaways most applicable to the field of international development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Addie Ryan
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/distance-learning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/distance-learning.html</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
