<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:08:28 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:08:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>GeekFest 2017: Delving into Public Access with Duduzile Mkhwanazi of Project Isizwe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/geek%20fest%20smallest.jpg?download&quot; alt=&quot;geek fest logo&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;
Welcome to GeekFest 2017, a series of interviews featuring ICT4D thought leaders. Our goals for #geekfest2017 are: to highlight the people and organizations who are pushing the field in new directions, to feature their work and show how it’s different or new, and to support the overall growth of the ICT4D community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we are focusing on public access as a solution to closing the Digital Divide. Being able to access free public wifi can be crucial for those who cannot afford internet subscriptions: It can be the difference between finally finding that job, getting the training you need or linking up with a valuable investor for your new venture. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://a4ai.org/affordability-report/report/2017/&quot;&gt;2017 A4AI  Affordability Report&lt;/a&gt; noted the importance of public wifi for engendering use of the internet: Research shows public wifi as one of the most popular options for online access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down with Duduzile Mkhwanazi, CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projectisizwe.org/&quot;&gt;Project Isizwe&lt;/a&gt;-an organization making great strides in providing free public wifi in South Africa, a country where inequality is rife and the affordability of mobile data is just out of reach for many, despite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileconnectivityindex.com/#year=2016&amp;amp;zoneIsocode=ZAF&quot;&gt;99 percent 3G coverage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blog1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 11:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-delving-into-public-access-with-duduzile-mkhwanazi-project-isizwe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-delving-into-public-access-with-duduzile-mkhwanazi-project-isizwe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Geekfest 2017</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Practicing the Principles for Digital Development in East Africa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by Mustapha Issa, Field Manager and MAST Coordinator and Gilead Mushaija, GIS Database Specialist, both from DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/tanzania-feed-future-tanzania-land-tenure-assistance-lta&quot;&gt;Feed the Future Land Tenure Assistance project.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa-tickets-37822273438&quot;&gt;Practicing the Principles for Digital Development&lt;/a&gt; event on October 12 in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania, 80 participants from organizations including DAI, the Ministry of Works, Transport, and Communications, and private organizations from Ethiopia, Kenya, Malawi, Rwanda, Tanzania, and Uganda attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalimpactalliance.org/&quot;&gt;Digital Impact Alliance&lt;/a&gt; (DIAL) and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hdif-tz.org/&quot;&gt;Human Development Innovation Fund Tanzania&lt;/a&gt; (HDIF-UKAid) stewarded the event and were joined by leading organizations in endorsing the Digital Principles. DAI is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/endorse/endorsers/&quot;&gt;signatory to the Principles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 11:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gilead-mushaija-b015aa33/">Gilead Mishaija</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mustapha-issa-93b3a014a/">Mustapha Issa</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Key Takeaways from USAID’s New Gender and ICT Survey Toolkit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week USAID’s Global Development Lab and mStar project released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/Gender_and_ICT_Toolkit.pdf&quot;&gt;Gender and ICT Survey Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;. In an informative webinar (you can listen to the recording &lt;a href=&quot;http://solutionscenter.nethope.org/webinars/view/introducing-usaids-gender-and-ict-toolkit&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), the team that produced the report discussed both the content and the context surrounding the genesis of the toolkit. I tuned in and spent the majority of the time silently cheering, thrilled to hear USAID promoting research tactics and information needs that align with what we on DAI’s ICT team are doing with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Digital Insights&lt;/a&gt; work. In between cheers, I feverishly took notes and captured these three key takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/three-key-takeaways-from-usaids-new-gender-and-ict-survey-toolkit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/three-key-takeaways-from-usaids-new-gender-and-ict-survey-toolkit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Testing Data Collection with OpenDataKit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Primary data collection: One of the most challenging, but necessary, components of any research project. Mobile and browser-based technologies have revolutionized the speed and efficiency of collecting data, enabling teams to work together on a centralized database without the headache of managing paper forms, or multiple excel documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this article, it’s likely you’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/forms/about/&quot;&gt;Googleforms&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/&quot;&gt;Survey Monkey&lt;/a&gt; for your work. But what if you need to collect data in regions without 3G or LTE coverage? You’ll need a tool to manage offline data collection, and load the data once you access a wireless internet connection. Fortunately, there are several tools designed to do just that, and one of them is completely free and open source. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendatakit.org/&quot;&gt;OpenDataKit&lt;/a&gt; (ODK). Let’s take a look at how this technology works.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/data-collection-with-opendatakit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/data-collection-with-opendatakit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Innovation in 60 Minutes or Less</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we do “open innovation,” it’s essential to define the problem we are trying to solve. And crucial to that process is crafting a good “Call.”  Can this be done in 60 minutes or less?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/workshop-5df2eb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workshop-5df2eb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAI facilitated workshop on open innovation at the Triangle Global Health Conference in Raleigh, North Carolina.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 16:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-innovation-in-60-minutes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-innovation-in-60-minutes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Second Chance Fund: Learning and Iteration with Tech in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any honest digital designer will admit it: Most tech tools fail. At least the first time around. Getting your users to drop the old way of doing things and use your new website (or gadget, or app) isn’t easy. It doesn’t matter if it visualizes their transactions in some really clever way, or sends their user data to the cloud for real-time analysis, or even if it saves them time or money. Behavior change is difficult, and doubly so when you’re designing across cultures. Why? A few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia-second-chance-fund.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia-second-chance-fund.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investments in Internet Access Must Include Investments in “Critical Digital Literacy”</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Expanding internet access in ‘last-mile markets’ is a priority for development agencies—and rightly so. The economic costs to countries that do not offer their populations internet access is high: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canback.com/files/2014_Offline_and_falling_behind_Barriers_to_Internet_adoption.pdf&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; have detailed the internet’s macroeconomic boost to GDP, the economic and employment benefits of the growth in the digital sector, and the impact of ICT on small business revenue and job creation. Internet access has also been shown to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/wdr2016&quot;&gt;improve learning and health&lt;/a&gt; outcomes and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/ie/Documents/TechnologyMediaCommunications/2014_uk_tmt_value_of_connectivity_deloitte_ireland.pdf&quot;&gt;catalyze civic engagement&lt;/a&gt;. Reading these reports, it seems we’re in an all-hands-on-deck moment to get bandwidth into every last corner of the earth. But what about the risks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/fake%20news.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fake news.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo from Kenyan Daily Star&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 11:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/investments-in-internet-access-must-include-investments-in-critical-digital-literacy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/investments-in-internet-access-must-include-investments-in-critical-digital-literacy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Catalyzing Ghana’s Growing AgriTech Ecosystem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the wrap-up piece for 2017 in our ongoing series about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosmosinnovationcenter.com/&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC) Ghana and its annual AgriTech Challenge, which DAI supports and helps implement. We’ll pick this series back up again for KIC’s 2018 cohort, but in the meantime, browse our KIC archives &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/women-in-agritech-profiles-from-ghana.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/ict-in-the-agricultural-sector-business-concepts-from-ghanaian-youth.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/ghana-agritech-exchange.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 02:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html</guid>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Series Part 3: Spatial Analysis with QGIS (Article 2/2)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-series-spatial-analysis-with-qgis.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I introduced QGIS, and previewed some of the basic functions in the upcoming release of Version 3.0. In this second of two articles, I’ll compare using QGIS in professional organizations to the use of proprietary software, and provide recommendations for organizations seeking to test the waters with spatial analysis. I’ve also reached out to three GIS professionals with experience integrating spatial analysis software into diplomatic and development work environments, and shared their perspectives in a Q&amp;amp;A section below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/logo_evolution.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo_evolution.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-series-spatial-analysis-with-qgis-article-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-series-spatial-analysis-with-qgis-article-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Management Series Part 3: Painting a Vivid Picture with Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back! After reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=data-management-series&quot;&gt;previous two posts in this series&lt;/a&gt;, you’ve come a long way: you’ve devised a brilliant monitoring, evaluation, and learning plan, set up your data storage and management infrastructure, and conducted your baseline data collection. It’s finally time to get to the good stuff and dive into the data to make sense of it all—with eye-popping graphics worth of downtown billboards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/160939707%20data%20visualisation-ab2ed4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;160939707 data visualisation-ab2ed4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/karim-bin-humam">Karim Bin-Humam</a>; <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/ben-mann">Ben Mann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/data-management-series-analysis-and-visualization-part-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/data-management-series-analysis-and-visualization-part-3.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
