<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 15:19:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 15:19:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5545435994_acd18f073c_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>As Democracy Goes Digital, Cybersecurity Takes Precedence: 5 Critical Resources For Protecting Elections Against Digital Threats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From introducing biometric voter verification machines in Kenya to testing an internet voting pilot in Norway, election management bodies (EMBs) have increasingly digitized elections in efforts to increase efficiency, promote transparency, and encourage greater voter participation. While many elections have increasingly involved technology, including digital voter rolls, biometric voter registration, and electronic voting machines, these critical democratic processes have become more susceptible to a rapidly evolving threat—cyberattacks. Failure to address cybersecurity risks inherent to a digitized electoral process can pose a grave threat to electoral integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/as-democracy-goes-digital-cybersecurity-takes-precedence-5-critical-resources-for-protecting-elections-against-digital-threats.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/as-democracy-goes-digital-cybersecurity-takes-precedence-5-critical-resources-for-protecting-elections-against-digital-threats.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm_VZR9145.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Playing the Short and Long Game: The Importance of Adaptability in Cybersecurity Programming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: This post is adapted from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaldevforum.com/agenda/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming&quot;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; presented at the recent Global Digital Development Forum (GDDF) 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, DAI has expanded its cybersecurity portfolio to cover regions including Asia-Pacific, Eastern Europe, and the Western Balkans. Designing and delivering programs that focus on building the resilience of cybersecurity stakeholders and ecosystems involves investments in three key elements of cybersecurity: people, process, and technology. It also demands that we apply this approach with local existing conditions. Importantly, cybersecurity programming also requires flexibility for rapid responses in case of unforeseen and new threats, political turnover, or major geopolitical developments expanding cyber or hybrid warfare. This is naturally dictated by realities and conditions in the geographies where we work, where local actors and beneficiaries often face external shocks requiring adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/VZR9145.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VZR9145.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Stock.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 06:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-odisheli-a2a56494/">Alexander Odisheli</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20Photo%20Credit_Mawingu.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Bridging the Gender Digital Divide: Four Approaches to Bringing Women Online From the USAID/Microsoft Airband Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Globally, women are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/r/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The-Mobile-Gender-Gap-Report-2022.pdf&quot;&gt;18 percent&lt;/a&gt; less likely than men to own a smartphone. This statistic illustrates—particularly in low-income, rural households—the “gender digital divide,” where women are less likely to be connected to the internet and lack access to important tools that could improve their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gender digital divide limits women and girls’ opportunities on all fronts—from gaining an education to accessing their finances online to participating in politics and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing how digital inclusion empowers women and boosts the economies of rural communities, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/usaid-microsoft-airband-initiative&quot;&gt;USAID/Microsoft Airband Initiative&lt;/a&gt; has partnered with six private companies in five countries to provide women and girls with meaningful connectivity, internet access, and the skills necessary to navigate the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Photo%20Credit_%20New%20Sun%20Road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo Credit_ New Sun Road.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: New Sun Road.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 08:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Lana Alnesany
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/bridging-the-gender-digital-divide-four-approaches-to-bringing-women-online-from-the-usaid-slash-microsoft-airband-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/bridging-the-gender-digital-divide-four-approaches-to-bringing-women-online-from-the-usaid-slash-microsoft-airband-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Skills</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/smCambodia%20DI.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Kids are Alright: Reframing “Digital Natives”  for International Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is adapted from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaldevforum.com/agenda/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development&quot;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; presented at the 2023 Global Digital Development Forum (GDDF).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term digital native was coined by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Prensky&quot;&gt;Mark Prensky&lt;/a&gt; in 2001. The writer and educator used it to broadly describe a generation that grew up in an era shaped by the internet and digital technology. Digital natives are believed to possess a mastery of technological skills that are inherently different from prior generations. Prensky referred to the arrival of the digital age as a “singularity” that caused students of the time to “think and process information fundamentally differently than their predecessors.” These skills were attributed to the early introduction of digital tools into the homes, schools, and social lives of young people and the perception that this technology is seamlessly integrated into their daily interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AI%20SM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Toward More Transparent and Accountable AI Algorithms in Public Service Delivery: Insights from Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Egypt, Ghana, Kenya, Mexico, and Rwanda</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From our social media feeds to the societal benefits we receive, artificial intelligence (AI) is everywhere and affects everyone. AI may assist us in a variety of ways: it can execute difficult, risky, or tedious tasks on our behalf; assist us in saving lives and coping with natural disasters; entertain us; and make our daily lives more enjoyable. AI helps doctors make decisions about our health and helps judges and lawyers sift through cases, speeding up the judicial process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments worldwide are increasingly turning to AI algorithms to automate or support decision-making in public services. Algorithms assist in urban planning, prioritize social-care cases, make decisions about welfare entitlements, detect unemployment fraud, or monitor people in criminal justice and law enforcement settings. The use of these algorithms is often seen to improve efficiency and lower the costs of public services.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 07:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/miriam-stankovich/">Miriam Stankovich</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/erica-behrens/">Erica Behrens</a>, and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/julia-burchell/">Julia Burchell</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/toward-more-transparent-and-accountable-ai-algorithms-in-public-service-delivery-insights-from-brazil-chile-colombia-egypt-ghana-kenya-mexico-and-rwanda.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/toward-more-transparent-and-accountable-ai-algorithms-in-public-service-delivery-insights-from-brazil-chile-colombia-egypt-ghana-kenya-mexico-and-rwanda.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Ahlan%20SimSim-4acced.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights Libya: Understanding Children’s Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sesame Workshop and the International Rescue Committee (IRC) partnered to address the critical needs of children affected by the Syrian conflict and other crises in Jordan, Lebanon, Syria, and Iraq. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ahlansimsim.org/&quot;&gt;Ahlan Simsim initiative&lt;/a&gt; addresses the urgent needs of children affected by crisis and conflict by creating educational resources that reach children through an award-winning and impactful TV series viewed by more than 23 million children and through early childhood services that integrate media reaching more than 1 million children and caregivers in Iraq, Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria. Ahlan Simsim is exploring the possibility of expanding its work to other countries, specifically Libya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 18 months, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has been working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sesameworkshop.org/what-we-do/refugee-response&quot;&gt;Sesame Workshop&lt;/a&gt; to explore the possibilities for using digital tools to provide education services to young children living in crisis-affected communities. Using DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights™&lt;/a&gt; methodology, in 2021 DAI conducted research in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-yemen-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;Yemen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-colombia-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;Colombia&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-south-sudan-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html&quot;&gt;South Sudan  &lt;/a&gt;to understand communities’ barriers to connectivity, technology usage habits, and ways to leverage those habits to improve access to educational content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October and November 2022, the team continued its research in Libya, focusing on three locations: Khoms (east of Tripoli), Brak al Shati (south), and Tripoli Center. The local research team conducted surveys with 64 households, focused on children ages 3–8 and their parents or caregivers. In this blog we share the findings from that research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Ahlan%20SimSim.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ahlan SimSim.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 05:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/talia-dweck/">Talia Dweck</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-carrington/">Chloe Carrington</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-libya-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-libya-understanding-childrens-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202023-04-21%20at%2010.48.29%20AM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Introducing Sesame Workshop’s Technology Decision Roadmap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that Sesame Street has produced an immense amount of educational media content for children. The iconic video of the Count von Count muppet teaching children how to count to ten permeates through American society. This value has expanded beyond the United States, providing globally accessible videos to numerous countries. Most recently, in 2022, Sesame Workshop, the nonprofit behind Sesame Street, created a library of newly produced, modular, play-based, and globally relevant animation videos called Watch, Play, Learn (WPL) to be distributed in humanitarian contexts and beyond. The 140 segments are five minutes each and cover thematic early childhood development areas: science, math, social-emotional learning, and health, safety, and child protection.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 08:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Carrington
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/introducing-sesame-workshops-technology-decision-roadmap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/introducing-sesame-workshops-technology-decision-roadmap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20Munni%20Akhter_PC%20Atanu%20Bhattacharjee_Bangladesh%20Digital%20Activity.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons Learned in Bangladesh: Engaging Women in Digital Agriculture Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The role of women in agriculture is crucial, especially in countries such as Bangladesh where they make up almost half of the sector’s labor force. However, women often have limited access to resources and assets that could improve their livelihoods, including information that can be accessed through technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital agriculture tools, such as mobile apps and texting services, can help overcome the information disparity between men and women. But first, it is essential to understand the unique challenges that women face in agriculture and how digital tools can address those challenges. Women often have limited access to land, capital, and information, which hinders their participation. Moreover, they have limited mobility, which makes it difficult for them to physically access markets and other agricultural services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Plantix_BNA_Patuakhali_Sador_Add%20On%20%20Farmer_Ayesha%20Begum_16Mr22.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Plantix_BNA_Patuakhali_Sador_Add On  Farmer_Ayesha Begum_16Mr22.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: BDAA.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tasnuba/">Tasnuba Sinha</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-in-bangladesh-engaging-women-in-digital-agriculture-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-in-bangladesh-engaging-women-in-digital-agriculture-tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Digital Ecosystem Country Assessment (DECA) has Spurred Innovative Digital Development Around the World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the Government of Colombia and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) brokered a peace accord that ended nearly five decades of internal armed conflict. After years of reconciliation and peacebuilding efforts, however, new emerging threats to civil society, while digital, have the potential to incite physical violence, according to findings in a 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-strategy/implementation-tracks/track1-adopt-ecosystem/digital-ecosystem-country-assessments&quot;&gt;Digital Ecosystem Country Assessment&lt;/a&gt; (DECA) report published by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalfrontiersdai.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project. The report recommended that USAID invest in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/cybersecurity&quot;&gt;cyber hygiene programming&lt;/a&gt; in Colombia to assess and improve online and offline safety. Today, USAID Colombia has partnered with USAID’s Digital APEX project to build just this type of capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more USAID Missions like Colombia’s grapple with the emerging opportunities and challenges of our digital world, the Digital Strategy is shaping the Agency’s response. To design policies and programs that take advantage of technology, stakeholders need to first understand the building blocks of a country’s digital landscape. The DECA, a cornerstone of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-strategy&quot;&gt;Digital Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, is helping development practitioners to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/deca%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;deca 1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Hanz Rippe/Paramo Films for USAID.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Patrick Malone
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-digital-ecosystem-country-assessment-deca-has-spurred-innovative-digital-development-around-the-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-digital-ecosystem-country-assessment-deca-has-spurred-innovative-digital-development-around-the-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CSISPhotoBlog2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Preparing International Development Professionals for the Digital Age</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/preparing-international-development-professionals-digital-age&quot;&gt;originally appeared&lt;/a&gt; on the Center for Strategic and International Studies’ website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in technology are transforming every industry in the global economy. In particular, the disruption created by the COVID-19 pandemic pushed governments, companies, and citizens to adopt a wide range of digital solutions. Many activities—including government services, work, schooling, and retail—shifted online. The pandemic also revealed that workers and regular citizens were not equipped with the right skills to operate in the digital age. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/web/products-eurostat-news/-/ddn-20220330-1&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; conducted by the European Commission in 2021 revealed that only 54 percent of Europeans possess basic digital skills. In 2022, Salesforce’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforce.com/news/press-releases/2022/01/27/digital-skills-index-update/&quot;&gt;Digital Skills Index&lt;/a&gt; found that three out of four workers globally did not feel ready to operate in a digital-first world. Most worrisome is the fact that the same study revealed only 28 percent of respondents were actively engaged in training programs or pursuing learning opportunities to acquire digital skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CSISPhotoBlog2-702fe0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CSISPhotoBlog2-702fe0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: FADEL SENNA/AFP/Getty Images.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 08:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.csis.org/people/romina-bandura">Romina Bandura</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/preparing-international-development-professionals-for-the-digital-age.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/preparing-international-development-professionals-for-the-digital-age.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
