<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 12:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 12:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/days_joint.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 3: Rethinking the Global Health Security Index</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The next installment in our COVID-19 analysis series connects the dots between the datasets we have explored in our previous posts and brings in a new dataset that came to our attention over the past couple of weeks. In this paper, we look at the relationship between country scores from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghsindex.org&quot;&gt;Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI)’s Global Health Security Index&lt;/a&gt; and levels of response by country governments measured using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bsg.ox.ac.uk/research/research-projects/oxford-covid-19-government-response-tracker%5D&quot;&gt;Oxford COVID-19 Government Response Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. You can read more about our initial exploratory analysis of the Global Health Security Index &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-2-health-capacity-and-preparedness.html&quot;&gt;here in our previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Oxford University has provided an initial report of its data on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-3-rethinking-the-global-health-security-index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-3-rethinking-the-global-health-security-index.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/COVID-19_BehaviorChange.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Approaching Digital Behavior Change Communications in the COVID-19 Era</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While tackling the spread of the COVID-19 disease takes a multi-faceted approach, behavior change—especially around personal and respiratory hygiene, proper handwashing, social distancing, and so on—remains a critical need across countries where DAI and our clients operate. Further, as organizations and individuals increasingly embrace digital-based approaches to collaboration, communication, and information gathering, we are presented with an opportunity to incorporate these technologies across behavior change communication strategies. However, as many organizations have experienced since the start of near-global lockdowns, this transition to an all-digital way of working comes with unique roadblocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, the DAI Center for Digital Acceleration has been exploring how digital communication tools can be used to build communications campaigns aimed at stemming the COVID-19 tide and spreading accurate information about targeted behaviors. We’ve pulled together some quick thoughts on the topic, but frankly, these are principles that apply in most &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; effort of this sort.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anand-varghese/">Anand Varghese</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsey-kirn-8903a55/">Lindsey Kirn</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/approaching-digital-behavior-change-communications-in-the-covid-19-era.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/approaching-digital-behavior-change-communications-in-the-covid-19-era.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SHE%20Investments'%20Ngeay%20Ngeay%20business%20info%20and%20online%20learning%20site.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Promoting Resilient Ecosystems: How Cambodians are Adapting in the Face of COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years in Cambodia leading the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/cambodia-development-innovations&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; project taught me a lot about innovation. I saw innovators employ entrepreneurial thinking to develop out-of-the-box, creative solutions to problems, helping hundreds of thousands of Cambodians—automated phone calls warning people of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/blog/the-tech-mermaid-alert/&quot;&gt;coming floods&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind, as does a mobile &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edemy.org/#tesdopi&quot;&gt;test prep application&lt;/a&gt; to help high school students prepare for national exams. It’s this entrepreneurial thinking that the world desperately needs in this time of hardship, where livelihoods, the economy, and social cohesion are being challenged in unprecedented ways. Which naturally begs the question: In the face of COVID-19, what happens next in Cambodia’s innovation community?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/promoting-resilient-ecosystems-how-cambodians-are-adapting-in-the-face-of-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/promoting-resilient-ecosystems-how-cambodians-are-adapting-in-the-face-of-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/COVID_Data_Map.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 2: Health Capacity and Preparedness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was written by DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-parr-4a534897/&quot;&gt;Jamie Parr&lt;/a&gt;, with contributions from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/greg-maly/&quot;&gt;Greg Maly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/gratiana-fu/&quot;&gt;Gratiana Fu&lt;/a&gt;. This analysis is Part 2 of a series on known risk factors associated with COVID-19. We aim to use publicly available data sets to identify national and subnational populations most at risk for infection and case fatality. The analysis will be updated as we receive additional data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>CDA Analytics Team
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-2-health-capacity-and-preparedness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-2-health-capacity-and-preparedness.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAI%203D%20printer.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Plan C: How Makerspaces are Providing a Stopgap for COVID-19 Supply Shortages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the participants in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/success-stories/think-global-make-local-3d-printing-propels-young-cambodians-future/&quot;&gt;Think Global Make Local&lt;/a&gt; product development workshop, sponsored by our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/cambodia-development-innovations&quot;&gt;Cambodia Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; project in 2016, created a design for a toy called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Doydoycompany/&quot;&gt;Doy Doy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. With &lt;em&gt;Doy Doy’s&lt;/em&gt; silicone straws and plastic connectors, kids can build complex structures. The product has gone on to achieve modest commercial success locally. I found &lt;em&gt;Doy Doy&lt;/em&gt; instructive because of the way its creator, Em Chanrithykol, ended up manufacturing the toy’s plastic connectors. Because of a lack of local injection-molding capacity and administrative barriers to importing parts made by contract manufacturers outside of Cambodia, Chanrithykol turned to a less traditional method: He contracted a local firm to churn out the parts on a battery of 3D printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3D printing is slow, expensive, and inefficient. It is great for small runs of one-off items or prototypes, but it is a terrible way to mass manufacture a product. But the lesson of &lt;em&gt;Doy Doy&lt;/em&gt; is that a bad way to mass manufacture a product can still be better than having &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; way to mass manufacture a product. This is why I am currently manufacturing personal protective face shields for Baltimore-area hospitals in my basement.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 11:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/plan-c-how-makerspaces-are-providing-a-stopgap-for-covid-19-supply-shortages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/plan-c-how-makerspaces-are-providing-a-stopgap-for-covid-19-supply-shortages.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ulloa_DEA_COVID.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Importance of Understanding Digital Divides During the COVID-19 Response</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our work at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration intersects with global COVID-19 responses in many ways. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-1-demography-behavior-and-environment.html&quot;&gt;Earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, our data scientists presented an analysis of risk factors and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/COVID-looking-for-the-helpers-in-the-hardware-community.html&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt; we got a glimpse at the hardware community’s approach to the crisis. There is another element to our work that I think is critical to highlight—digital ecosystem assessments.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-the-importance-of-understanding-digital-divides-during-the-pandemic-response.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-the-importance-of-understanding-digital-divides-during-the-pandemic-response.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/COVID_Data_Map.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 1: Demography, Behavior, and Environment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was written by DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/gratiana-fu/&quot;&gt;Gratiana Fu&lt;/a&gt;, with contributions from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/greg-maly/&quot;&gt;Greg Maly&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-parr-4a534897/&quot;&gt;Jamie Parr&lt;/a&gt;. This analysis is Part 1 of a series on known risk factors associated with COVID-19. We aim to use publicly available data sets to identify national and subnational populations most at risk for infection and case fatality. The analysis will be updated as we receive additional data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>CDA Analytics Team
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-1-demography-behavior-and-environment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-1-demography-behavior-and-environment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CDC-coronavirus-image-23311-for-web.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19: Looking for Helpers in the Hardware Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/11/health/coronavirus-pandemic-world-health-organization/index.html&quot;&gt;pandemic&lt;/a&gt; makes its way across the globe, and even well-resourced health systems struggle with the availability of critical supplies needed to treat patients, initiatives have emerged in the hardware community looking to help solve the shortage of physical supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/COVID-looking-for-the-helpers-in-the-hardware-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/COVID-looking-for-the-helpers-in-the-hardware-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/20191121-_MG_4393.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Unlocking the Value of Digital Transformation in the Social Sector</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For many years, the support of international donors to civil society organizations and private and public sectors in the technology field revolved around the provision of equipment, hardware, and software. On many occasions, these types of support have proved ineffective. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/261263057_Overcoming_ICT_project_failures_-_A_practical_perspective&quot;&gt;researchers&lt;/a&gt; wrote in 2013, these investments quickly became obsolete or abandoned. Since then, we in the digital development community have supported international donors and international programming to better integrate technology into our work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/unlocking-the-value-of-digital-transformation-in-the-social-sector.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/unlocking-the-value-of-digital-transformation-in-the-social-sector.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/WCC2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Closing the Gender Digital Divide: What We’re Doing to Bring Women Online</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital technologies are revolutionizing the way we access information, financing, and networks—all critical tools for fully participating in the global economy. Yet, these technologies, most notably internet connectivity and mobile phones, are not reaching all people equally. In recognition of International Women’s Day, we are looking at one of the most pressing barriers women face to their economic advancement—the gender digital divide—and how DAI is addressing this problem through the U.S. Agency for International Development’s W-GDP&lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/newsletter_final.pdf&quot;&gt; WomenConnect Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, implemented by DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project. (For the latest information, please read our most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/newsletter_final.pdf&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nataliedomond/">Natalie Domond</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/closing-the-gender-digital-divide-what-were-doing-to-bring-women-online.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/closing-the-gender-digital-divide-what-were-doing-to-bring-women-online.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
