<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:05:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Satellite Imagery and ‘Light at Night’ Helps Development Practitioners Estimate GDP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sure many of you have come across a map like the one below. I find that images of our planet are always awe-inspiring and this image is certainly not an exception. I can easily get lost in satellite imagery for hours if I am not careful. Most of those images are based on visual spectrum optical technology (LandSAT, Sentinel, etc.), thus requiring daylight for the powerful digital cameras to “see.” Remote sensing satellites such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ncc.nesdis.noaa.gov/VIIRS/&quot;&gt;VIIRS&lt;/a&gt;—which DAI uses for its analysis—are equipped with special infrared equipment and able to capture beautiful images of the earth at night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o-df5bef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;712130main_8246931247_e60f3c09fb_o-df5bef.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: NASA and DMSP.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lights-at-night-wheres-the-gdp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lights-at-night-wheres-the-gdp.html</guid>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Satellite</category>
        
        <category>Imagery</category>
        
        <category>Imagery Analysis</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Data Analysis</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Chapter%20Ambassador%20Voneat%20Pen.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking Girls in Tech with Voneat Pen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kate Heuisler recently spoke with Voneat Pen, the Chapter Ambassador for &lt;a href=&quot;https://technovationcambodia.com/&quot;&gt;Technovation&lt;/a&gt; in Cambodia, about her work growing the successful all-girl tech entrepreneurship education program for the seventh year in a row. While juggling her roles as the co-founder of the tech startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/606Digital/&quot;&gt;606&lt;/a&gt;, a programmer and STEM advocate, Voneat has been instrumental to Technovation’s success during its most challenging years. When COVID-19 pushed the program online overnight, the Technovation community (and its partners) were still able to successfully engage new all-girl teams, mentors, schools, and provinces across the country. To date, Technovation has helped connect more than 2,000 Cambodian girls to essential 21st-century tech creator skills.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-girls-in-tech-with-voneat-pen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-talking-girls-in-tech-with-voneat-pen.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator Series</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Krista.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Fast Company's World Changing Ideas Awards Highlight Opportunities for Digital Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fast Company magazine has been around for decades…but is it relevant for digital development work? The publication was founded in 1995 at a time when business was changing the world in new ways. Today, 26 years later, we are still coming to terms with the ways that technologies are transforming the ways we work and live—especially during the COVID-19 global pandemic. As I work with clients and projects focused on digital development, the businesses and organizations featured in Fast Company offer new ideas, inspiration, and out-of-the-box thinking to those of us heads down in global development projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I wanted to share some of the winners of Fast Company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90623897&quot;&gt;2021 World-Changing Ideas Awards&lt;/a&gt;—and how these innovations could apply to our work. World Changing Ideas is one of Fast Company’s major annual awards programs and is focused on social good, seeking to elevate finished products and brave concepts that make the world better.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/world-changing-ideas-direct-from-fast-company.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/world-changing-ideas-direct-from-fast-company.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>E-Commerce</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Inta.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New Research Explores Digital Technologies and Their Impact on Social Accountability in Southeast Asia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ian Cocroft, Karen Lee, and Connor MacKenzie are second-year master’s students in the international development program at the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS). The SAIS International Development (IDEV) practicum allows students to work directly with public, private, and nongovernmental organizations as a capstone to their graduate studies. Ian, Karen, and Connor worked with the Center for Digital Acceleration at DAI. The students conducted virtual research in Burma, Cambodia, Thailand, and Vietnam during the 2020-21 academic year to better understand how civil society organizations (CSOs) use digital technologies to support social accountability in public service delivery. The team’s final report provides DAI with considerations on how CSOs can better integrate digital technologies into their operations and highlights regional examples of digital tools for social accountability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our practicum team worked with DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration on a regional study about how CSOs in Burma, Thailand, and Vietnam use digital technologies for social accountability in public service delivery, providing a series of recommendations for the U.S. Agency for International Development-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fhi360.org/projects/innovations-social-accountability-cambodia-isac&quot;&gt;Innovations for Social Accountability in Cambodia (ISAC) program&lt;/a&gt;. As part of our research, we undertook an extensive literature review and held Zoom interviews with country representatives from CSOs, tech organizations, and multilateral institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-cocroft/">Ian Cocroft</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connor-mackenzie/">Connor Mackenzie</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karen-lee-187934123/">Karen Lee</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/idev-practicum-2021-exploring-digital-technologies-and-their-impact-on-social-accountability-in-southeast-asia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/idev-practicum-2021-exploring-digital-technologies-and-their-impact-on-social-accountability-in-southeast-asia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018-04-11-image-6.webp" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Right to Repair is a Development Issue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Who owns the device you are reading this blog post on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem like a straightforward question until a power surge fries a key circuit or a stray elbow knocks a unit to the floor. At this point, the process of repairing what you thought was your (or your employer’s) property is likely to get a bit more complicated: The device turns out to be held together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_screw_drives#Proprietary_head&quot;&gt;proprietary screws&lt;/a&gt;, contains deliberately unobtainable spare parts, has software locks that cannot be overridden without the manufacturer’s express permission, or other random features included specifically to seal you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018-04-11-image-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;2018-04-11-image-6.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: TechSpot.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</guid>
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Alana.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Support USAID Missions through Digital Agriculture Ecosystem Assessments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the incredible progress made over the last decade by the U.S. Government’s global hunger and food security &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feedthefuture.gov/&quot;&gt;Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt; program, continued shocks, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-resilience-and-food-security/responding-to-covid-19-impact-on-resilience-and-food-security&quot;&gt;COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, make the work towards a more resilient global population and improved food security more relevant than ever. COVID’s impact on food security continues to be revealed but it’s estimated that 124 million more people experienced long-lasting poverty and hunger in 2020 and that 2.6 million more children will face stunting due to the pandemic. Across the globe, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) is working to address these impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-missions-through-digital-agriculture-ecosystem-assessments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-usaid-missions-through-digital-agriculture-ecosystem-assessments.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>RFP</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Eduardo%201.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>My Transition from a Tech Company to DAI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before joining DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA), I worked in the software development industry. For the majority of my 15 years in this field, I only worked for tech companies whose main business model was building software. To successfully build software, there are multiple practices and skills that companies need. These skills are, for example, agile methodologies and good coding practices (such as patterns and documentation) that often vary from company to company and the type of technology used. Other practices include daily meetings and specialized resources for each phase of the software development process. In addition, there are roles such as back-end developers, front-end developers, DevOps, scrum masters, graphic designers, UX designers, and more! From this, you can see there is a lot that goes into making even a small web application. But, what I have just described is the experience of working on very large teams that only make software, which is very different from work within CDA’s Products team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Eduardo Gonzalez
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/my-transition-from-a-tech-company-to-dai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/my-transition-from-a-tech-company-to-dai.html</guid>
        
        <category>software development</category>
        
        <category>agile</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Stephanie%201.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>In Case You Missed It: The Digital Journey in South Asia—Opportunities and Challenges for Small Firms and Women Entrepreneurs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; Project, in partnership with the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s Indo-Pacific Office, recently hosted a thought-provoking webinar featuring views from the field in Bangladesh, India, and Nepal on opportunities and challenges for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) and women entrepreneurs in South Asia. Our panel brought together diverse perspectives from experts in government, private sector, and civil society to discuss the key problems faced by SMEs in South Asia today and what the development community can do to break down barriers and help women entrepreneurs take their place as major players in the economy. Missed the discussion? Read the highlights below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Stephanie%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stephanie 1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo Credit: Digital Empowerment Foundation.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/mynetwork/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/in-case-you-missed-it-the-digital-journey-in-south-asia-opportunities-and-challenges-for-small-firms-and-women-entrepreneurs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/in-case-you-missed-it-the-digital-journey-in-south-asia-opportunities-and-challenges-for-small-firms-and-women-entrepreneurs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Julia-b075d1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>We Urgently Need to Build Skills to Bolster Trust in Digital Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of last year’s launch events for the DAI Center for Digital Acceleration’s flagship Frontier Insights research on&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/fi-cyber-user-trust-summary.pdf&quot;&gt; user perceptions of trust and privacy on the internet&lt;/a&gt;, two panels of experts helped underscore and widen the discussion around issues raised in the report. In the South Asia panel, a theme that emerged very clearly was the urgent need to build digital skills as a means to develop and maintain trust in digital services. Both the research and expert discussion highlighted the need for a multi-stakeholder approach to enable informed use and trust throughout the digital value chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Julia-b075d1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Julia-b075d1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: Global Citizen.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Julia Burchell
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/we-urgently-need-to-build-skills-to-bolster-trust-in-digital-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/we-urgently-need-to-build-skills-to-bolster-trust-in-digital-tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Chloe-f84906.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Knowledge Sharing in ICT4D: Beyond Internet Searches and Panel Events</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we head into “event season”—albeit remotely—I’ve been thinking about how we share knowledge about what we do in the ICT4D space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing some recent research and sector mapping, I noted how different the levels of ICT4D development are amongst various sectors. In digital agriculture, it is generally accepted that there are numerous innovations out there and a plethora of pilot projects, but many are struggling to bring these innovations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cta.int/en/digitalisation-agriculture-africa&quot;&gt;to scale&lt;/a&gt;. Many programs might be integrating digital as a pilot here and there, but struggling to identify what works and how they can reach the program goals. There are a huge number of initiatives seeking to share lessons within sectors, but how many are taking lessons from sector to sector?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-sharing-in-ict4d-beyond-internet-searches-and-panel-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-sharing-in-ict4d-beyond-internet-searches-and-panel-events.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
