<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 15:29:43 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 15:29:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ATLATL%20(Timor%20Leste)%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>4 Critical Considerations When Developing ICT Policies and Regulations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world dominated by rapid innovation, information and communications technology (ICT) is not only an accelerator for economic growth, it also provides on-ramps for vulnerable populations to participate in society and not get left behind. However, the potential of this type of tech can only go as far as a nation’s regulatory environment allows. A weak regulatory environment can drastically limit the benefits of ICT for a country’s economy, consumers, and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 10:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/4-critical-considerations-when-developing-ict-politics-and-regulations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/4-critical-considerations-when-developing-ict-politics-and-regulations.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/stemazone%20thumbnail.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Emerging eLearning Series: Innovative Success for Children—A Look Into Oman’s Stemazone Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in a series that seeks to capture e-learning efforts, celebrate innovations, consider critical lessons learned, and support practitioners who do this work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandrosolis/?originalSubdomain=cr">Alejandro Solis</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-innovative-success-for-children-a-look-into-omans-stemazone-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-innovative-success-for-children-a-look-into-omans-stemazone-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>eLearning</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>STEAM</category>
        
        <category>Emerging eLearning Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Flagged for Review: A Look at Hate Speech in the International Development Context</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many countries &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globesmart.com/blog/celebrating-lgbt-pride-around-the-world-things-to-know/&quot;&gt;around the world&lt;/a&gt; recognize June as Pride Month—a time to celebrate lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ) people, while reflecting on the community’s history. But this year it’s not just sunshine and rainbows. In cyberspace, the discourse about LGBTQ people and their rights is increasingly crowded with hate speech. On any given day, my own Twitter feed is sprinkled with posts arguing that LGBTQ people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/05/11/1096623939/accusations-grooming-political-attack-homophobic-origins&quot;&gt;“grooming”&lt;/a&gt; children, claiming &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benshapiro/status/1536667667150651392?s=21&quot;&gt;same-sex couples&lt;/a&gt; shouldn’t be represented in Disney movies, or attacking the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/anti-lgbtq-threats-orchestrated-on-internet-shut-down-events-rcna33955&quot;&gt;validity and humanity&lt;/a&gt; of transgender people. While I find these messages deeply distressing, I’m forced to ask myself, “Is this hate speech?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I’m going to use the example of LGBTQ hate speech to lay out what hate speech is, link it to the international development context, and explore what social media platforms and other stakeholders are doing to combat hate speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rami-al-zayat-w33-zg-dNL4-unsplash-6021b0.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image: Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 14:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Nancy Haugh
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/flagged-for-review-a-look-at-hate-speech-in-the-international-development-context.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/flagged-for-review-a-look-at-hate-speech-in-the-international-development-context.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Rights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Communications</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Model.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>USAID Launches Digital Government Model</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2021, as people around the world—and their governments—were grappling with a rapid transition to digital technology, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalfrontiersdai.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project began working with the Technology Division of USAID’s Innovation, Technology, and Research (ITR/T) Hub to create a conceptual model of digital government, or e-government. That model is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-government-model&quot;&gt;live&lt;/a&gt; and available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/usaid-launches-its-digital-government-model.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/usaid-launches-its-digital-government-model.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Government</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/mars-sector-6-IgUR1iX0mqM-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Literacy Series: The DigComp Framework</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the onset of the pandemic spurring ever-faster digitalization around the world, we at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration are thinking about the key elements needed to ensure sustainable digital transformation in the countries where we work. One of the primary building blocks needed to achieve sustainability is strengthening digital literacy. As digital development practitioners, digital literacy is a big part of our work. Whether a person is getting online for the first time or is a cyber specialist, we have a responsibility to ensure those we work with have the agency to use the appropriate technology meaningfully: to achieve professional and personal goals, while avoiding digital harm. We also have a responsibility to close the digital divide by supporting novices in developing basic skills, so they are not left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Carrington
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AIGraphic.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Four Awardees Are Paving the Way for a More Equitable AI-Powered Future</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-the-winners-of-usaids-equitable-ai-challenge&quot;&gt;Introducing the Winners of USAID’s Equitable AI Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) tools are a dual-edged sword: they promise tremendous benefits for international development, but have also demonstrated instances of bias and harm, often resulting from inequitable design, use, and impact. Recognizing that AI technologies can cause gender biases, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) urgently looked for innovative and creative approaches to address gender-inequitable outcomes by launching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictworks.org/gender-equitable-artificial-intelligence-outcomes/#.YnPvuejMKUl&quot;&gt;Equitable AI Challenge&lt;/a&gt; in the fall of 2021. This challenge, implemented through DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;, sought to support approaches that increase the accountability and transparency of AI systems in global development contexts. Dozens of competitors submitted approaches related to the prevention, identification, or monitoring of bias and harm against women and gender-nonconforming people—reflecting the larger goals of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/usaid-digital-strategy&quot;&gt;USAID’s Digital Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/oct-26-2021-administrator-samantha-power-first-ever-national-strategy-gender&quot;&gt;National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality&lt;/a&gt;, and the recently launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/artificial-intelligence-action-plan&quot;&gt;USAID AI Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-four-awardees-are-paving-the-way-for-a-more-equitable-ai-powered-future.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-four-awardees-are-paving-the-way-for-a-more-equitable-ai-powered-future.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Broken%20Bridge%20uMlazi.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Drone Mapping Reflects Solid Waste and Ocean Plastic Impact of the Durban Floods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Heavy downpours over only two days in April 2022 caused South Africa’s worst and most deadly natural disaster to date: a flash flood so rare and devastating it has a one in the 300-year probability of recurring. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://erccportal.jrc.ec.europa.eu/ECHO-Products/Echo-Flash#/daily-flash-archive/4474&quot;&gt;European Union&lt;/a&gt;, approximately 435 people died and up to 41,000 people were affected. Rescue and disaster response efforts, which began immediately, are ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/716884061?h=ff95501847&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 13:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-palfreman-wastewash/?originalSubdomain=za">Joshua Palfreman</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/drone-mapping-reflects-solid-waste-and-ocean-plastic-impact-of-the-durban-floods.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/drone-mapping-reflects-solid-waste-and-ocean-plastic-impact-of-the-durban-floods.html</guid>
        
        <category>Environment</category>
        
        <category>Waste Management</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/pexels-sergio-souza-3907943%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Can the Mexican Automotive Industry Capitalize on Data-Driven Global Value Chains?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smart factories could position Mexico as an Industry 4.0 hub and open doors to data-driven global value chains (GVCs).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mexico is embracing Industry 4.0. The digital factory in Puebla, the aerospace corridors in Querétaro, Guanajuato, Baja California, Sonora, Chihuahua, and Nuevo León showcase Industry 4.0 manufacturing throughout the country. Smart factories are facilities that primarily use automated tools and machines, from production robots to transportation devices or 3D printers. Products are equipped with sensors that allow them to connect and exchange data and communicate with each other. They make up a cyber-physical production system (CPPS) connected via the industrial Internet of Things (IoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data are the smart factory’s blood vessels and the key enabler of modern global value chains (GVCs). In the networked smart factory, identities can be assigned to tools, machines, products, and materials. Items at each level of the GVC can thereby be precisely located and tracked. This networked and automated production environment is supplemented with “big data” (huge amounts of data from millions of nodes within a network, including the ability to process and analyze large amounts of data using cloud computing, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning). Data can be handled, processed, and analyzed in real time and passed on through GVCs. Greater customization is possible while retaining speed and efficiency. Individual products are networked and identifiable; customization is possible by drawing on user data, while customer data is directly transferred to machine data. Cloud computing and additive manufacturing enable decentralized production.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mimistankovic/">Miriam Stankovich</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/agustin-filippo-3586814/">Agustin Filippo</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>industry 4.0</category>
        
        <category>Smart Factory</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Main%20Cover%202022%20Digis.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: 2022 USAID Digital Development Awards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you used digital technology to promote locally led development? Have you safeguarded digital ecosystems by facilitating access to digital infrastructure for marginalized populations, securing internet freedom and human rights, exposing violent extremism, countering misinformation and disinformation, or strengthening cybersecurity?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Awards</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Rights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture%20digital%20upskilling%20pwd.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Realizing Inclusive Digital Development Through Boosting the Digital Skills of People Living with Disabilities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five percent of the nearly 1 billion people living with disabilities around the world live at or below the poverty line. Unfortunately, these roughly 250 million people are more likely to face obstacles ranging from finding employment to outright discrimination. However, digital technologies offer the potential to expand employment opportunities for people living with disabilities, allowing them to realize their capabilities, expand their networks, and increase their mobility through digital accessibility. DAI, implementing activities under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP)&lt;/a&gt;, is designing activities that create employment opportunities and support networks for people living with disabilities in countries such as Cambodia and India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its work with the Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) and the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI), DAI recognizes disability as a cross-cutting issue and strives to provide equitable access to digital tools for people with a wide array of abilities, including those who are hard of hearing, have visual impairments, speech impediments, or other learning, developmental, and psychosocial disabilities. DAI’s grantee organizations, consultants, and partners are making significant steps towards digital inclusion through the facilitation of trainings, workshops, and mentoring groups specifically targeted and tailored for people living with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-anderson-2b69391b6/">Jeremy Anderson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
