<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 14:13:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 14:13:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Don’t Need to Reinvent the Wheel, But it’s Time to Invest in Roads and Highways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/AL%20headshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AL headshot.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the good news: Over the past 10 years the digital health community has begun to heal from a severe case of pilotitis. As a community of innovators and health systems researchers, we increasingly recognize that creating and testing new digital health tools in the absence of investments in the enabling ecosystem is likely to produce limited, short-term, and small-scale impact. Without concerted efforts to fertilize the soil in which the seeds of innovation are planted, those seeds will never mature beyond a sapling. That is, unless we pay attention to the policy and regulatory environment, the telecommunications and electrical infrastructure, and most importantly, the availability of trained and appropriate human resources to facilitate scale-up and sustainability, we cannot expect national-scale digital health projects to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://twitter.com/alabriqu">Dr. Alain Labrique</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/time-to-invest-in-roads-and-highways.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/time-to-invest-in-roads-and-highways.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build a Facebook Messenger Chatbot in 5 Steps in Just 5 Minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I wrote a post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-chatbot.html&quot;&gt;“I Made a Facebook Chatbot (And You Can, Too)”&lt;/a&gt; where I laid out the case for chatbots as an outreach and engagement tool in international development. To recap, here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 14:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KIC Expands its Support of Tech-Driven Entrepreneurship to Mauritania</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of Digital@DAI will know that we’ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;supporting&lt;/a&gt; Kosmos Energy’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosmosinnovationcenter.com/&quot;&gt;Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC) in Ghana for the last two years. KIC’s work with young tech entrepreneurs in the agricultural sector has garnered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosmosinnovationcenter.com/2016-awards/&quot;&gt;awards &lt;/a&gt;and plenty of media attention, and Kosmos is now looking to apply what it has learned to a new country: Mauritania.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 12:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Sub-Saharan Africa</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking Ahead to 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year provides a great opportunity to think about priorities for year ahead. Last week we wrote a post highlighting the top &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-ten-posts-of-2017.html&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; of 2017. The most-read articles covered a lot of ground—from reflections on specific projects, to advances in our thinking on best practices for human-centered design (HCD), to technology reviews. So, what’s on our minds for the year to come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Looking%20ahea%20to%202018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking ahea to 2018.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 12:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-to-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-to-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital@DAI Year in Review: Top 10 Posts of 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year Digital@DAI published more than 120 posts, covering everything from our work in human-centered design (HCD) to advances in remote sensing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We featured digital experts from organizations such as Panoply, BanQu, Omelas, and Bamba, and had almost 40,000 page views. We continue to explore the potential of digital technology across sectors, geographies, clients, and constituents in the blog and in the work that we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-reader-top-five-posts-of-2016.html&quot;&gt;final blog&lt;/a&gt; of 2016 we reviewed the top five most read articles of the year. With our audience and total number of blog posts expanding, we’ll look at our top 10 of 2017, which showcase a broad range of topics, content, and writers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017%20Year%20in%20Review%20C.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2017 Year in Review C.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-ten-posts-of-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-ten-posts-of-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lean HCD: How to HCD When You Can’t Travel to the Field</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in late 2015, I landed a unique design gig. The job came via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/guatemala-nexos-locales&quot;&gt;Nexos Locales&lt;/a&gt;, a USAID-funded, DAI-run project that works with municipalities around the Western Highlands of Guatemala to improve public financial management and citizen engagement. A newly elected mayor in the municipality of Chiantla wanted to open his finances to the public to close the space for corruption, and I was asked by the project to scope out the activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/USE.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;USE.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lean-hcd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lean-hcd.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q&amp;A Responses: Looking For a Partner to Fight Fall Armyworm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 7, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-rfp-for-an-innovative-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html&quot;&gt;DAI released&lt;/a&gt; a request for proposals (RFP) for a prize implementation partner to confront fall armyworm. This partner will join DAI and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) in designing a results-driven prize to find digital tools and services that help smallholder farmers across sub-Saharan Africa. Thank you to those who asked questions about the RFP. We have reviewed your questions, and provided answers to each below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 14:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="mailto:DigitalFrontiers@dai.com">Yasmine Williams</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-responses-looking-for-a-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-responses-looking-for-a-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GeekFest 2017: Talking Gender-Disaggregated Data with Alex Tyers, Panoply Digital</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/geekfest-d47647.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;geekfest-d47647.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;
Welcome to GeekFest 2017, a series of interviews featuring ICT4D thought leaders. Our goals for our #geekfest2017 interviews are 1. to highlight the people and organizations who are pushing the field in new directions, 2. feature their work and show how it’s different or new, and 3. to support the overall growth of the ICT4D community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/AlexTyers_Headshot_May2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AlexTyers_Headshot_May2017.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;
This week I chat with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/our-team/#/alex-tyers-2/&quot;&gt;Alexandra “Alex” Tyers&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Founder and Director at Panoply Digital. Alex is a mobiles for development (M4D) professional, specializing in monitoring and evaluation for innovation, mobile learning in emerging markets, and women’s mobile and ICT access and use. Alex recently spoke at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/frontiers-in-digital-inclusion-event.html&quot;&gt;Frontiers in Digital Inclusion Event&lt;/a&gt; in London on the importance of gender-disaggregated data for digital access and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-talking-gender-disaggregated-data-with-alex-tyers-panoply-digital.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-talking-gender-disaggregated-data-with-alex-tyers-panoply-digital.html</guid>
        
        <category>Geekfest 2017</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apply Now: Looking For a Partner to Fight Fall Armyworm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, DAI releases a request for proposals for a prize implementation partner to confront fall armyworm head on. This partner will join DAI and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) in designing a results-driven prize to find digital tools and services that help smallholder farmers across sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A farmer in Ethiopia inspects his fall armyworm-infested maize. (Photo Credit: FAO/Tamiru Legesse)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="mailto:DigitalFrontiers@dai.com">Yasmine Williams</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-rfp-for-an-innovative-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-rfp-for-an-innovative-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GeekFest2017: A Discussion with Cassandra Mickish Gross</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to GeekFest 2017, a series of interviews featuring ICT4D thought leaders. Our goals for our #geekfest2017 interviews are 1. to highlight the people and organizations who are pushing the field in new directions, 2. feature their work and show how it’s different or new, and 3. to support the overall growth of the ICT4D community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Cassandra%20Mickish%20Gross%20Headshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cassandra Mickish Gross Headshot.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;
This week I’m speaking with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/blog/authors/cassandra-mickish&quot;&gt;Cassandra Mickish Gross&lt;/a&gt; from the Johns Hopkins Center for Communication Programs to discuss the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/&quot;&gt;Knowledge for Health Project&lt;/a&gt;. In this post Cassandra reflects on her experience developing a digital health platform. We explore the choice between an established solution with the potential to scale, versus one that has clear evidence of impact on health outcomes. During the interview, she reflects on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/projects/sub-saharan-africa&quot;&gt;Faster to Zero Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, implemented in partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;http://healthenabled.org/wordpress/&quot;&gt;HealthEnabled&lt;/a&gt;, that aims to support the Ministries of Health of South Africa and Uganda in the scale-up of digital health tools and accelerate the elimination of mother-to-child transmission of HIV.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 14:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest2017-a-discussion-with-cassandra-mickish-gross.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest2017-a-discussion-with-cassandra-mickish-gross.html</guid>
        
        <category>Geekfest 2017</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
