<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:46:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:46:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/HSNP%20payment%20staff%20assisting%20elderly%20beneficiaries%20fill%20in%20Bank%20Account%20opening%20forms%20at%20Qilta%20Marsabit.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Consent to Data Processing in Humanitarian and Development Contexts, Part 1: Who, What, When, and How</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 and early 2020, DAI and our partner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cariboudigital.net/&quot;&gt;Caribou Digital,&lt;/a&gt; worked closely with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-development-office&quot;&gt;U.K. Foreign, Commonwealth &amp;amp; Development Office&lt;/a&gt; to analyse identification and registration systems in protracted and recurrent crises. For those interested in reading more about the research, the report can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/bsic-MIS-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post—the first of a two-part series—we dig into some of the issues around consent and other legal bases for data processing in humanitarian and development contexts identified in our research. For other blogs about our research, see our comments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-interoperability.html&quot;&gt;interoperability&lt;/a&gt; and the risks and benefits of management information systems at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-part-2-risks-and-benefits.html&quot;&gt;humanitarian-social protection nexus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chloemessenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachaelsteller/">Rachel Steller</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/consent-to-data-processing-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts-part-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/consent-to-data-processing-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts-part-one.html</guid>
        
        <category>Consent</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>Interoperability</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AI%202%20copy%20(002).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Reflections on Machine Learning for Gender Inclusion in Afghanistan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past summer, DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/afghanistan-women-in-the-economy&quot;&gt;Promote: Women in the Economy (WIE)&lt;/a&gt; project came to an end. Funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development, the project bolstered women’s inclusion in Afghanistan’s economy through technical assistance, access to finance, and business training. In 2016, our team &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-will-help-development-projects-achieve-scale.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about the possibility of leveraging machine learning to “automate the alignment of unstructured CVs and resumes with available jobs, thereby facilitating the Afghan women’s access to employment opportunities.” Four years later, this use case for machine learning is one of our favorite examples. We reflect on five lessons from this initiative, and how we can translate its success into future endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-machine-learning-for-gender-inclusion-in-afghanistan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-machine-learning-for-gender-inclusion-in-afghanistan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Afghanistan</category>
        
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Budapest%20Convention_resized.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Considerations for a Successful ICT Strategy in Local Context: Lessons from Timor-Leste</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those with access to technology in various parts of the world use it in similar ways. In places as distant as Chile, Vietnam, and Norway, people use e-commerce platforms for buying and selling goods, emailing each other, and e-calendars for business schedules, and social media platforms for sharing news, communicating, and organizing. Despite these crosscutting uses of technology and often the ubiquity of the platforms themselves (Facebook is the world’s most popular social media site, with 2.6 billion monthly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/268136/top-15-countries-based-on-number-of-facebook-users/&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/a&gt;), the context in which these technologies exist matter greatly for how that technology is governed and understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology strategies and policies must be tailored to the local context so that a country can successfully promote the use of technology for growth and prosperity while governing its use to protect citizens and national security. This approach aligns closely with the first two &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/principles/&quot;&gt;Principles for Digital Development,&lt;/a&gt; which are &lt;strong&gt;1) Design with the user&lt;/strong&gt;—using conversation, observation, and co-creation to create a product or initiative that is truly beneficial and appropriate and &lt;strong&gt;2) Understand the existing ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;—considering the particular structures and needs that exist in each country, region, and community.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/considerations-for-a-successful-ict-strategy-in-local-context-lessons-from-timor-leste.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/considerations-for-a-successful-ict-strategy-in-local-context-lessons-from-timor-leste.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Asia and the Pacific</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/JB%203.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Eliminating Cyber Violence Against Women and Girls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the United Nations’ International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women. Like every year on this day–and any other official “Day” that amplifies the inequalities between women and men–I’m heaving a big sigh… because we’re still here. We still require these Days. We continue to need reminding that women are &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; fighting for equality all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These thoughts can get me down, but today, I’m pulling up my positive socks. Observing these Days provides an opportunity to celebrate the progress societies have made in closing gender gaps and can galvanise us to acknowledge the work still left to do. If days like today inspire us to take positive action to shape a better world for women and men, then that is all to the good.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 07:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Julia Burchell
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/eliminating-cyber-violence-against-women-and-girls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/eliminating-cyber-violence-against-women-and-girls.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-04-23%20at%207.54.36%20AM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Respond Now: USAID Seeks ICT Regulatory Policy Technical Assistance Services in Latin America, the Caribbean, Africa, and the Indo-Pacific</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is issuing an expression of interest (EOI) to support the U.S. Agency for International Development’s (USAID) &lt;strong&gt;Promoting American Approaches to ICT Regulatory Policy (ProICT)&lt;/strong&gt; activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 09:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Andrea Falso
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-seeks-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services-in-latin-america-the-caribbean-africa-and-the-indo-pacific.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-seeks-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services-in-latin-america-the-caribbean-africa-and-the-indo-pacific.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Open%20Call%20winners.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Increasing Adoption and Awareness of Fintech Solutions in Mexico: Q&amp;A with Roberto Velez and Lorena Segura</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2019, the U.K. Foreign, Commonwealth &amp;amp; Development Office’s (FCDO) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/mexico-prosperity-fund-mexico-financial-services-programme&quot;&gt;Prosperity Fund Mexico Financial Services Programme&lt;/a&gt; aims to create a more inclusive and competitive financial services sector accessible to all segments of Mexican society and market entrants. Despite challenges due to COVID-19, this project has been able to hit the ground running with Caravana FinTech, an initiative that seeks to increase adoption and awareness of financial technology (FinTech) solutions that benefit micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs). I recently spoke with Roberto Velez, FinTech Adoption and Socialization Lead, and Lorena Segura, FinTech Socialization Leader, about how the programme is supporting MSMEs to expand their reach and encourage the use of FinTech solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/increasing-adoption-and-awareness-of-fintech-solutions-in-mexico-interview-with-roberto-velez-and-lorena-segura.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/increasing-adoption-and-awareness-of-fintech-solutions-in-mexico-interview-with-roberto-velez-and-lorena-segura.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Muuve.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Talking About Life After an Accelerator with Muuve’s Phanith Phan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently spoke with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childrenshospitalvanderbilt.org/doctors/barkin-shari&quot;&gt;Phanith Phan,&lt;/a&gt; the CEO of Muuve, an innovative delivery services startup in Cambodia. Muuve was one of the startups involved in the 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smart.com.kh/smartscale-powered-by-seedstars-to-host-its-demo-day-in-phnom-penh/&quot;&gt;Smartscale by Seedstars&lt;/a&gt; accelerator, co-funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/cambodia-development-innovations&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; project and telecommunications company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smart.com.kh/?gclid=Cj0KCQjwreT8BRDTARIsAJLI0KLZGTfnbLbol8X5UuazEsB8sqzo_n9AF92h-QRptDHikMSmCCtMI2caAnohEALw_wcB&quot;&gt;Smart Axiata&lt;/a&gt;. This accelerator model was investor-led and focused on connecting scalable tech startups to mentors, investment advisory services, and targeted technical assistance. Muuve is one of Cambodia’s success stories in a growing &lt;a href=&quot;(https://www.raintreecambodia.com/research)&quot;&gt;digital ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;—even through the COVID-19 pandemic. The young team also &lt;a href=&quot;https://e27.co/cambodias-muuve-scores-funding-from-ooctane-to-take-its-food-delivery-service-to-new-cities-20200123/&quot;&gt;secured investment&lt;/a&gt; from Cambodian venture fund, OOCTANE, a few months after finishing the accelerator in 2019. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 06:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/WB.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Strengthening Cyber Resilience as a Cornerstone of Self-Determination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity and cyber resilience are becoming increasingly crucial considerations for countries seeking to assert sovereignty and self-determination. This desire is particularly acute in regions such as Eastern Europe, South Caucasus, and the Western Balkans, all of which face increasingly complex cyberattacks emanating from nefarious individual and nation-state actors. As these countries navigate digitalization and the interconnectedness of their critical infrastructure (CI) operations, including financial networks and government services, they must strengthen their capacity to address vulnerabilities caused by new technological developments and an increasingly hostile international security environment. Domestic leadership, regional cohesion, and international support are pivotal in strengthening cybersecurity capacity, legislative and strategic frameworks, and institutions in these regions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Alexander Sekhniashvili
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/strengthening-cyber-resilience-as-a-cornerstone-of-self-determination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/strengthening-cyber-resilience-as-a-cornerstone-of-self-determination.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Critical Infrastructure</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Capture-a98d9f.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Top 3 Considerations for eLearning Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has caused major disruptions for people from all walks of life. It has dramatically changed the nature of activities we used to do in person, especially those aiming to bring people together to learn, exchange knowledge, and strengthen relationships. As we grapple with the uncertainty of how in-person education and training will continue as the pandemic evolves, many types of learning experiences have preemptively moved online, especially those for adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Center for Digital Acceleration, we see significant opportunities for creative digital collaboration that would have been impossible just a year ago. Electronic learning has emerged as a particularly interesting category for development solutions. Projects with goals that span the thematic spectrum—from strengthening agricultural supply chains to supporting rule of law to stemming climate change—are considering how to implement digital curricula and thinking carefully about what approaches could work best for their myriad stakeholder groups.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandrosolis/">Alejandro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/top-three-considerations-for-elearning-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/top-three-considerations-for-elearning-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>elearning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/alex%20blog%201%20image%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Western Nations Seek to Bulk Up Critical Infrastructure, Digitalization, and Cybersecurity in the Western Balkans</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Western Balkans, like many regions across the world, is navigating the disruptive effects of COVID-19 on their economies, while also digitalizing numerous critical sectors. Critical infrastructure (CI) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/topic/critical-infrastructure-security&quot;&gt;defined&lt;/a&gt; as “the physical and cyber systems and assets that are so vital to [a country] that their incapacity or destruction would have a debilitating impact on physical or economic security or public health or safety.” Recent threats emanating from malicious individual and nation-state actors remind us that cybersecurity considerations are vital to mitigate potentially widespread and devastating effects. In fact, the need to focus on network and system securities is only accelerated with the unique nature of digital challenges brought on by the COVID-19 pandemic in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Alexander Sekhniashvili
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/impact-of-the-us-and-eu-in-critical-infrastructure-digitalization-and-cybersecurity-in-the-western-balkans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/impact-of-the-us-and-eu-in-critical-infrastructure-digitalization-and-cybersecurity-in-the-western-balkans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Critical Infrastructure</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
