<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 13:24:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 13:24:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20head%20shot-0bcd9c-d7d5b5.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Resolution to Support the Tech Sector Where We Need It Most</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 5, I posted the message below on Facebook to hold myself accountable to my New Year’s resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20blog%20pic-3811e6.png&quot; alt=&quot;hanson blog pic-3811e6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple. I want tech businesses to grow and thrive in Nigeria &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of Lagos. I want to support someone who grew up in, works in, and wants to continue working in my hometown, Uyo. This is not just my resolution, but has been my life’s work since I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://starthub.com.ng/&quot;&gt;Start Innovation Hub&lt;/a&gt; five years ago. Start Innovation Hub is an ICT firm and innovation lab that works to expand the tech industry by supporting tech startups and talented individuals in Uyo. We build skills and connect entrepreneurs to economic opportunities, as well as support local businesses by developing software solutions. You can’t deny that the tech sector in Nigeria is growing rapidly, but the concentration of firms in Lagos means that places like Uyo are left behind. Through Start Innovation Hub, I hope to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nextdeegit/">Hanson Johnson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5.%20uganda%20cookstoves%20study.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Four Rs: An Interview With the Lean Research Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are huge fans of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research&quot;&gt;Lean Research&lt;/a&gt; initiative at DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration&lt;/a&gt;. I recently went to the Massachusetts Institute for Technology’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT D-Lab&lt;/a&gt; and sat with &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research/lean-research-community&quot;&gt;Elizabeth, Kendra, and Kim&lt;/a&gt;, the team behind Lean Research, to learn more about the genesis of the initiative and what tools and resources they offer ICT4D practitioners eager to “right-size” their own research approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI2%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Citizen-Centered Design and Frontier Insights in Kabul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Center for Digital Acceleration is excited to announce that we’re taking &lt;em&gt;MiMuni&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/munis-transparencia-gobierno-abierto/municipalidad-de-chiantla&quot;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; transparency and citizen participation application developed for Guatemalan municipalities, and replicating it for five municipalities in Afghanistan through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/afghanistan-strong-hubs-afghan-hope-and-resilience-shahar&quot;&gt;Strong Hubs for Afghan Hope and Resilience (SHAHAR)&lt;/a&gt; project, which is funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development. The first iteration will be with the Municipality of Kabul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI1%20(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FI1 (1).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights in Kabul, part of DAI's citizen-centered design process.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Dashboard-b07795.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>6 Tips for Making Great Monitoring and Evaluation Dashboards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology and data are converging in ways that allow monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;amp;E) professionals to more effectively monitor, evaluate, learn, and adapt on their projects. Dashboards are one of the key tools contributing to this trend, having become more accessible and user friendly through platforms such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/?&amp;amp;OCID=AID719832_SEM_bHb24t0B&amp;amp;lnkd=Google_PowerBI_Brand&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw08XeBRC0ARIsAP_gaQBWS9woBxKkiDNWqYJ1QffUY7fpDoUDQTRkOS4N15amKTJGVg8EmGMaAkDrEALw_wcB&quot;&gt;Microsoft PowerBI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboards are an information management tool that visually track, analyze, and display metrics and data points to monitor the status of a project. DAI is creating dashboards for all new projects to enable teams to learn, evaluate, and adapt to project realities in near real-time. Ultimately, these dashboards make for better monitoring and evaluation and—in turn—better projects. Therefore, it’s important to get it right. So where should you start?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-mataya-6a53373/">John Mataya</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/6-tips-for-making-great-monitoring-and-evaluation-dashboards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/6-tips-for-making-great-monitoring-and-evaluation-dashboards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI%20hairi2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights: Cyber Security Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The headline says it all: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/blog/biggest-data-breaches-2018/&quot;&gt;Over a billion people’s data was compromised in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.” Among the most egregious offenders were some of the most popular tech platforms in the world: Facebook, for example, admitted it had leaked the personal data of nearly 150 million users; Twitter leaked the passwords of nearly all 330 million of its users; and even mighty Google had two of its products hacked: Firebase (an app monitoring tool) leaked the data of more than 100 million users, and Google+ leaked 500,000 users’ personal info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cartography-3244166_640.png&quot; alt=&quot;cartography-3244166_640.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a> &amp; <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/kristen-roggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-cyber-security-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-cyber-security-edition.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2019LookAhead.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In our last post, we reviewed our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2018.html&quot;&gt;top posts of 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The most-read articles covered a lot of ground—from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/fortnite-for-international-development.html&quot;&gt;Fortnite for development&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-malawi-communication-among-rural-communities.html&quot;&gt;digital lives in rural Malawi&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html&quot;&gt;making your own chatbot&lt;/a&gt;. We equally expect 2019 to be full of interesting projects, engaging conversations with colleagues, and, as always, meaningful opportunities to keep learning and doing better, more impactful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few topics we’re thinking about as we dive into the year. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DAIGlobal&quot;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you want to collaborate as we explore where they’ll take us—and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9cb0638e1f8d7224ba7058efa&amp;amp;id=67e58edf98&quot;&gt;stay tuned to our blog&lt;/a&gt; for updates throughout the year!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 10:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2018YearDAIDig-17b95e.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Year in Review: Top 10 Posts of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, Digital@DAI published more than 50 posts covering everything from women’s entrepreneurship in Cambodia to cyber security for development to smartphone apps for fisheries in Central America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We featured digital experts from organizations such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alabriqu&quot;&gt;John’s Hopkins University&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simprints.com/&quot;&gt;Simprints&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.every1mobile.com/&quot;&gt;Every1Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hotosm.org/&quot;&gt;Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/&quot;&gt;Panoply Digital&lt;/a&gt;, and generated nearly 47,000 page views. The blog continues to explore the potential of digital technology across sectors, geographies, clients, and constituents, reflecting the work that we do. As we continue to engage with all of you—and with the ICT4D community through DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA)&lt;/a&gt;—our focus on research and products will expand as we ensure that our field-focused  deployments of digital solutions are responsible, inclusive, and dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-ten-posts-of-2017.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;final post of 2017&lt;/a&gt; we reviewed the 10 most-read articles of the year. With our audience and number of blog posts continuing to grow, we now present our top 10 for 2018. These posts showcase a range of topics, content, and writers. Going into 2019, we hope you will connect with us, read the blog, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://confirmsubscription.com/h/r/066AFBA15492935C&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to Digital@DAI so you don’t miss any updates in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 10:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ehr-1476525_1280%20(1)-e346f7.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>An Embarrassment of Riches</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Years ago, yours truly was struggling with a major life decision, one that had led to many a sleepless night: Where to go to grad school? I’d been accepted into a number of programs and was agonizing over my options. My dad had graciously taken on the role of my sounding board until one day he blurted out in frustration, “you have an embarrassment of riches, Rachel. Just decide!”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Rachel Clad
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/an-embarrassment-of-riches.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/an-embarrassment-of-riches.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Pirated%20Software-161a1c.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cyber Security Series Part 3: Pirated Software</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been about two months since I last contributed to the Cyber Security Series, but don’t let the time fool you into thinking we haven’t been engaging extensively on the topic. As many of you might remember, the Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) published the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-inclusion-and-a-trusted-internet.html&quot;&gt;Digital Inclusion and a Trusted Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; report in October on the topic. For those of you who have not read it, I highly recommend it, particularly if you’re interested in cyber security or data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-series-part-1-trust-is-why-cyber-security-matters-to-digital-development.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; in this series focused on the issue of trust and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-2.html&quot;&gt;second post&lt;/a&gt; argued that investment in regulations that support the enabling environment, strong institutions, and skills of the population are key to integrating cyber security across a country’s economy. This post focuses on a more micro-level challenge—pirated software—and how addressing it is key to responding to cyber security overall.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-series-part-3-pirated-software.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-series-part-3-pirated-software.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/headData.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Data, Analysis, and Information (Not as Boring as It Sounds)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t excited by the headline—you should be! In this blog I will highlight a few issues I run across when discussing projects or planning data analytics solutions. Going into the details of each of them would take quite some time, so I will keep the anecdotes (data?) brief. There will undoubtedly be many interpretations of the data -&amp;gt; analytics -&amp;gt; insights/information flow, but this blog is simply an opportunity for me to share my own thoughts. After all, what are we as good data stewards and scientists without proper debate?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/data-analysis-and-information.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/data-analysis-and-information.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Analysis</category>
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
