<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:16:08 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/photo-1585411241969-9ac0c565451b-a68beb.webp" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Privacy: How COVID-19 Has Sped Up the Debate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As many countries struggle to manage the COVID-19 crisis, governments globally are looking to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-30/the-world-embraces-contact-tracing-technology-to-fight-covid-19?utm_campaign=The%20Interface&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue%20newsletter&quot;&gt;data-driven technologies&lt;/a&gt; to minimize cases or to help facilitate a transition out of lockdown. The technologies being claimed to protect, prevent, and track include &lt;a href=&quot;corona.asan.gov.af&quot;&gt;symptom tracking apps&lt;/a&gt; that help us understand the disease, digital contact tracing apps that alert us to our interaction with the virus, quarantine enforcement apps that monitor people’s compliance (such as those in Hong Kong, Poland, and Kazakhstan; proposed in Russia and Egypt), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ukauthority.com/articles/open-university-develops-digital-certificate-for-covid-19-immunity/&quot;&gt;immunity certification&lt;/a&gt; that identify individuals who have had COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In more developed nations such as the United Kingdom and United States, conversations around data privacy are rife. For example, the UK National Health Service (NHS) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-52441428&quot;&gt;negotiating&lt;/a&gt; with Google and Apple about the efficacy of its proposed contact-tracing app in light of the two tech giants’ stringent adherence to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the face of serious threats, many of us might say we have a reasonable expectation that our government will use technology to track and pre-empt risks. In the same way we might expect protection from terrorist attacks, we may also accept such measures to be employed during a public health crisis like the current pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the vital question is: how can we ensure that the deployment of these digital tools are effective and do not set a dangerous precedent of digital surveillance?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 05:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/privacy-how-much-should-we-be-willing-to-give-up-in-a-covid-19-era.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/privacy-how-much-should-we-be-willing-to-give-up-in-a-covid-19-era.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fig8_cfr-0d2f6a.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 5: Different Models of Infection Rates in Mexico and What they Tell Us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenges of measuring the infection rates of COVID-19 are enormous for even the most prepared countries, given the need for testing to reach a significant enough amount of the population to accurately detect its spread. While the total number of recorded cases in the world thus far have mostly been in the United States, Europe, and East Asia, many low- and middle-income countries have begun to see increases in reported cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mexico, the number of cases has slowly risen. Public health experts have &lt;a href=&quot;https://mexiconewsdaily.com/news/coronavirus/experts-say-mexico-hasnt-done-enough-virus-testing/&quot;&gt;urgently suggested&lt;/a&gt; that testing needs to be dramatically increased to appropriately track the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic. As the graph below shows, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/#countries&quot;&gt;numbers reported from Worldometer&lt;/a&gt; corroborate this testing deficit, as Mexico has one of the lowest rates of testing per 1 million people in the region, even among countries of similar size and income per capita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fig1_testingpercap-c8bcbb.png&quot; alt=&quot;fig1_testingpercap-c8bcbb.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-part-5-different-methods-to-model-infection-rates-in-mexico-and-what-they-tell-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-part-5-different-methods-to-model-infection-rates-in-mexico-and-what-they-tell-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>5 Ways Entrepreneurship Ecosystems are Using Technology to Adapt to the COVID-19 Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During this unprecedented global economic downturn caused by COVID-19, accelerators, incubators, and other entrepreneurship support organizations have a valuable role to play in helping entrepreneurs and small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in emerging and frontier markets. Over the past two months supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-shell-livewire-global-consultancy&quot;&gt;Shell LiveWIRE&lt;/a&gt; global entrepreneurship program and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/ghana-kosmos-innovation-center-kic&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt;, DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/sustainable-business&quot;&gt;Sustainable Business Group&lt;/a&gt; has worked closely with the Global Accelerator Network (&lt;a href=&quot;C:\\Users\\ZRaheem\\Documents\\DAI\\Sustainable Business Group (SBG)\\Brown Bag Presentations\\10 Trends Changing Entrepreneurship Ecosystems\\Blog on Entrepreneurship Trends\\gan.co&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt;) and the Aspen Network of Development Entrepreneurs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://andeglobal.org/&quot;&gt;ANDE&lt;/a&gt;) to leverage technology in support of global entrepreneurship in emerging economies. For corporates, foundations, donors, and development banks that support similar entrepreneurship ecosystems, we offer some learning here from our projects and global networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oscar-nilsson-1BHYZFVyGaw-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo by Oscar Nilsson on Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/zaki-raheem">Zaki Raheem</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/doug-mclean">Doug McLean</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-ways-entrepreneurship-ecosystems-are-using-technology-to-adapt-to-the-covid-19-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-ways-entrepreneurship-ecosystems-are-using-technology-to-adapt-to-the-covid-19-crisis.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/figure_5.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 4: Forecasting Hospital Capacity in Mexico</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was written by DAI Data Scientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-parr-4a534897/&quot;&gt;Jamie Parr&lt;/a&gt;, with contributions from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/greg-maly/&quot;&gt;Greg Maly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/gratiana-fu/&quot;&gt;Gratiana Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/eduardo-gonzalez-pier&quot;&gt;Eduardo González-Pier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/susan-scribner&quot;&gt;Susan Scribner&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kirsten-weeks&quot;&gt;Kirsten Weeks&lt;/a&gt;. This analysis is Part 4 of a series on known risk factors associated with COVID-19, with a specific focus on Mexico. It is the first of several posts that will provide an analytical overview of different aspects of COVID-19 in Mexico. The analysis will be updated as we receive additional data and the code for all related analysis will be made available shortly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/examining-hospital-capacity-in-mexico.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/examining-hospital-capacity-in-mexico.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Information Liberation: What is Open Data, and Why Does it Matter?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Less than two weeks ago, on April 21, 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2020/04/21/open-data-campaign-divide/&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; announced its support for the growing open data movement through the launch of an “Open Data Campaign.” Having recently spent several days researching successful open data initiatives, the statement caught my attention. The World Bank uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendatatoolkit.worldbank.org/en/essentials.html&quot;&gt;the Open Knowledge Foundation’s definition&lt;/a&gt; for open data. According to it, open data means data “can be freely used, modified, and shared by anyone for any purpose.” In practical terms, this means data that is both &lt;em&gt;legally&lt;/em&gt; open, publicly accessible or with minimal restrictions, and &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; open, published in electronic formats that are computer readable and nonproprietary. This type of data is not to be confused with “big data.” As I recently learned, there are differences. For instance, open data derives its value from the sharing of the data and its widespread availability, rather than the volume (as big data does). I won’t be spending more time on this particular topic, but if you’re interested in learning more, I highly recommend reading a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/should-big-data-be-open-data.html&quot;&gt;guest post&lt;/a&gt; we published on the subject in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-what-is-open-data-and-why-does-it-matter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-what-is-open-data-and-why-does-it-matter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/blog%201.webp" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Everything Old is New Again: Remembering the Lessons of Early ICT4D in the COVID-19 Era</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often in the early days of digital development, it felt like there was a small group of big, innovative brains in one room all working on similar visions of how best to leverage the growing presence of the iconic Nokia 3310 across the developing world. Frontline SMS, Ushahidi, Souktel, and other groups were leading the charge from various corners of the earth, and design luminaries such as Jan Chipchase were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2008/04/13/magazine/13anthropology-t.html&quot;&gt;interviewed&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; think pieces on how cellphones could end global poverty. When I moved to Palestine to work for Souktel at the end of 2010, I was often in the same room as ICT4D “godparents” &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Banks&quot;&gt;Ken Banks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/waugaman/&quot;&gt;Adele Waugaman&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erik_Hersman&quot;&gt;Erik Hersman&lt;/a&gt;, pleading our case to skeptical mobile network operators and Silicon Valley types who found our little ventures thrilling in a slightly Orientalist way. With texting as the tech &lt;em&gt;du jour&lt;/em&gt;, everyone codified similar lessons in real time around the successful design of, for example, mobile awareness campaigns. The ICT4D sector grew rapidly across markets, simultaneously building strong use cases for users and development practitioners alike. I do have some hilarious stories of mobile campaign lessons learned from the Somali piracy crisis, but I will save those for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, all these lessons are relevant again as we globally try to tackle the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 09:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/everything-old-is-new-again-remembering-the-lessons-of-early-ict4d-in-the-covid-era.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/everything-old-is-new-again-remembering-the-lessons-of-early-ict4d-in-the-covid-era.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/coding%20classes_Cambodia%20DI.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New RFA Calls for Innovative Solutions to Advance Digital Skills for Small Firms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone is talking about digital transformation—especially now that digital processes and tools are a mandatory part of daily activities for most businesses, schools, and citizens across the world in response to the global COVID-19 outbreak. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and DAI have been working to enhance digital skills, improve connectivity, and enable locally led innovation for years. Today, we are all confronted with a new set of urgent challenges. How do we ensure that citizens can safely and effectively use digital technologies to advance their own economic livelihoods and those of their countries?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kate Heuisler
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-rfa-calls-for-innovative-solutions-to-advance-digital-skills-for-smes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-rfa-calls-for-innovative-solutions-to-advance-digital-skills-for-smes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/days_joint.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>COVID-19 Data Analysis, Part 3: Rethinking the Global Health Security Index</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The next installment in our COVID-19 analysis series connects the dots between the datasets we have explored in our previous posts and brings in a new dataset that came to our attention over the past couple of weeks. In this paper, we look at the relationship between country scores from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghsindex.org&quot;&gt;Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI)’s Global Health Security Index&lt;/a&gt; and levels of response by country governments measured using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bsg.ox.ac.uk/research/research-projects/oxford-covid-19-government-response-tracker%5D&quot;&gt;Oxford COVID-19 Government Response Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. You can read more about our initial exploratory analysis of the Global Health Security Index &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-2-health-capacity-and-preparedness.html&quot;&gt;here in our previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Oxford University has provided an initial report of its data on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-3-rethinking-the-global-health-security-index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19-data-analysis-part-3-rethinking-the-global-health-security-index.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/COVID-19_BehaviorChange.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Approaching Digital Behavior Change Communications in the COVID-19 Era</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While tackling the spread of the COVID-19 disease takes a multi-faceted approach, behavior change—especially around personal and respiratory hygiene, proper handwashing, social distancing, and so on—remains a critical need across countries where DAI and our clients operate. Further, as organizations and individuals increasingly embrace digital-based approaches to collaboration, communication, and information gathering, we are presented with an opportunity to incorporate these technologies across behavior change communication strategies. However, as many organizations have experienced since the start of near-global lockdowns, this transition to an all-digital way of working comes with unique roadblocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, the DAI Center for Digital Acceleration has been exploring how digital communication tools can be used to build communications campaigns aimed at stemming the COVID-19 tide and spreading accurate information about targeted behaviors. We’ve pulled together some quick thoughts on the topic, but frankly, these are principles that apply in most &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; effort of this sort.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anand-varghese/">Anand Varghese</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsey-kirn-8903a55/">Lindsey Kirn</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/approaching-digital-behavior-change-communications-in-the-covid-19-era.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/approaching-digital-behavior-change-communications-in-the-covid-19-era.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SHE%20Investments'%20Ngeay%20Ngeay%20business%20info%20and%20online%20learning%20site.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Promoting Resilient Ecosystems: How Cambodians are Adapting in the Face of COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years in Cambodia leading the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/cambodia-development-innovations&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; project taught me a lot about innovation. I saw innovators employ entrepreneurial thinking to develop out-of-the-box, creative solutions to problems, helping hundreds of thousands of Cambodians—automated phone calls warning people of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/blog/the-tech-mermaid-alert/&quot;&gt;coming floods&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind, as does a mobile &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edemy.org/#tesdopi&quot;&gt;test prep application&lt;/a&gt; to help high school students prepare for national exams. It’s this entrepreneurial thinking that the world desperately needs in this time of hardship, where livelihoods, the economy, and social cohesion are being challenged in unprecedented ways. Which naturally begs the question: In the face of COVID-19, what happens next in Cambodia’s innovation community?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/promoting-resilient-ecosystems-how-cambodians-are-adapting-in-the-face-of-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/promoting-resilient-ecosystems-how-cambodians-are-adapting-in-the-face-of-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
