<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 08:38:58 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 08:38:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Thumbnail%20MFA.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Authentication Dilemma: Can a Single Solution Guarantee Security for Small Firms?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the rapid rate of digitalization catalyzed by the COVID-19 pandemic, cyber-attacks have become ubiquitous, presenting opportunities to improve cybersecurity practices for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs). SMEs contribute up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/smefinance&quot;&gt;40 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the gross domestic product in emerging economies, make up 90 percent of all businesses, and provide more than 50 percent of employment worldwide, making them significant economic drivers and digital supply chain actors. They also endure unprecedented malicious cyber activity, such as ransomware, phishing, password targeting, and advanced persistent threat attacks. In Nigeria, cyber attacks against SMEs have increased by &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardian.ng/business-services/cyber-attack-on-nigerian-smes-up-by-89-per-cent-in-2022/&quot;&gt;89 percent&lt;/a&gt;, in 2022 alone, and in India, more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/more-than-60-of-mid-sized-indian-organizations-surveyed-fell-victim-to-a-cyberattack-in-2021-sophos-research-shows/articleshow/90517626.cms&quot;&gt;60 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all SMEs experienced attacks last year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alexander Sekhniashvili
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-authentication-dilemma.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-authentication-dilemma.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>SME</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/austin-distel-x1J0zj63ZjM-unsplash%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Future of Work: A Review on the Trending Phenomenon of Digital Nomads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020, the world witnessed and experienced the COVID-19 pandemic reshape organizational cultures and how people define work in their lives. Companies shifted their models to accommodate working from home, and that trend continues, as an Upwork &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/press/releases/upwork-study-finds-22-of-american-workforce-will-be-remote-by-2025&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; estimated that by 2025, 22 percent of the U.S. workforce will be remote workers. The reshaping of work also pushed further the phenomenon of digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/afua-owusu/">Afua Owusu</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/temi-olatunji/">Temi Olatunji</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-of-work-a-review-on-the-trending-phenomenon-of-digital-nomads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-of-work-a-review-on-the-trending-phenomenon-of-digital-nomads.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Economy</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Digital Communications</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Future of Work</category>
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/pexels-pixabay-60504.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lack of Cybersecurity Talent Poses a Global Challenge and Opportunity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The limited supply of a skilled workforce is one of the major challenges plaguing the technology ecosystems of countries around the world. The field of cybersecurity is an excellent case study. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/2021/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Workforce-Study-2021.ashx&quot;&gt;2021 (ICS)2Cybersecurity Workforce Study&lt;/a&gt;, the cybersecurity workforce gap—the number of people needed to help organizations protect their critical assets from cybersecurity threats—is 2.72 million worldwide. Although down from 3.12 million the previous year, this is still a significant gap. The true shortfall is likely greater, as the study does not account for the public policy, diplomatic, or business talent in small and medium-sized enterprises. This post explores opportunities to enhance the cybersecurity literacy of policymakers, diplomats, and business leaders, and makes the case for cybersecurity workforce development across these professions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyberworkforce.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyberworkforce.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/tariq%20image.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Emerging eLearning Series: Accessible Training at Scale to Increase Local Governance Capacity in Libya</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) has been at the forefront of supporting international development projects to understand, apply, and implement eLearning solutions in settings that had not initially considered their wide-scale use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second in a series of posts that seek to capture some of these efforts, celebrate innovative successes, consider critical lessons learned, and support practitioners who continue to do this work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 23:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/trevor-oxley">Trevor Olexy</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anne-hand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-accessible-training-at-scale-to-increase-local-governance-capacity-in-libya.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-accessible-training-at-scale-to-increase-local-governance-capacity-in-libya.html</guid>
        
        <category>eLearning</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>Emerging eLearning Series</category>
        
        <category>eTraining</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Neema%20Iyer%20Headshot.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Shaping History Series: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation—Interview with Neema Iyer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ineema/&quot;&gt;Neema Iyer&lt;/a&gt; is a trailblazer. Iyer is an artist and technologist influencing the digital development sector with her innovative lens on the intersection of data, technology, and design to improve government service delivery. The East African native is the founder and director of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pollicy.org/&quot;&gt;Pollicy&lt;/a&gt;, a feminist collective of technologists, data scientists, and creatives. After graduating with a master’s degree in global epidemiology from Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, Iyer returned to Africa, where she was exposed to the lack of gendered perspectives in the information and communications sector on the continent. Simultaneously, she was also experiencing and witnessing frustrations at various touch points with the government, such as securing important documents, information, or services.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 10:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/afua-owusu/">Afua Owusu</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/inta-plostins/">Inta Plostins</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-series-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-interview-with-neema-iyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-series-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-interview-with-neema-iyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Shaping History Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare for Development 4.0: Recommendations for Policymakers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, artificial intelligence (AI) is broadly understood to include not only long-term efforts to simulate the general intelligence humans exhibit, but also fast-evolving technologies—such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/cloud/learn/convolutional-neural-networks&quot;&gt;convolutional neural networks&lt;/a&gt;—that affect many facets of modern society, such as healthcare, national security, social media, agriculture, and more. The sweeping changes caused by AI have significantly increased the gap between government policy and innovative business models that rely on AI deployment. AI is changing norms and business models throughout society, demanding new and effective policy responses from governments on subjects with little real precedence. While governments struggle to adapt to the rapid pace of change, AI brings new solutions and offers the potential to transform how policy is made by providing new tools and methods of policy development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 12:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare-for-development-4-dot-0-recommendations-for-policymakers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare-for-development-4-dot-0-recommendations-for-policymakers.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>industry 4.0</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FTF%20Press%20Release.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Webinar Series: Connecting Innovators with Funders in Bangladesh</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Identifying and facilitating linkages between those who own promising digital tools for the agriculture sector—better known as AgTech—and those who have funds to invest is key to supporting the long-term sustainability of scalable digital AgTech tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panelists at a recent webinar unpacked exactly how these links can be accomplished. Hosted by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Feed the Future Bangladesh Digital Agricultural Activity, and the first in a series, “Scaling Digital AgTech: Building Ecosystem for Innovation, Investment, and Sustainability of Digital Tools in Bangladesh” featured panelists from business accelerators, venture capital firms, impact investment organizations, donor organizations supporting digital agriculture tools, and technology firms.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 11:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavelhoq/?originalSubdomain=bd">Sajedul Hoq</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/naba-tareque/?originalSubdomain=bd">Naba Nashit Tareque</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/connecting-innovators-with-funders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/connecting-innovators-with-funders.html</guid>
        
        <category>AgTech</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FHI%20360%20Blog%20Post.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Improving Digital Literacy and Security Training In Cambodia: Suggestions for Funders, Training Providers, and Content Creators</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maura Joul, Annie Kemmerer, Baker Lu, and Billy Taki are second-year master’s students in the Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) international development program. They worked with DAI on the Innovations for Social Accountability in Cambodia (ISAC) project, implemented by FHI 360 and funded by U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), to conduct a landscape assessment of digital literacy and security education and training initiatives in Cambodia. The team interviewed digital security consultants, content creators, training providers, local civil society organizations (CSOs), international organizations, and industry experts in Cambodia. This post summarizes their key findings and recommendations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSOs in Cambodia are experiencing rapid changes in response to COVID-19. The pandemic forced Cambodian citizens served by CSOs into the digital world, leading these organizations to shift their communications and programming to virtual platforms. Although Cambodian CSOs successfully aclimated to the rapid digitalization, the move to virtual has increased digital security issues in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FHI%20360%20Blog%20Post.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FHI 360 Blog Post.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 14:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maura-joul/">Maura Joul</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anne-kemmerer/">Annie Kemmerer</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/xiaoyilu/">Baker Lu</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamtaki/">Billy Taki</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/improving-digital-literacy-and-security-training-in-cambodia-suggestions-for-funders-training-providers-and-content-creators.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/improving-digital-literacy-and-security-training-in-cambodia-suggestions-for-funders-training-providers-and-content-creators.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>Digital Skills</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Designing%20for%20Dig%20Lit.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Literacy Series: Closing the Gap for Semi-Literate and Illiterate Populations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the Center for Digital Acceleration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=docs&amp;amp;ust=1658146562000797&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3j9jpbm928yigZBp2zwbhX&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a series dedicated to digital literacy in international development. We want to learn more about this nuanced topic because digital literacy is central to sustaining the rapid digitalization that has taken place over the last two years. As donors, implementing partners, private companies, and government agencies invest in the digital transformation of key sectors and services, practitioners must prioritize helping the communities interact with digital technology “&lt;a href=&quot;https://publications.jrc.ec.europa.eu/repository/handle/JRC128415&quot;&gt;confidently, critically, and safely.&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I’ve had the pleasure of learning how international development projects can achieve this goal. While conducting research for the U.S. Agency for International Development’s (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-literacy-primer&quot;&gt;Digital Literacy Primer&lt;/a&gt;, I learned how important it is to design digital literacy activities that meet users where they are. A university student looking for an office job, a government official expected to adhere to new cybersecurity policies, and a farmer looking to use his mobile phone to diagnose crop diseases all have different contexts and needs that will shape how a practitioner supports a digital literacy journey. Recognizing the importance of developing unique strategies to serve these unique user groups, one question lingers in my mind: How can we support digital literacy among users who are not literate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, are you new to the concept of digital literacy? If so, I highly recommend reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-the-digcomp-framework.html&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; of this series to learn more about the concept and how frameworks such as the European Union DigComp Framework can help development practitioners categorize the skills, knowledge, and attitudes needed to develop digital literacy. Another recent post, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://dai-global-digital.com/defining-and-exploring-digital-literacy-in-digital-development.html&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=docs&amp;amp;ust=1658146562000292&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1KCoAHF1nIj1Q2nGOCPyLn&quot;&gt;“Defining and Exploring Digital Literacy in Digital Development,”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is also a helpful resource that shares how USAID defines digital literacy and how the USAID-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; program is incorporating digital literacy activities throughout its portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/packard_pb_india_11.11fullrelease016-1200x800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;packard_pb_india_11.11fullrelease016-1200x800.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Images of Empowerment.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-closing-the-gap-for-semi-literate-and-illiterate-populations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-closing-the-gap-for-semi-literate-and-illiterate-populations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sumeet-singh-okfXVsBHAtQ-unsplash%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Embracing the Unlikely Resilience of Feature Phones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of us in the development sector have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.worldbank.org/digital-development/mobile-based-solutions-can-strengthen-human-capital-gains-disrupted-covid-19&quot;&gt;preparing&lt;/a&gt; for an inevitable and imminent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/events/2021/06/10/using-smartphones-to-strengthen-the-human-capital-of-online-and-offline-populations-new-evidence-and-collaborations-for-&quot;&gt;smartphone&lt;/a&gt; future. But in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/business-60763168&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, the BBC highlighted an interesting—if somewhat unexpected—phenomenon in the world of digital devices: the “return of the dumbphones” (we prefer the less pejorative term “feature phones,” which we use in this piece). According to the article, “While sales figures are hard to come by, one report said that global purchases of [feature phones] were due to hit one billion units last year, up from 400 million in 2019. This compares to worldwide sales of 1.4 billion smartphones last year, following a 12.5 percent decline in 2020.” Some might argue that the feature phone has never really gone away.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/anand-varghese">Anand Varghese</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/galia-nurko">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/embracing-the-unlikely-resilience-of-feature-phones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/embracing-the-unlikely-resilience-of-feature-phones.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Skills</category>
        
        <category>Smartphones</category>
        
        <category>Feature Phones</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
