<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 10:16:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 10:16:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting ICT Into the Hands of More Women</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 8 is International Women’s Day! To celebrate, we’ll look at a course on women and ICT inclusion developed by USAID Digital Inclusion, mSTAR, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/&quot;&gt;Panoply Digital&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/gender-and-ict-online-course/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to access the course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/catherine-highet-a924094/">Katie Highet</a> &amp; <a href="https://www.panoplydigital.com/our-team/#/alex-tyers-2/">Alex Tyers</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-improve-gender-and-ict-outcomes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-improve-gender-and-ict-outcomes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Resilience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICT for Citizen Engagement and Advocacy: Lessons Learned from Mozambique DIÁLOGO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/mozambique-democratic-governance-support-programme-dgsp&quot;&gt;Mozambique Democratic Governance Programme&lt;/a&gt;, DIÁLOGO, funded by the U.K. Department for International Development, worked with citizens, civil society, local media, and municipal government to engage more effectively on local issues. DIÁLOGO supported innovative solutions, including mobile- and web-based technologies, to amplify the voices of citizens and help governments respond to their demands. The programme ran from 2012 in the five urban municipalities of Beira, Maputo, Nampula, Quelimane, and Tete, and ended last December.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/icts-for-citizen-engagement-and-advocacy-lessons-learned-from-mozambique-dialogo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/icts-for-citizen-engagement-and-advocacy-lessons-learned-from-mozambique-dialogo.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DFID’s Digital Strategy: What Does it Mean for DAI?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the U.K. Department for International Development (DFID) launched its much-anticipated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dfid-digital-strategy-2018-to-2020-doing-development-in-a-digital-world&quot;&gt;Digital Strategy 2018-2020: Doing Development in a Digital World&lt;/a&gt;, outlining its vision and approach towards using technology to have a bigger, faster, and more cost-effective impact on the lives of poor people—particularly those who are marginalised.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/dfids-digital-strategy-what-does-it-mean-for-dai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/dfids-digital-strategy-what-does-it-mean-for-dai.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Past the Blockchain Hype Cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Distributed Ledger Technologies (DLTs), commonly referred to as blockchain applications, are possibly the most talked about innovation of the day. And the most commonly discussed DLT applications are those that involve financial transactions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptocurrency&quot;&gt;cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Fortune Magazine&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/12/26/4-technology-trends-2018/&quot;&gt;recently listed&lt;/a&gt; “The Fintech Renaissance” as the second-most important technology trend of 2018, and with good reason. Last month Bitcoin saw more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockchain.info/charts/n-transactions?timespan=all&quot;&gt;400,000 transactions&lt;/a&gt; per day. Despite warnings of Bitcoin’s volatility, the increased investment in cryptocurrencies is hard to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about all of the other promises of DLTs? There are no shortage of articles written about their impact on data security, the value of smart contracts to create efficient online transactions, and the value of data democratization and transparency through shared ledgers. While there are case studies for each of these promising areas, distributed application developers are in short supply, and active implementations for global development projects are rare. As a result, I get the sense that blockchain may be entering the peak if its hype cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-past-the-blockchain-hype-cycle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-past-the-blockchain-hype-cycle.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why is DAI Investing in a Coding School?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI and Rockville, Maryland-based United Solutions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/dai-hosts-launch-of-new-coding-school-in-montgomery-county&quot;&gt;recently launched&lt;/a&gt; a business called Code Partners to provide classroom instruction in software development. Code Partners will rely on the proven curriculum and teaching methods of Seattle-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codefellows.org/&quot;&gt;Code Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, starting with beginner-level courses in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 10:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/bobby-jefferson">Bobby Jefferson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/why-is-dai-investing-in-a-coding-school.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/why-is-dai-investing-in-a-coding-school.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“S3” Site Selection System: A Data-Driven Decision-Making Tool for Effective Engagement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently while on assignment in Haiti, a project manager for a local agricultural development project asked my team why we weren’t targeting certain rural communities. According to him, those communities are the ones that could really benefit from the type of work we were doing. While we had good reason to work where we were working, the question stuck: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can we be certain that we are targeting the right communities?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 12:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/karim-bin-humam">Karim Bin-Humam</a>,<a href="https://twitter.com/jmatz1919">Josh Linden</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/sit-selection-data-driven-decision-making-for-effective-beneficiary-targeting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/sit-selection-data-driven-decision-making-for-effective-beneficiary-targeting.html</guid>
        
        <category>Site Selection</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Don’t Need to Reinvent the Wheel, But it’s Time to Invest in Roads and Highways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the good news: Over the past 10 years the digital health community has begun to heal from a severe case of pilotitis. As a community of innovators and health systems researchers, we increasingly recognize that creating and testing new digital health tools in the absence of investments in the enabling ecosystem is likely to produce limited, short-term, and small-scale impact. Without concerted efforts to fertilize the soil in which the seeds of innovation are planted, those seeds will never mature beyond a sapling. That is, unless we pay attention to the policy and regulatory environment, the telecommunications and electrical infrastructure, and most importantly, the availability of trained and appropriate human resources to facilitate scale-up and sustainability, we cannot expect national-scale digital health projects to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://twitter.com/alabriqu">Dr. Alain Labrique</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/time-to-invest-in-roads-and-highways.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/time-to-invest-in-roads-and-highways.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build a Facebook Messenger Chatbot in 5 Steps in Just 5 Minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I wrote a post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-chatbot.html&quot;&gt;“I Made a Facebook Chatbot (And You Can, Too)”&lt;/a&gt; where I laid out the case for chatbots as an outreach and engagement tool in international development. To recap, here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 14:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KIC Expands its Support of Tech-Driven Entrepreneurship to Mauritania</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of Digital@DAI will know that we’ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;supporting&lt;/a&gt; Kosmos Energy’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosmosinnovationcenter.com/&quot;&gt;Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC) in Ghana for the last two years. KIC’s work with young tech entrepreneurs in the agricultural sector has garnered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosmosinnovationcenter.com/2016-awards/&quot;&gt;awards &lt;/a&gt;and plenty of media attention, and Kosmos is now looking to apply what it has learned to a new country: Mauritania.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 12:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Sub-Saharan Africa</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking Ahead to 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year provides a great opportunity to think about priorities for year ahead. Last week we wrote a post highlighting the top &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-ten-posts-of-2017.html&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; of 2017. The most-read articles covered a lot of ground—from reflections on specific projects, to advances in our thinking on best practices for human-centered design (HCD), to technology reviews. So, what’s on our minds for the year to come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Looking%20ahea%20to%202018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking ahea to 2018.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 12:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-to-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-to-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
