<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:04:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/susannah%20blog%20photo%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Part I: Big Data in Agriculture Conference Download: Building Trust and Fueling Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a data enthusiast with a budding curiosity in digital agriculture, I was excited to attend the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigdata.cgiar.org/hyderabad-2019/&quot;&gt;2019 CGIAR Big Data in Agriculture Convention&lt;/a&gt; in Hyderabad, India. The event brought together attendees from around the globe to connect over the theme of &lt;em&gt;Trust: humans, machines, and ecosystems.&lt;/em&gt; The CGIAR Big Data Platform aims to “use big data approaches to solve agriculture development problems faster, better, and at greater scale than before.” The platform does this by connecting CGIAR-affiliated researchers from around the globe with development practitioners and ag-tech providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did I have the rare opportunity to engage with super smart scientist-types who, unlike me, have job titles like “plant geneticist” and “mycology and plant pathology specialist,” but I also was compelled to consider the definition and role of trust in the application of data and technology to building resilient global food security.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/part-i-big-data-in-agriculture-conference-download-building-trust-and-fueling-innovation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/part-i-big-data-in-agriculture-conference-download-building-trust-and-fueling-innovation.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/India%20Photo5%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Respond Now: USAID Seeks ICT Regulatory Policy Technical Assistance Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is issuing an expression of interest (EOI) to support the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;strong&gt;Promoting American Approaches to ICT Regulatory Policy (ProICT)&lt;/strong&gt; activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 06:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-is-seeking-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-is-seeking-ict-regulatory-policy-technical-assistance-services.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SLW%20PH%20TOT.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>10 Trends Changing Entrepreneurship Ecosystems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re supporting early stage entrepreneurs in emerging and frontier markets, there’s a lot to be excited about as we approach the start of the third decade of this century! Over the past year supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-shell-livewire-global-consultancy&quot;&gt;Shell LiveWIRE&lt;/a&gt; global entrepreneurship program and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/ghana-kosmos-innovation-center-kic&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center (KIC)&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve had the chance to attend some rather dynamic conferences, ‘un’-conferences, meetups, and pitch events with the Global Accelerator Network (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gan.co/&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt;), the Aspen Network of Development Entrepreneurs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://andeglobal.org/&quot;&gt;ANDE&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techstars.com/&quot;&gt;Techstars&lt;/a&gt;, and the International Business Innovation Association (&lt;a href=&quot;https://inbia.org/&quot;&gt;InBIA&lt;/a&gt;). I’ve observed some trends from the inspiring incubator and accelerator program managers that I’ve gotten to meet from around the world—and will share the best ones below:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/zaki-raheem">Zaki Raheem</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/10-trends-changing-entrepreneurship-ecosystems.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/10-trends-changing-entrepreneurship-ecosystems.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID on the Digital Development Awards and Communications Activities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Global Development Lab, the Center for Digital Development (CDD) addresses gaps in digital access and affordability and advances the use of technology and advanced data analysis in development. DAI’s Digital Frontiers project works closely with the CDD’s Knowledge and Insights (K&amp;amp;I) team, which leads the Center’s work in knowledge management, communications, and training.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-and-insights-rfp-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/knowledge-and-insights-rfp-blog.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: El contexto digital de la población con discapacidad en Honduras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se estima que el número de personas que viven con algún tipo de discapacidad en América Latina y el Caribe entre 2001 y 2013 fue de más de &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paho.org/hon/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;amp;view=download&amp;amp;alias=383-identificacion-y-caracterizacion-de-las-personas-con-discapacidad-en-francisco-morazan-2017&amp;amp;category_slug=fortalecimiento-de-sistemas-de-salud&amp;amp;Itemid=211&quot;&gt;70 millones&lt;/a&gt; (o 12.5 porciento de la población regional total, el 12.6 porciento de la población de América Latina y el 61 porciento de los países del Caribe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En Honduras los estudios acerca del tema de discapacidad son escasos y limitados. Según los resultados de la Encuesta Permanente de Hogares con Propósitos Múltiples del Instituto Nacional de Estadística (INE) realizada en septiembre 2002, se encontró que en Honduras existían 177,516 personas con discapacidad, lo que representa una prevalencia de 2.65 porciento, con predominio masculino (55 porciento) en comparación de la población femenina (45 porciento). Sin embargo, estudios recientes del [Censo 2013 del INE] indicaron la existencia de 205,423 personas con discapacidad, y &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;otro estudio&lt;/a&gt; de Flores, et al. (2014) encontró una tasa de prevalencia del 4.6 porciento, que significa un total de 381,287 personas que viven con discapacidades asumiendo una población de 8.2 millones.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: How the Disability Community in Honduras Uses Digital Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies on how many disabled people live in Honduras are scarce. Results of a survey by the National Statistics Institute (INE), carried out in September 2002, showed there are 177,516 people with disabilities in the country. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;Academic studies&lt;/a&gt; tell a different story. They estimate that the number of people in Honduras with disabilities is closer to 381,287. These differing reports prevent the government, institutions, and civil society from effectively thinking through how ensure that services are accessible to those with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/TLC%20pic%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building Digital Medical Records for Floating Villages in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you digitize medical records in Cambodia when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5DRZBiE6BTE&quot;&gt;your clinics are on a lake&lt;/a&gt;, have minimal internet connectivity, and are four hours away from the nearest big city? Impossible, you say? Not quite. Let me introduce you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lakeclinic.org/&quot;&gt;the Lake Clinic&lt;/a&gt; (TLC), a health clinic working to solve this complex challenge with the support of the six-year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org&quot;&gt;Development Innovations (DI)&lt;/a&gt; project, funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/setha-rath/">Setha Rath</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/case-study-from-cambodia-customizing-an-electronic-medical-records-system-for-floating-villages-in-tonle-sap-lake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/case-study-from-cambodia-customizing-an-electronic-medical-records-system-for-floating-villages-in-tonle-sap-lake.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/artificial-intelligence-3382507_640.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Making Sure Data Science For Good Does Good</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week at the 74th U.N. General Assembly, the Rockefeller Foundation announced a $100 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockefellerfoundation.org/about-us/news-media/using-data-save-lives-rockefeller-foundation-partners-launch-100-million-precision-public-health-initiative/&quot;&gt;Precision Public Health initiative&lt;/a&gt; to integrate data analytics and data science tools such as machine learning into the community health systems of low- and middle-income countries. During the announcement, Rockefeller noted the significant impact of data science innovations in the most privileged communities, explaining its hope to replicate this effect to improve healthcare for people globally. The initiative aims to save at least 6 million women and children’s lives by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/making-sure-data-science-for-good-does-good.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/making-sure-data-science-for-good-does-good.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/phone%20image%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development for Newbies, Part 1: The Basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) several months ago as an international development professional: familiar with ADS 302, Geo Code 937, Form AID 1420-17, among other industry acronyms, but a newcomer to the language of tech trends, digital buzzwords, and product design. I found the CDA team to be both inspiring and daunting, boasting individuals with unique expertise and passions—whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=cyber-security-series&quot;&gt;cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=human-centered-design&quot;&gt;human-centered design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=remote-sensing-series&quot;&gt;remote sensing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=blockchain-serieshttps://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=blockchain-series&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/what-good-is-the-internet-of-things-to-people-who-dont-have-internet.html&quot;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;. As a neophyte, it’s easy to be overwhelmed by what you don’t know in the seemingly limitless world of digital technology but I’m here to help! If you, too, are new to this sphere, what do you need to know to integrate digital tools into your development programs or proposals? Below are some key points to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Addie Ryan
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-1-the-basics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-1-the-basics.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ActivityKenya.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Applying the Principles for Digital Development in a Flourishing Digital Ecosystem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a co-facilitator at a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/what-we-do/agriculture-and-food-security/increasing-food-security-through-feed-future&quot;&gt;Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt; training on digital development for resilience and food security in Nairobi, I was struck by the stark contrast between the short amount of time (a scant four years) I’ve been settling debts with friends on Venmo and the participants’ resounding “we’ve been using it forever” response when I asked how long they had been using Kenya’s mobile payment system, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital.hbs.edu/platform-rctom/submission/m-pesa-transforming-kenya-with-mobile-money/&quot;&gt;M-Pesa&lt;/a&gt;. While I can imagine a world without Venmo, it is clear that, for many Kenyans, life without M-Pesa is inconceivable.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/applying-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-a-flourishing-digital-ecosystem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/applying-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-a-flourishing-digital-ecosystem.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
