<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:56:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:56:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Chatbots for the International Development and Humanitarian Sectors: What Works?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed chatbots becoming more commonplace in your life. Buying yourself a new sound system online? A chatbot pops up offering help. Need to confirm flight details? The airline’s chatbot can do that for you. Chatbots can offer a quick and easy way to get the information you need on the platform you are already using, whether that be a website, Facebook Messenger, or WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they operate with low bandwidth and are simple to use, chatbots seem like they could be a beneficial technology to engage with recipients of our development and humanitarian programs, don’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any technology, the use of chatbots is migrating from the private sector and becoming more prevalent in crisis and conflict response. However, documentation of lessons learned, successes and failures, and best practices of the use of chatbots in the development and humanitarian sectors are still few and far between. Through our work with Sesame Workshop, DAI conducted desk research and key informant interviews to examine use cases and review lessons learned for the use of chatbots in the international development and humanitarian sectors. In this blog, we summarize our key findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1-dc4d49.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture1-dc4d49.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image: Pixabay/Mohamed Hassan.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Carrington
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/chatbots-for-the-international-development-and-humanitarian-sectors-what-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/chatbots-for-the-international-development-and-humanitarian-sectors-what-works.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/system-g3f0828b60_640.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Look Into the Future: Rwanda’s Road to Digital Transformation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, my family was visiting me in Rwanda. We were traveling two hours outside of the capital, in a rural, forested area, on what seemed to be the only straight patch of road in the mountainous country. As we were admiring the landscape, in my rearview mirror, I saw a flash. I knew she got me. Sophia—one of Rwanda’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ktpress.rw/2021/11/rwanda-police-drivers-in-traffic-fines-controversy/&quot;&gt;notorious traffic cameras&lt;/a&gt; (jokingly called “Sophia” by Rwandans and named after a humanoid robot that spoke at the Transform Africa Summit in 2019) cruelly captured me going over the speed limit. Within 15 minutes, I received a speeding ticket via text message. I quickly paid the fine through Rwanda’s mobile money app, MoMo, and we continued our trip. Despite the ticket, I had to marvel at the technology that underpinned the entire exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 08:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Ben Harguth
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/rwandas-road-to-digital-transformation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/rwandas-road-to-digital-transformation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/solen-feyissa-3aLMXGvH4GA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Rewind: The Rise of TikTok—How One App is Making Waves in the Global Development Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recently, I’ve been thinking about how the organizational shifts at Twitter will affect TikTok. With Tesla CEO Elon Musk now owning one of the world’s most high-profile information systems, there are bound to be changes in user satisfaction. While TikTok and Twitter have different features and purposes, a few questions have popped up for me. Will we see more users flocking to TikTok due to Musk’s acquisition (or vice versa)? Will TikTok’s brand, ownership, or features change to compete with Twitter’s upcoming changes? Will communities find new ways to organize and communicate beyond both apps? Is it a matter of time before a more unique, more innovative platform rides the wave (and hopefully, betters all of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://oakparktalon.org/15364/opinion/tiktok-is-shortening-our-attention-spans/&quot;&gt;attention spans&lt;/a&gt;)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While I don’t have the answers to any of these questions, I do have the answer to one question: Is TikTok really that influential?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Afua Owusu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/arno-senoner-42t-DKecmPk-unsplash%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>In Case You Missed It—Discussing the Impact and Implications of AI on Digital Inclusion at the NetHope Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration hosted a panel discussion during the NetHope Global Summit featuring artificial intelligence (AI) experts representing the public, private, and civil society sectors to discuss practical uses for facial recognition technology (FRT) and its impact on digital inclusion. The panelists presented specific case studies where they have seen their work intersect with AI and facial recognition technologies and digital inclusion, providing lessons learned for attendees to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 05:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/gratiana-fu/">Gratiana Fu</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/nancy-haugh/">Nancy Haugh</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/in-case-you-missed-it-discussing-the-impact-and-implications-of-ai-on-digital-inclusion-at-the-nethope-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/in-case-you-missed-it-discussing-the-impact-and-implications-of-ai-on-digital-inclusion-at-the-nethope-conference.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GettyImages-1379895972.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Potential Value of AI—and How Governments Could Capture It, Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-and-social-sector/our-insights/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-look-to-capture-it&quot;&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Company&lt;/a&gt; website. Read Part 1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 14:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/niklas-berglind-92571231/?originalSubdomain=se">Niklas Berglind</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankit-fadia/">Ankit Fadia</a> and <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/our-people/tom-isherwood">Tom Isherwood</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it-part-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aman-pal-15r9RAOy38Q-unsplash-912957.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Headlining, Part 2: How Misinformation Could Impact Development Programming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/headlining-part-1-spreading-misinformation.html&quot;&gt;Headlining, Part I: Spreading Misinformation&lt;/a&gt;, which defines “headlining” as a form of misinformation that uses a sensational headline to uncritically pass along false information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also offered tips and tricks to avoid falling victim to headlining, like taking a moment to pause and ask yourself, “Does this sound too good or too awful to be true?” and actually reading a news article before you share it. Now I want to take headlining and situate it directly in the contexts and communities in which international development practitioners work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aman-pal-15r9RAOy38Q-unsplash-48d28a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;aman-pal-15r9RAOy38Q-unsplash-48d28a.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Aman Pal/Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Nancy Haugh
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/headlining-part-2-how-misinformation-could-be-impacting-your-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/headlining-part-2-how-misinformation-could-be-impacting-your-projects.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Misinformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GettyImages-1379895972.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Potential Value of AI—and How Governments Could Capture It, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-and-social-sector/our-insights/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-look-to-capture-it&quot;&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Company&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) could have a significant impact on individuals, businesses, and governments. Here is what countries need to know about its benefits—and the first steps toward realizing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long-term potential of AI to change key aspects of the way we live and to support the operations of businesses, governments, and other organizations is hard to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, AI has contributed to improvements in quality of life for all segments of society through innovations such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/healthcare-systems-and-services/our-insights/transforming-healthcare-with-ai&quot;&gt;predictive healthcare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/education/our-insights/how-artificial-intelligence-will-impact-k-12-teachers&quot;&gt;adaptive education&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/artificial-intelligence/applying-artificial-intelligence-for-social-good&quot;&gt;optimized crisis response&lt;/a&gt;. The National Health Service in the United Kingdom, for instance, set up a National COVID-19 Chest Imaging Database containing a shared library of chest X-rays, computerized tomography (CT) scans, and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) images to support the testing and development of AI technologies to treat COVID-19 and a variety of other health conditions. Businesses have seen increased productivity and operational efficiency using autonomous robotics in manufacturing, AI-optimized supply chains, and intelligent cargo routing with autonomous vehicles, among other initiatives. For example, many logistics companies are using AI-powered sorting robots to optimize their warehouse operations. Governments can also harness the power of AI through personalized services and automated processes. Consider Singapore’s “Ask Jamie,” a virtual assistant that helps citizens and businesses navigate government services across roughly 70 government agencies through AI-powered chat and voice.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 08:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/niklas-berglind-92571231/?originalSubdomain=se">Niklas Berglind</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankit-fadia/">Ankit Fadia</a> and <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/our-people/tom-isherwood">Tom Isherwood</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/guerrillabuzz-crypto-pr-T9rKvI3N0NM-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital @ DAI Rewind: Is Intellectual Property Ready for Blockchain?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re an avid reader of the Digital@DAI blog, then by now you’ve surely heard of blockchain technology. For those in need of a refresher, blockchain is a decentralized database system that records information in a way that makes it near-to-impossible to change, breach, or cheat the system. International donors and the private sector have deployed blockchain towards furthering financial inclusion, digital government, and improved supply chain management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More recently, governments and the private sector are exploring how this technology can be applied toward the building of secure and data-preserving e-governance systems. Governments across the &lt;a href=&quot;https://irishtechnews.ie/global-blockchain-adoption-which-countries-are-leading-the-charge/&quot;&gt;globe&lt;/a&gt;, such as in Chile, Estonia, Singapore, Uzbekistan, and Venezuela, to name a few, are using blockchain and other emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, the Internet of Things and smart contracts to build digital governance systems. An exciting feature of blockchain is that it can support the creative industry by serving as intellectual property rights register and enforcement tool. For instance, the European Union Intellectual Property (IP) Office, in collaboration with participating offices, launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scintilla-ip.com/blockchain-ip-register-at-the-euipo/&quot;&gt;Blockchain IP register&lt;/a&gt;, which has the ability to automatically store data about registered IP rights in various IP offices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As blockchain is a versatile technology that impacts many sectors from cryptocurrency to creative industries and IP management, it is crucial that the digital development sector stays abreast of blockchain’s impact on digital transformation. This week, we will revisit a post from 2021 from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/miriam-stankovich&quot;&gt;Dr. Miriam Stankovich&lt;/a&gt; about blockchain’s applicability to patents, copyrights, trademarks, and industrial designs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 07:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-rewind-is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-rewind-is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Blockchain Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/dan-cristian-padure-BxgVEo_rF-o-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Rewind: Right to Repair is a Development Issue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.repair.org/stand-up&quot;&gt;Right to Repair&lt;/a&gt;” is a concept and advocacy movement centered around the idea that anyone who owns a device, machinery, or piece of equipment should have the right to repair it themselves or take it to a repair person or shop of their choosing. While this has been a subject in tech news for the last several years, the concept is back in the spotlight. Last week, Apple unveiled its new, more repairable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/09/19/apple-iphone-14-easiest-to-fix-since-2016-ifixit.html&quot;&gt;iPhone 14&lt;/a&gt; and in June, the New York state legislature &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/3/23153504/right-to-repair-new-york-state-law-ifixit-repairability-diy&quot;&gt;passed&lt;/a&gt; the United States’ first Right to Repair bill. With the movement picking up steam, we are reminded that there are linkages to our work in digital development. This week, we will revisit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html&quot;&gt;2021 post&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/robert-ryan-silva&quot;&gt;Rob Ryan-Silva&lt;/a&gt;, Director of DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/dai-maker-lab&quot;&gt;Maker Lab&lt;/a&gt;, about why this movement is an issue the development community needs to care about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 07:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ukraine%20cross%20post.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Starting Now on Digital Transformation for Ukraine Reconstruction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictworks.org/digital-transformation-ukraine-reconstruction/&quot;&gt;ICTworks blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the war in Ukraine comes to an end (hopefully with Ukraine having recovered all of its territories, including Crimea), Western countries are likely to provide a massive aid package to help rebuild Ukrainian infrastructure, buildings, and lives. This moment in history will offer an opportunity for Ukraine to engage in rapid digital transformation. We should already begin deploying digital tools that will help Ukraine as it continues to fight bravely against the invaders, with the intention of seeing the country emerge from war on the right foot for a quick recovery. As President Volodymyr Zelenskyy himself &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anews.com.tr/world/2022/07/03/zelensky-calls-for-international-assistance-to-rebuild-ukraine&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the post-war reconstruction should use the moment to build “a new foundation for our lives: … accessible new technologies, best practices, new institutions and, of course, reforms.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 12:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/troyetulain/">Troy Etulain</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/starting-now-on-digital-transformation-for-ukraine-reconstruction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/starting-now-on-digital-transformation-for-ukraine-reconstruction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Government</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
