<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:59:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:59:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Capture-a98d9f.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Top 3 Considerations for eLearning Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has caused major disruptions for people from all walks of life. It has dramatically changed the nature of activities we used to do in person, especially those aiming to bring people together to learn, exchange knowledge, and strengthen relationships. As we grapple with the uncertainty of how in-person education and training will continue as the pandemic evolves, many types of learning experiences have preemptively moved online, especially those for adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Center for Digital Acceleration, we see significant opportunities for creative digital collaboration that would have been impossible just a year ago. Electronic learning has emerged as a particularly interesting category for development solutions. Projects with goals that span the thematic spectrum—from strengthening agricultural supply chains to supporting rule of law to stemming climate change—are considering how to implement digital curricula and thinking carefully about what approaches could work best for their myriad stakeholder groups.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/annehand/">Anne Hand</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandrosolis/">Alejandro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/top-three-considerations-for-elearning-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/top-three-considerations-for-elearning-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>elearning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/alex%20blog%201%20image%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Western Nations Seek to Bulk Up Critical Infrastructure, Digitalization, and Cybersecurity in the Western Balkans</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Western Balkans, like many regions across the world, is navigating the disruptive effects of COVID-19 on their economies, while also digitalizing numerous critical sectors. Critical infrastructure (CI) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/topic/critical-infrastructure-security&quot;&gt;defined&lt;/a&gt; as “the physical and cyber systems and assets that are so vital to [a country] that their incapacity or destruction would have a debilitating impact on physical or economic security or public health or safety.” Recent threats emanating from malicious individual and nation-state actors remind us that cybersecurity considerations are vital to mitigate potentially widespread and devastating effects. In fact, the need to focus on network and system securities is only accelerated with the unique nature of digital challenges brought on by the COVID-19 pandemic in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Alexander Sekhniashvili
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/impact-of-the-us-and-eu-in-critical-infrastructure-digitalization-and-cybersecurity-in-the-western-balkans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/impact-of-the-us-and-eu-in-critical-infrastructure-digitalization-and-cybersecurity-in-the-western-balkans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Critical Infrastructure</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/intablognew.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: The View from Latvia’s Startup Scene with TrueSix’s Julia Gifford</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/1870/J2SR_Fact_Sheet_June_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;Journey to Self-Reliance&lt;/a&gt; has been covered extensively by the press, think tanks, academia, and implementers since its 2018 launch (more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=usaid\+journey\+to\+self\+reliance&amp;amp;rlz=1C1GCEA_enUS877US877&amp;amp;oq=usaid\+journey&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j69i57j0j69i59j69i60l2.1337j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;390,000 Google search results&lt;/a&gt; and counting), not much has been written about the countries that have actually graduated from assistance. Latvia—a small country of two million people wedged between Russia and the Baltic Sea—was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/1863/EE_20Year_Review.pdf&quot;&gt;one of 11&lt;/a&gt; central, eastern, and southeastern European states to graduate in the 1990s or early 2000s. After $57 million over &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdf.usaid.gov/pdf_docs/PDACI589.pdf&quot;&gt;eight years of USAID support&lt;/a&gt; ending in 1999, what’s going on in Latvia now? Specifically, what’s going on in Latvia’s startup scene and in the digital realm? Quite a bit, as it turns out—from &lt;a href=&quot;https://catchbox.com/&quot;&gt;throwable microphones&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lokalise.com/&quot;&gt;localization and translation management platforms&lt;/a&gt; to one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-tech-latvia-idUSKBN23118I&quot;&gt;world’s first COVID-19 contact tracing apps&lt;/a&gt; using the Apple/Google application programming interfaces (APIs). I sat down with my friend of 25 years, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/julijagifford?lang=en&quot;&gt;Julia Gifford&lt;/a&gt;, Canadian-Latvian startup advocate and founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://truesix.co/&quot;&gt;TrueSix&lt;/a&gt;—a Latvian content marketing firm that helps brands get noticed in the U.S. market with strategic content, copy, and advertising—to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-the-view-from-latvias-start-up-scene-with-truesixs-julia-gifford.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-innovator-series-the-view-from-latvias-start-up-scene-with-truesixs-julia-gifford.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/HOT%20Peru%20Photo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How to Protect Digital Privacy and Security During COVID-19 Response</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What do cyber attacks, virtual learning platforms, and the spread of misinformation online have in common?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All have seen substantial spikes over the past four months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each one would be nonexistent without digital technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology has served as both an advantage and a hindrance during &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictworks.org/tag/covid-19-response/&quot;&gt;COVID-19 digital response&lt;/a&gt;. On one hand, apps like Zoom have allowed people to stay connected with loved ones while safe at home, and many have been able to work remotely without major disruption to their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/janesarahclifford/">Jane Clifford</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-protect-digital-privacy-and-security-during-covid-19-response.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-protect-digital-privacy-and-security-during-covid-19-response.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-10-15%20at%209.06.53%20AM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cybersecurity Frontier Insights Findings: User Perceptions of Trust and Privacy on the Internet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last week we shared that the Center for Digital Acceleration was launching our most recent Cybersecurity Frontier Insights research into user perceptions of trust and privacy in India and Ghana. Here are the findings from that report, which can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/fi-cyber-user-trust.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the creation of the internet more than 30 years ago, our lives, economies, and societies have changed dramatically and the restrictions of the COVID-19 pandemic have accelerated change even more. As we’ve developed seemingly endless new methods of online communication, commerce, and civic participation, the international development community has become more acutely aware of a growing digital divide: those who are poor, rural, remote, illiterate, female, or living with disabilities in emerging markets risk being excluded from the benefits of digital transformation. Therefore, especially in recent years and months, we’ve seen valiant efforts from governments, private companies, and the development community to bridge digital gaps aiming to enable more people to access and benefit from online services. However, as access and use has increased, so has the number of digital risks, with data breaches, fraud, surveillance, and cybercrime on the rise globally.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 06:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Julia Burchell
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-frontier-insights-findings-user-perceptions-of-trust-and-privacy-on-the-internet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-frontier-insights-findings-user-perceptions-of-trust-and-privacy-on-the-internet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Trust</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/EricaBblog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How to Use Digital Payments During the COVID-19 Response</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The pandemic is affecting the way people interact with money; how much we spend, what we buy, and whether to opt for digital payments. In the United States, the switch to digital has even led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/29/business/coin-shortage-penny.html&quot;&gt;coin shortage&lt;/a&gt;, and the rest of the world is more reliant on cashless options, too.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/erica-bustinza-418191b2/">Erica Bustinza</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-use-digital-payments-during-covid-19-response.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-use-digital-payments-during-covid-19-response.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202020-10-15%20at%209.06.53%20AM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Research Launch: User Perceptions of Trust and Privacy on the Internet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration cordially invites you to an online event on findings from our latest Cybersecurity Frontier Insights research into user perceptions of trust and privacy in India and Ghana. We’ll be discussing these findings with a diverse panel of distinguished speakers from A4AI, USAID, FCDO, GSMA, and the Ghana Chamber of Telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 06:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/youre-invited-research-launch-user-perceptions-of-trust-and-privacy-on-the-internet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/youre-invited-research-launch-user-perceptions-of-trust-and-privacy-on-the-internet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Trust</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/trevorblogpic.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Understanding Data Tracking: Tips, Tricks, and Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it will ever be possible to overstate the importance of data privacy. I also don’t think it will be possible to overstate the necessity of digital literacy. And unfortunately, I don’t think it will ever be possible to completely protect our online selves from data harvesting or tracking. However, there are measures we can take to keep our data where it belongs. These measures can be taken by anyone using a phone with access to the internet and help keep us from being tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/online-tracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/online-tracking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Tracking</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/TZ-Mugumu-Neptune-Day1-_31_8027.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Launch of Two W-GDP WomenConnect Challenges: Apply Now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers project&lt;/a&gt; has just launched a call for proposals for two challenges under the White House-led Women’s Global Development and Prosperity (W-GDP) Initiative’s WomenConnect Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WomenConnect Challenge was first launched by Advisor Ivanka Trump and U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Administrator Mark Green on International Women’s Day in 2018. Since then, USAID awarded nine grantees that are working to address barriers limiting women’s access to technology and to connect nearly 1 million women in 12 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 06:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/launch-of-two-w-gdp-womenconnect-challenges-apply-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/launch-of-two-w-gdp-womenconnect-challenges-apply-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/16697496505_648084a306_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How to Responsibly Invest in Digital Development During COVID-19 Response</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has shifted the world to increasingly rely on digital technology to survive. Children are using online platforms to learn. People are using digital payment software to send money to their loved ones, and local businesses are entering the digital space to deliver goods and services that are no longer offered in person.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 06:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rashel-rabinovich-b3469099?challengeId=AQEy5wdzmx-JvQAAAXTgVbP65l_jvqz9qhAPg2VLEh-mJiptq7ldu-geOmVCajVP-AEG4JeFys-mWPPY_42oRnAtXG1ro7U5CA&amp;submissionId=280315a5-13a4-3916-95b1-5178d9f80479">Rashel Rabinovich</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-responsibly-invest-in-digital-development-during-covid-19-response.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-responsibly-invest-in-digital-development-during-covid-19-response.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
