<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 09:45:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 09:45:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Pulse_oximeter_sensor.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Racist Hardware and What to Do About It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMc2029240&quot;&gt;an astonishing letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor published in the December 17, 2020, edition of the &lt;em&gt;New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/em&gt; (NEJM), a group of five doctors from the University of Michigan Medical School presented findings from their study on adult inpatients receiving supplemental oxygen at the University’s hospital. They found that the variance between blood oxygen levels measured through a pulse oximeter—an optical device that estimates blood oxygen by analyzing the light absorbed in an extremity, usually a finger—and more rigorous (and invasive) analyses of arterial blood gas differed substantially depending on whether the patient was Black or white. Moreover, Black patients tended to get more optimistic readings from the oximeter. Such inaccuracies could quite possibly lead to worse clinical outcomes and could be particularly detrimental when treating COVID-19 as careful monitoring of patients’ blood oxygen levels can trigger lifesaving medical care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against the backdrop of the ongoing global conversation about racism and bias, one might ask whether the pulse oximeters in this study are racist. Can a piece of hardware even be racist?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/racist-hardware-and-what-to-do-about-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/racist-hardware-and-what-to-do-about-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        <category>Makerspace</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2021.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we (happily) say farewell to 2020, we at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) feel stronger and more optimistic than ever before. If 2020 taught us anything, it is that adaptation is paramount. The events of the last year have changed almost every aspect of how we think, work, and live, and we would be naïve to think that our digital toolkit won’t change right along with us. Therefore, heading into 2021, we have high ambitions to continue to analyze and elevate inclusive, ethical, human-focused digital products and services that can help us rise to the occasion and address some of the deeply complex issues that 2020 unveiled. Below are seven areas we look forward to exploring further throughout the year—so stay tuned and check back often.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Year%20in%20Review.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI 2020 Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has been a year like no other. While those of us in the development sector have long anticipated the increased frequency of once-in-a-lifetime events—as our social, environmental, political, and economic systems grow increasingly strained and interconnected—none of us expected these “problems of tomorrow” to arise as quickly, globally, and devastatingly as they did.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-2020-year-in-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-2020-year-in-review.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202020-12-22%20105419.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Addressing Concurrent Crises with Digital Tools: An ICTforAg Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back on 2020, it is still difficult for me to comprehend the many challenges the world faced this year and their implications for agriculture and resilience. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20200806-the-biblical-east-african-locust-plagues-of-2020&quot;&gt;locust outbreak in East Africa&lt;/a&gt;, to wildfires and extreme weather events, and of course, the COVID-19 pandemic, this year has made it clear that in a world increasingly shaped by unpredictability, the digital development community can no longer afford to address one specific challenge at a time. This year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictforag.com/&quot;&gt;ICTforAg&lt;/a&gt; conference invited its speakers and participants to reflect on this reality and discover how digital tools and technologies can help us respond to concurrent—and increasingly frequent—crises worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/addressing-concurrent-crises-with-digital-tools-an-ictforag-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/addressing-concurrent-crises-with-digital-tools-an-ictforag-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Resilience</category>
        
        <category>Digital Collaboration</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Capture-9dbe6c.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Vision for Smart Connectivity in the Three Seas Region</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, we have been struck by one of the few upsides of this new way of working—the ability to bring together experts and thinkers virtually in ways that contribute to a more global conversation. This was the case recently when DAI spoke at the Three Seas Initiative with leaders and experts from across Europe and beyond about the concept of ‘Smart Connectivity.’&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/margusmagi/">Margus Magi</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/glomazic/">Rade Glomazic</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-vision-for-smart-connectivity-in-the-three-seas-region.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-vision-for-smart-connectivity-in-the-three-seas-region.html</guid>
        
        <category>Environment &amp; Energy</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hacker-1944688_1280.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID’s DRG Center in Addressing Electoral Cybersecurity Threats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The increasingly widespread use of technology in the electoral process in countries around the world creates significant cybersecurity risks, ranging from simple hacks to sophisticated exploitation of hardware or software vulnerabilities. Governments, election management bodies (EMBs), candidates, and parties are often ill-equipped to prepare for and respond to cybersecurity attacks and key decision makers may not understand the gravity of the risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USAID’s Democracy, Human Rights, and Governance (DRG) Center views electoral processes as pivotal to a country’s stability and aims to strengthen technical knowledge on addressing electoral cybersecurity threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers &lt;/a&gt;releases a request for proposals (RFP) to experienced organizations, firms, or individuals to develop and convene expert briefings and presentations for USAID DRG staff on cybersecurity in elections, including risks, threats, and mitigation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Andrea Falso
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaids-drg-center-in-addressing-electoral-cybersecurity-threats.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaids-drg-center-in-addressing-electoral-cybersecurity-threats.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/HSNP%20payment%20staff%20assisting%20elderly%20beneficiaries%20fill%20in%20Bank%20Account%20opening%20forms%20at%20Qilta%20Marsabit.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Consent to Data Processing in Humanitarian and Development Contexts, Part 1: Who, What, When, and How</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 and early 2020, DAI and our partner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cariboudigital.net/&quot;&gt;Caribou Digital,&lt;/a&gt; worked closely with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-development-office&quot;&gt;U.K. Foreign, Commonwealth &amp;amp; Development Office&lt;/a&gt; to analyse identification and registration systems in protracted and recurrent crises. For those interested in reading more about the research, the report can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/bsic-MIS-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post—the first of a two-part series—we dig into some of the issues around consent and other legal bases for data processing in humanitarian and development contexts identified in our research. For other blogs about our research, see our comments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-interoperability.html&quot;&gt;interoperability&lt;/a&gt; and the risks and benefits of management information systems at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-part-2-risks-and-benefits.html&quot;&gt;humanitarian-social protection nexus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chloemessenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachaelsteller/">Rachael Steller</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/consent-to-data-processing-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts-part-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/consent-to-data-processing-in-humanitarian-and-development-contexts-part-one.html</guid>
        
        <category>Consent</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>Interoperability</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/AI%202%20copy%20(002).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Reflections on Machine Learning for Gender Inclusion in Afghanistan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past summer, DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/afghanistan-women-in-the-economy&quot;&gt;Promote: Women in the Economy (WIE)&lt;/a&gt; project came to an end. Funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development, the project bolstered women’s inclusion in Afghanistan’s economy through technical assistance, access to finance, and business training. In 2016, our team &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-will-help-development-projects-achieve-scale.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about the possibility of leveraging machine learning to “automate the alignment of unstructured CVs and resumes with available jobs, thereby facilitating the Afghan women’s access to employment opportunities.” Four years later, this use case for machine learning is one of our favorite examples. We reflect on five lessons from this initiative, and how we can translate its success into future endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-machine-learning-for-gender-inclusion-in-afghanistan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-machine-learning-for-gender-inclusion-in-afghanistan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Afghanistan</category>
        
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Budapest%20Convention_resized.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Considerations for a Successful ICT Strategy in Local Context: Lessons from Timor-Leste</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those with access to technology in various parts of the world use it in similar ways. In places as distant as Chile, Vietnam, and Norway, people use e-commerce platforms for buying and selling goods, emailing each other, and e-calendars for business schedules, and social media platforms for sharing news, communicating, and organizing. Despite these crosscutting uses of technology and often the ubiquity of the platforms themselves (Facebook is the world’s most popular social media site, with 2.6 billion monthly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/268136/top-15-countries-based-on-number-of-facebook-users/&quot;&gt;active users&lt;/a&gt;), the context in which these technologies exist matter greatly for how that technology is governed and understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology strategies and policies must be tailored to the local context so that a country can successfully promote the use of technology for growth and prosperity while governing its use to protect citizens and national security. This approach aligns closely with the first two &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/principles/&quot;&gt;Principles for Digital Development,&lt;/a&gt; which are &lt;strong&gt;1) Design with the user&lt;/strong&gt;—using conversation, observation, and co-creation to create a product or initiative that is truly beneficial and appropriate and &lt;strong&gt;2) Understand the existing ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;—considering the particular structures and needs that exist in each country, region, and community.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/considerations-for-a-successful-ict-strategy-in-local-context-lessons-from-timor-leste.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/considerations-for-a-successful-ict-strategy-in-local-context-lessons-from-timor-leste.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Asia and the Pacific</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/JB%203.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Eliminating Cyber Violence Against Women and Girls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the United Nations’ International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women. Like every year on this day–and any other official “Day” that amplifies the inequalities between women and men–I’m heaving a big sigh… because we’re still here. We still require these Days. We continue to need reminding that women are &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; fighting for equality all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These thoughts can get me down, but today, I’m pulling up my positive socks. Observing these Days provides an opportunity to celebrate the progress societies have made in closing gender gaps and can galvanise us to acknowledge the work still left to do. If days like today inspire us to take positive action to shape a better world for women and men, then that is all to the good.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 07:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Julia Burchell
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/eliminating-cyber-violence-against-women-and-girls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/eliminating-cyber-violence-against-women-and-girls.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
