<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 15:52:40 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 15:52:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1-be05cb.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Path to a Sustained Network for Women Entrepreneurs in South Asia: Insights from the SARDI Strengthening Women in Tech Symposium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you take your chai or coffee? These opening words welcomed participants from all around the world for the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) Strengthening Symposium, a series of conversations about the most pressing barriers to investment in women-owned enterprises. Covering tremendous ground in 10 hours over four days, this virtual event connected finalists for potential partnerships, inspired applicants by clearly articulating the goals of the activity, and strengthened phase two applications in the process for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-strengthening-women-in-tech-in-south-asia.html&quot;&gt;Strengthening Women in Tech in South Asia&lt;/a&gt; Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SARDI initiative, implemented under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP),&lt;/a&gt;aims to address barriers for women entrepreneurs seeking to expand their business by connecting women across the region for peer-learning opportunities, providing mentorship, investment, and capacity-building support, and building awareness around the ICT policy environment that governs their businesses. The finalists participating in the symposium, ranging from large international organizations to consortia made up of local accelerators and industry associations, are in the running to ultimately design and implement this important regional network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SARDI designed the symposium to bring together the best and brightest, selecting the top 10 out of more than 40 applicants.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christincoster/">Christiy Coster</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-path-to-a-sustained-network-for-women-entrepreneurs-in-south-asia-insights-from-the-sardi-strengthening-women-in-tech-symposium.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-path-to-a-sustained-network-for-women-entrepreneurs-in-south-asia-insights-from-the-sardi-strengthening-women-in-tech-symposium.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%201%20EAI.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 1 — Changing Social Norms and Cultural Perceptions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge(WCC)&lt;/a&gt; is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It can lead to stealing. Or promiscuous activities, drug abuse, rudeness, stubbornness, lies… 90 percent of the causes of immorality, bad behavior, attitudes of urban women are related to the internet.” This was one man’s justification for restricting his female family members from using the internet and mobile phones. “The internet will destroy their good upbringing and morality,” declared another young man. “We feel that the phone is a simple way to destroy a woman’s morality and alter her thoughts,” agreed yet another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When WCC grantee&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equalaccess.org/our-work/projects/closing-the-gender-digital-divide-tech4families/&quot;&gt; Equal Access International (EAI)&lt;/a&gt; began its #Tech4Families program in northern Nigeria, baseline interviews were rife with this idea that women’s use of the internet and digital technologies would lead to their moral decline. At the baseline, 80 percent of men and boys interviewed did not believe the internet could be beneficial for women and girls, citing women’s use of digital technologies as immoral, inappropriate, or unnecessary. Many female interviewees echoed the sentiments of their male counterparts, perhaps having internalized the negative gender norms or fearing community backlash.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 11:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-1-changing-social-norms-and-cultural-perceptions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-1-changing-social-norms-and-cultural-perceptions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/InnovationBus2.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Innovator Series: Discussing Entrepreneurship Ecosystems with Paing Hein Htet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paing Hein Htet is a startup enthusiast and ecosystem builder from Myanmar. Paing has been working with innovators and startups across Myanmar for eight years, first by running fashion commerce and artificial intelligence startups, then through work in digital service design, and now as an investor. We recently spoke to Paing on strengthening digital ecosystems, the current state of entrepreneurial communities in Southeast Asia, and much more. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kate-heuisler-1745326/?originalSubdomain=kh">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/strengthening-digital-ecosystems-with-paing-hein-htet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/strengthening-digital-ecosystems-with-paing-hein-htet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Innovator Series</category>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/msme-study-thumbnail-global.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Global Insights from a Major New Study on MSME Digital Tool Use in Emerging Markets Amidst the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic caused an unprecedented economic slowdown that had an outsized, adverse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intracen.org/uploadedFiles/intracenorg/Content/Publications/ITCSMECO2020.pdf&quot;&gt;impact&lt;/a&gt; on micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) across the globe. As the world begins to reckon with the ‘new normal’ and countries take steps toward economic stabilization, it is clear that MSMEs—which account for two-thirds of employment globally and 80 to 90 percent of employment in &lt;a href=&quot;https://unctad.org/news/supporting-small-businesses-critical-covid-19-recovery&quot;&gt;low-income countries&lt;/a&gt;—will play an essential role in strengthening pandemic recovery efforts as they fuel economic growth and spur &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/content/documents/25851MSMEs_and_SDGs_Final3120.pdf&quot;&gt;job creation&lt;/a&gt; in emerging markets. The pandemic also revealed the vital role digital technologies play in enabling businesses, communities, and individuals to connect, function, and thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/global-insights-from-a-major-new-study-on-msme-digital-tool-use-in-emerging-markets-amidst-the-covid-19-pandemic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/global-insights-from-a-major-new-study-on-msme-digital-tool-use-in-emerging-markets-amidst-the-covid-19-pandemic.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/nastya-dulhiier-OKOOGO578eo-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Rise in Internet Shutdowns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, a snowstorm knocked out the internet connection at my apartment. While I could still communicate with others from my cellphone and use 4G to check Twitter for outage updates, the temporary inconvenience highlighted how dependent my life is on reliable internet access and how vulnerable our day-to-day lives are when that access is unexpectedly taken away. For many individuals, especially those in countries with authoritarian governments, unanticipated internet shutdowns have become increasingly common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trtworld.com/magazine/explained-how-do-internet-shutdowns-work-44212&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/a&gt; for an internet shutdown is when a government or nonstate actor intentionally disrupts access to the internet or certain platforms for a specific population or entire location to exert control over information. In 2020, Access Now’s Shutdown Tracker Optimization Project collected &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/keepiton/&quot;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; on 155 reported instances of an internet shutdown, a significant increase from the 56 reported instances in 2016. As internet access has become more ingrained in a society’s ability to communicate, organize, and function, political leaders have increasingly leveraged their control of this resource to stifle dissent and reassert control.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 17:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connor-mackenzie/">Connor Mackenzie</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-in-internet-shutdowns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-in-internet-shutdowns.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Repression</category>
        
        <category>digital justice</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1579368606627.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Shaping History Series: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation—Dr. Joy Buolamwini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aligned with the Center for Digital Acceleration’s commitment to fostering equity and inclusion within our team and the broader international development sector, Digital@DAI is launching a new series during Black History Month called Shaping History: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation. The series aims to spotlight racially diverse leaders in the tech space at home and in the countries where we work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, meet our first profile subject: Dr. Joy Buolamwini.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 08:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-dr-joy-buolamwini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-dr-joy-buolamwini.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Shaping History Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Security.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: SARDI MSME Cybersecurity Awareness Campaign Design and Implementation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) activity is seeking applications from organizations interested in conducting an awareness campaign for micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) in Bangladesh to help them improve their personal and business digital hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Security.png&quot; alt=&quot;Security.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Pixelcreatures, Pixabay.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 20:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermetkabylova/?originalSubdomain=kg">Bermet Kabylova</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-cybersecurity-awareness-campaign-design-and-implementation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-cybersecurity-awareness-campaign-design-and-implementation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/20181023_2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Help Assess Guatemala’s Digital Financial Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; seeks applications from firms to assess market conditions and identify gaps and opportunities in the use of financial services in Guatemala among low-income and marginalized populations, particularly women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-income and marginalized populations, especially women, are more susceptible to shocks, whether economic, climate, or other, leading them to fall into poverty and sometimes migrate within or outside of their country. Often, individuals lack digital and financial literacy and skills, which prevents them from using financial services to help them better deal with shocks and build their resilience and incomes. This activity will better assess demand and supply-side market conditions to understand Guatemalan customer segments’ financial needs better. The partner will also develop a new or improved financial service prototype to target customer needs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-falso-99474a103/">Andrea Falso</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-help-assess-guatemalas-digital-financial-services.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-help-assess-guatemalas-digital-financial-services.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Intro%20Blog%20-%20EAI.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“All technology has potential when modeled in the vacuum of our whiteboards and proposals,” remarks Revi Sterling, Director of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge&lt;/a&gt; (WCC). Shrewdly cutting to the chase, Sterling adds: “[But] rural smallholder farmer women do not live in vacuums.” In other words: for digital technologies to be part of any development solution, practitioners must first address the myriad of real-life barriers and inequities surrounding technology use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agrilinks.org/post/why-women-arent-using-your-ag-app&quot;&gt;recent blog&lt;/a&gt; on the low uptake of digital agriculture applications by women, Sterling explains how digital development programming often fails to grapple with the inherent gender biases imbued in many software platforms and services. Many digital interventions also fail to investigate the unique social and cultural circumstances that may bar women from participation in the digital sphere. Social norms surrounding intersectional identities such as class, disability, caste, indigenous identity, gender identity, sexual orientation, language minority, and other factors can further intensify these barriers to technology access and use. These oversights in program or software design often unintentionally exacerbate poverty and inequality, deepening the &lt;a href=&quot;https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/8cf03f8fcb374af8849cb95dc5e47931&quot;&gt;gender digital divide&lt;/a&gt; and undermining the development effort’s good intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 02:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-introducing-strategies-for-closing-the-gender-digital-divide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-introducing-strategies-for-closing-the-gender-digital-divide.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Global%20Forced%20Displacement.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Technology and Displacement: The Role of Digital Tools Among Displaced Persons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/in-honor-of-womens-history-month-exploring-the-gender-digital-divide.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; from last March, I wrote about the reality of the gender digital divide, in which I noted the difference in digital access and usage among women and men globally and the lost potential that results from women’s lack of access. When able to access, understand, and leverage digital tools, women can use these tools to better their economic outcomes and those of their families and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, women are not the only group facing the reality of the digital divide. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/en/content/digital-cooperation-roadmap/assets/pdf/Roadmap_for_Digital_Cooperation_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;United Nations Secretary-General’s Roadmap for Digital Cooperation,&lt;/a&gt; a report presenting strategies for inclusive, equitable adoption of digital technologies, notes some of the many other groups affected by similar challenges, including “migrants, refugees, internally displaced persons, older persons, young people, children, persons with disabilities, rural populations, and indigenous peoples.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/technology-and-displacement-the-role-of-digital-tools-among-displaced-persons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/technology-and-displacement-the-role-of-digital-tools-among-displaced-persons.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
