<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 11:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 11:31:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: El contexto digital de la población con discapacidad en Honduras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Se estima que el número de personas que viven con algún tipo de discapacidad en América Latina y el Caribe entre 2001 y 2013 fue de más de &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paho.org/hon/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;amp;view=download&amp;amp;alias=383-identificacion-y-caracterizacion-de-las-personas-con-discapacidad-en-francisco-morazan-2017&amp;amp;category_slug=fortalecimiento-de-sistemas-de-salud&amp;amp;Itemid=211&quot;&gt;70 millones&lt;/a&gt; (o 12.5 porciento de la población regional total, el 12.6 porciento de la población de América Latina y el 61 porciento de los países del Caribe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En Honduras los estudios acerca del tema de discapacidad son escasos y limitados. Según los resultados de la Encuesta Permanente de Hogares con Propósitos Múltiples del Instituto Nacional de Estadística (INE) realizada en septiembre 2002, se encontró que en Honduras existían 177,516 personas con discapacidad, lo que representa una prevalencia de 2.65 porciento, con predominio masculino (55 porciento) en comparación de la población femenina (45 porciento). Sin embargo, estudios recientes del [Censo 2013 del INE] indicaron la existencia de 205,423 personas con discapacidad, y &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;otro estudio&lt;/a&gt; de Flores, et al. (2014) encontró una tasa de prevalencia del 4.6 porciento, que significa un total de 381,287 personas que viven con discapacidades asumiendo una población de 8.2 millones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;–!more–&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En el 2009, el poder judicial de dicho país en su plan de modernización señaló la existencia de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poderjudicial.gob.hn/transparencia/planeacion/documents/PlandeModernizaci%C3%B3nPoderJudicial200420091.pdf&quot;&gt;problemas de acceso a la información&lt;/a&gt;, la cual se encuentra concentrada en Tegucigalpa, se indica que no existen los medios para acceder a la misma o para difundirla, en dicho plan no se mencionan los mecanismos de inclusión de las poblaciones con discapacidad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La actividad de &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/honduras-united-for-justice&quot;&gt;Justicia, Derechos Humanos y Seguridad de Honduras conocida como “Unidos por la Justicia”&lt;/a&gt; apoyada por USAID, buscaba alternativas para mejorar el acceso a la justicia de poblaciones vulnerables, y antes de realizar algún esfuerzo en el área digital se implementó un estudio bajo la metodología de Frontiers Insights® con el apoyo del Centro de Aceleración Digital (CDA) de DAI Global. El estudio tenía como objetivo principal, comprender el nivel de acceso a la justicia a través de las tecnologías de información y comunicación. Se utilizó una muestra de 310 personas distribuidas proporcionalmente de acuerdo con el tipo de discapacidad en Tegucigalpa, San Pedro Sula, Tela, y La Ceiba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;infogram-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;59d30854-8421-4cfc-9195-87e094679b16&quot; data-type=&quot;interactive&quot; data-title=&quot;Discapacidad&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;!function(e,i,n,s){var t=&quot;InfogramEmbeds&quot;,d=e.getElementsByTagName(&quot;script&quot;)\[0\];if(window\[t\]&amp;&amp;window\[t\].initialized)window\[t\].process&amp;&amp;window\[t\].process();else if(!e.getElementById(n)){var o=e.createElement(&quot;script&quot;);o.async=1,o.id=n,o.src=&quot;https://e.infogram.com/js/dist/embed-loader-min.js&quot;,d.parentNode.insertBefore(o,d)}}(document,0,&quot;infogram-async&quot;);&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;más-acceso-del-esperado-pero-poco-conocimiento-de-la-ley&quot;&gt;Más acceso del esperado pero poco conocimiento de la ley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dentro de los hallazgos en el uso y acceso a la tecnología y teléfonos más importantes se encontró que:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;En general, el 85 porciento tiene algún teléfono móvil&lt;/strong&gt;. Un 72 porciento tiene un Smartphone lo cual es alto en comparación a la media de Honduras que según el &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileconnectivityindex.com/#year=2018&amp;amp;zoneIsocode=HND&amp;amp;analysisView=HND&quot;&gt;índice de conectividad de GSMA  en el país un 52.7 &lt;/a&gt;porciento cuenta con un Smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;El 85 porciento de los usuarios de teléfonos tienen un Android&lt;/strong&gt;, el 14 porciento tiene un teléfono básico y el 8 porciento tiene un iPhone (Algunos tienen ambos un iPhone y un Android).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Las personas con discapacidad auditiva usan teléfonos inteligentes (95 porcentaje)&lt;/strong&gt; a una tasa mayor que otros grupos de personas con discapacidad, seguidos de visual (82 porceiento), físico (78 porciento), psicosocial (73 porciento), intelectual (67 porciento) y amputados (65 porciento).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Las personas con discapacidades intelectuales son las que tienen más probabilidades de no tener móvil (50 porciento), seguidas de las personas con discapacidades múltiples (12 porciento).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La gran mayoría no comparte su teléfono&lt;/strong&gt;, aunque las personas con bajos niveles de educación tienden a compartir y pedir prestado sus teléfonos a una tasa más alta que el promedio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;La probabilidad de tener un móvil cae después de los 50 años en todos los grupos demográficos (no es de extrañar, pero es útil saber la edad específica).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Las aplicaciones que más utiliza esta población es el &lt;strong&gt;Facebook, WhatsApp y Messenger&lt;/strong&gt; además de aplicaciones de apoyo específicas a su discapacidad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;infogram-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;ec8c98a8-2f67-4325-8381-b00e503c52d5&quot; data-type=&quot;interactive&quot; data-title=&quot;Phone 4&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;!function(e,i,n,s){var t=&quot;InfogramEmbeds&quot;,d=e.getElementsByTagName(&quot;script&quot;)\[0\];if(window\[t\]&amp;&amp;window\[t\].initialized)window\[t\].process&amp;&amp;window\[t\].process();else if(!e.getElementById(n)){var o=e.createElement(&quot;script&quot;);o.async=1,o.id=n,o.src=&quot;https://e.infogram.com/js/dist/embed-loader-min.js&quot;,d.parentNode.insertBefore(o,d)}}(document,0,&quot;infogram-async&quot;);&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En cuanto al acceso a la justicia y respeto se encontró que:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sólo el 35% conoce la ley&lt;/strong&gt; de Honduras para personas con discapacidades. Las personas con discapacidad auditiva (25 porciento) e intelectual (14 porciento) fueron las que menos conocimiento de la ley tenían y las personas con discapacidad física (50 porciento) y visual (55 porciento) fueron las más consientes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sólo el 24 porceiento considera que, como persona con discapacidad, el gobierno y las empresas los respetan&lt;/strong&gt;, pero hay una importante divergencia por discapacidad. Las personas discapacidad auditiva (41 porciento) e intelectual (44 porciento) reportaron la mayor percepción de respeto.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Las personas con discapacidades físicas (13 porciento), psicosociales (13 porciento) y visuales (8 porciento) percibieron significativamente menos respeto por su discapacidad en todos los sectores.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resultado-de-la-aplicación-de-frontiers-insights-a-poblaciones-con-discapacidad&quot;&gt;Resultado de la aplicación de Frontiers Insights® a poblaciones con discapacidad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;La aplicación de la encuesta tuvo algunos retos importantes específicamente en la aplicación de esta, fue por ello por lo que parte del equipo implementador fueron personas con discapacidades para lograr una mayor empatía y una interpretación más adecuada según el tipo de discapacidad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Las tecnologías móviles son ampliamente utilizadas por la población con discapacidad, y representa una ventana de oportunidad para el acceso a la información y herramientas que mejoren su calidad de vida.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;El estudio no solamente determinó el contexto digital de la población en cuestión, sino que también abarcó organizaciones y familias como medios de acceso a la justicia.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;El resultado afianza cualquier estrategia o acción a tomar en el proyecto Unidos por la Justicia, identificando acciones concretas basadas en la evidencia y datos colectados.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Éste estudio no hubiese sido posible, sin el apoyo del Sr. Adam Fivenson y todo el equipo técnico y administrativo de la Actividad de Justicia, Derechos Humanos y Seguridad de Honduras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Imagen%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Insights: How the Disability Community in Honduras Uses Digital Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this post in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/los-vehiculos-digitales-para-poblaciones-con-discapacidad-en-honduras.html&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies on how many disabled people live in Honduras are scarce. Results of the Permanent Survey of Households with Multiple Purposes of the National Statistics Institute (INE), carried out in September 2002, showed there are 177,516 people with disabilities in the country. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bvs.hn/Honduras/UICFCM/Articulo3_Vol83-1-2-Discapacidad.Sujetos.18-65a.pdf&quot;&gt;Academic studies&lt;/a&gt; tell a different story. They estimate that the number of people in Honduras with a disability is closer to 381,287 people. These differing reports demonstrate that Honduras has limited clarity on how many people within their country have a disability—preventing the government, institutions, and civil society from effectively thinking through how ensure that services are accessible to those with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/How-the-Disability-Community-in-Honduras-Uses-Digital-Tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/TLC%20pic%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building Digital Medical Records for Floating Villages in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you digitize medical records in Cambodia when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5DRZBiE6BTE&quot;&gt;your clinics are on a lake&lt;/a&gt;, have minimal internet connectivity, and are four hours away from the nearest big city? Impossible, you say? Not quite. Let me introduce you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lakeclinic.org/&quot;&gt;the Lake Clinic&lt;/a&gt; (TLC), a health clinic working to solve this complex challenge with the support of the six-year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org&quot;&gt;Development Innovations (DI)&lt;/a&gt; project, funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/setha-rath/">Setha Rath</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/case-study-from-cambodia-customizing-an-electronic-medical-records-system-for-floating-villages-in-tonle-sap-lake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/case-study-from-cambodia-customizing-an-electronic-medical-records-system-for-floating-villages-in-tonle-sap-lake.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/artificial-intelligence-3382507_640.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Making Sure Data Science For Good Does Good</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week at the 74th U.N. General Assembly, the Rockefeller Foundation announced a $100 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockefellerfoundation.org/about-us/news-media/using-data-save-lives-rockefeller-foundation-partners-launch-100-million-precision-public-health-initiative/&quot;&gt;Precision Public Health initiative&lt;/a&gt; to integrate data analytics and data science tools such as machine learning into the community health systems of low- and middle-income countries. During the announcement, Rockefeller noted the significant impact of data science innovations in the most privileged communities, explaining its hope to replicate this effect to improve healthcare for people globally. The initiative aims to save at least 6 million women and children’s lives by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/making-sure-data-science-for-good-does-good.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/making-sure-data-science-for-good-does-good.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/phone%20image%202.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development for Newbies, Part 1: The Basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) several months ago as an international development professional: familiar with ADS 302, Geo Code 937, Form AID 1420-17, among other industry acronyms, but a newcomer to the language of tech trends, digital buzzwords, and product design. I found the CDA team to be both inspiring and daunting, boasting individuals with unique expertise and passions—whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=cyber-security-series&quot;&gt;cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=human-centered-design&quot;&gt;human-centered design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=remote-sensing-series&quot;&gt;remote sensing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=blockchain-serieshttps://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=blockchain-series&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/what-good-is-the-internet-of-things-to-people-who-dont-have-internet.html&quot;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;. As a neophyte, it’s easy to be overwhelmed by what you don’t know in the seemingly limitless world of digital technology but I’m here to help! If you, too, are new to this sphere, what do you need to know to integrate digital tools into your development programs or proposals? Below are some key points to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Addie Ryan
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-1-the-basics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-for-newbies-part-1-the-basics.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ActivityKenya.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Applying the Principles for Digital Development in a Flourishing Digital Ecosystem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a co-facilitator at a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/what-we-do/agriculture-and-food-security/increasing-food-security-through-feed-future&quot;&gt;Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt; training on digital development for resilience and food security in Nairobi, I was struck by the stark contrast between the short amount of time (a scant four years) I’ve been settling debts with friends on Venmo and the participants’ resounding “we’ve been using it forever” response when I asked how long they had been using Kenya’s mobile payment system, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital.hbs.edu/platform-rctom/submission/m-pesa-transforming-kenya-with-mobile-money/&quot;&gt;M-Pesa&lt;/a&gt;. While I can imagine a world without Venmo, it is clear that, for many Kenyans, life without M-Pesa is inconceivable.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Susannah Horton
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/applying-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-a-flourishing-digital-ecosystem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/applying-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-a-flourishing-digital-ecosystem.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Panel.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Confidence Not Competence: What Holds Women Back from Embracing Tech in Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life, I’ve heard women grumble about using technology—from my mom, from friends in school, and from work colleagues—yet these are highly educated, often extremely logical thinkers that excel at, well, Excel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony of the situation has been troubling me in the past few months. Why? Because there is a clear contrast in attention paid to the benefits of empowering women and girls through technology in low-and middle-income countries, with the attention paid to empowering women and girls through technology in high-income environments.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/carmen-tedesco">Carmen Tedesco </a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/confidence-not-competence-what-holds-women-back-from-embracing-tech-in-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/confidence-not-competence-what-holds-women-back-from-embracing-tech-in-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1TechnovationGirls.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from Cambodia: How to Grow a Girls’ Tech Entrepreneurship Challenge in Six Years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you get Cambodian girls &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.development-innovations.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Factors-Affecting-Women-Engaging-in-Tech-Careers-in-Cambodia-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;engaged&lt;/a&gt; in addressing the digital gender divide? This is a question that the six-year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/&quot;&gt;Development Innovations (DI) project&lt;/a&gt; has been wrestling with since it was launched by the U.S. Agency for International Development—and that DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA)&lt;/a&gt; and DI have &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/defeated-by-the-digital-divide-invest-in-inclusion.html&quot;&gt;regularly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/powering-women-entrepreneurs-in-cambodia.html&quot;&gt;chronicled&lt;/a&gt; on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/?s=technovation&quot;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/image001.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from the Makerspace Community in High-Income Countries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Makerspaces—akin to coworking spaces with tools such as 3D printers and computer numerical control (CNC) mills as well as more traditional woodworking and metalworking items—offer participants access to equipment traditionally the domain of specialists or well-funded firms. Along with the proliferation of independent makerspaces starting in the mid-2000s, national organizations emerged to promote the model and connect regional maker communities, as well as offer a commercial platform for vendors making innovative tools for that market.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-makerspace-community-in-high-income-countries.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-makerspace-community-in-high-income-countries.html</guid>
        
        <category>Makerspace</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SWIR.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Visualizing Remotely Sensed Data: True Color and False Color</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What kind of images do you think of when you imagine Google Maps of our planet? Landmarks? Roads? Roads on top of satellite imagery? When we see that satellite imagery base map, we generally expect to see a representation of the earth that matches our reality. This is what we call in the world of remote sensing, “natural color.” For the average person, this use of earth-sensing satellites is the most useful, but in reality it represents only a fraction of the information gathered.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/visualizing-remotely-sensed-data-true-color-and-false-color.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/visualizing-remotely-sensed-data-true-color-and-false-color.html</guid>
        
        <category>Remote Sensing Series</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
