<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 11:41:47 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 11:41:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Panel.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Confidence Not Competence: What Holds Women Back from Embracing Tech in Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life, I’ve heard women grumble about using technology—from my mom, from friends in school, and from work colleagues—yet these are highly educated, often extremely logical thinkers that excel at, well, Excel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony of the situation has been troubling me in the past few months. Why? Because there is a clear contrast in attention paid to the benefits of empowering women and girls through technology in low-and middle-income countries, with the attention paid to empowering women and girls through technology in high-income environments.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/carmen-tedesco">Carmen Tedesco </a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/confidence-not-competence-what-holds-women-back-from-embracing-tech-in-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/confidence-not-competence-what-holds-women-back-from-embracing-tech-in-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1TechnovationGirls.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from Cambodia: How to Grow a Girls’ Tech Entrepreneurship Challenge in Six Years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you get Cambodian girls &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.development-innovations.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Factors-Affecting-Women-Engaging-in-Tech-Careers-in-Cambodia-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;engaged&lt;/a&gt; in addressing the digital gender divide? This is a question that the six-year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/&quot;&gt;Development Innovations (DI) project&lt;/a&gt; has been wrestling with since it was launched by the U.S. Agency for International Development—and that DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA)&lt;/a&gt; and DI have &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/defeated-by-the-digital-divide-invest-in-inclusion.html&quot;&gt;regularly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/powering-women-entrepreneurs-in-cambodia.html&quot;&gt;chronicled&lt;/a&gt; on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.development-innovations.org/?s=technovation&quot;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/image001.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from the Makerspace Community in High-Income Countries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Makerspaces—akin to coworking spaces with tools such as 3D printers and computer numerical control (CNC) mills as well as more traditional woodworking and metalworking items—offer participants access to equipment traditionally the domain of specialists or well-funded firms. Along with the proliferation of independent makerspaces starting in the mid-2000s, national organizations emerged to promote the model and connect regional maker communities, as well as offer a commercial platform for vendors making innovative tools for that market.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-makerspace-community-in-high-income-countries.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-makerspace-community-in-high-income-countries.html</guid>
        
        <category>Makerspace</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SWIR.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Visualizing Remotely Sensed Data: True Color and False Color</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What kind of images do you think of when you imagine Google Maps of our planet? Landmarks? Roads? Roads on top of satellite imagery? When we see that satellite imagery base map, we generally expect to see a representation of the earth that matches our reality. This is what we call in the world of remote sensing, “natural color.” For the average person, this use of earth-sensing satellites is the most useful, but in reality it represents only a fraction of the information gathered.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/visualizing-remotely-sensed-data-true-color-and-false-color.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/visualizing-remotely-sensed-data-true-color-and-false-color.html</guid>
        
        <category>Remote Sensing Series</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Skilllab%20Photo.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Center for Digital Acceleration Partners with Award-Winning Tech Startup Skilllab</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the ways DAI tackles global challenges is by partnering with other innovators to invest in promising solutions. In joining forces with tech startups that align with our mission, we bring the power of technology and entrepreneurship to bear on global development challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, for example, we supported four startups through our ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/dai-and-partners-launch-innovation-action-challenge&quot;&gt;Innovation into Action Challenge&lt;/a&gt;’, including education tech firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laboratoria.la/en&quot;&gt;Laboratoria&lt;/a&gt;, renewable energy enterprise &lt;a href=&quot;https://solarsister.org/&quot;&gt;Solar Sister&lt;/a&gt;, and m-health platforms &lt;a href=&quot;https://clickmedix.com/&quot;&gt;ClickMedix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thinkmd.org/&quot;&gt;ThinkMD&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier this year, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/dai-global-health-invests-in-mhealth-leader-clickmedix&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;  our investment in ClickMedix. We’ve also invested in Ghanaian startups that emerged from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/new-cda-insights-publication-building-the-future-of-tech-enabled-agriculture.html&quot;&gt;Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt;. Keeping with this tradition, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration is pleased to announce a new strategic partnership with our friends and colleagues at &lt;a href=&quot;https://skilllab.io/&quot;&gt;Skilllab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/partnership-with-award-winning-tech-startup-skilllab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/partnership-with-award-winning-tech-startup-skilllab.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAI00418.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Navigating Barriers to Digital Inclusion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first began learning about digital development, I thought of it as a new frontier that could push international development out of its modus operandi. New digital tools could provide individuals, communities, governments, and organizations with new sources of information at rapid speeds—enabling new means of collaboration to propel development objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital technology is unique for two reasons. First, digital is &lt;em&gt;informative&lt;/em&gt;—providing users with increased access to new information and opportunities at their fingertips. Second, digital is &lt;em&gt;informed&lt;/em&gt;—enabling users to input information that will conceivably be used by industries and governments to tailor and update their products and benefit their business and economies to improve customer experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-magid/">Ariel Magid</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/navigating-barriers-to-digital-inclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/navigating-barriers-to-digital-inclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DSC_0061.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Understanding Cybersecurity for Healthcare Professionals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in exciting times. The ways in which we store and engage with health data have been transformed with the creation and adoption of digital health technology. Whether it’s using a Fitbit, accessing your vaccine records online, or virtually connecting with your doctor, understanding your health status in real time has never been easier… for some of us. We at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/global-health&quot;&gt;DAI Global Health&lt;/a&gt; are working tirelessly to increase access to healthcare in low- and middle-income countries by leveraging digital health technologies. The goal is to empower patients and professionals providing care to them to use data to make smart decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/rachel-clad/">Rachel Clad</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-for-health-professionals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-for-health-professionals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/digital-identity-usaid.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New USAID Guide: How to Create Digital ID for Inclusive Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.usaid.gov%2Fdigital-development%2Fdigital-id%2Fhow-to-guide&amp;amp;data=01%7C01%7CStephanie_Creed%40dai.com%7C1f9cda42f7114bd429d508d71147871e%7C7107113de20b4c20a4ce553cabbf686d%7C0&amp;amp;sdata=hn%2F6OZETU58OZUX59RCvfLdR8UywARdX66Or14vgUok%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;Guide to Creating Digital ID for Inclusive Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity is deeply personal. Issues of identity are complex and tied up with power, privacy, and protection. Yet identifying constituents is often critical to organizing and managing global development projects. Decades of development work have relied on ad hoc identity systems to administer programs, yet today we find that nearly 1 billion people still lack representative identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USAID’s 2017 report &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/IDENTITY_IN_A_DIGITAL_AGE.pdf&quot;&gt;Identity in a Digital Age: Infrastructure for Inclusive Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; documented some of the complexities that arise when we create or use digital ID in development programming. Done well, these systems can provide a unique, trusted, multipurpose ID to everyone, which is key to economic and social development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrissiy/">Chrissy Martin Meier</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shachee-doshi-47358a56/">Shachee Doshi</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-usaid-guide-how-to-create-digital-id-for-inclusive-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-usaid-guide-how-to-create-digital-id-for-inclusive-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Identity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cs1-9318e9.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Карти, гроші, VPN: кібербезпекові реалії в Україні</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this blog in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cупротив та неузгодженість — напевне, той асоціативний ряд, який спадає на думку, коли уявляємо, що в одній кімнаті мають зустрітися державні управлінці, громадський сектор та представники бізнесу для обговорення тонкощів кібербезпеки. Проте, на Cyber Security Day - серії подій, які команда SocialBoost нещодавно організувала з новим партнером DAI, нам вдалося досягти абсолютно іншого ефекту.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://ua.linkedin.com/in/denisgursky">Denis Gursky</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cs1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cybersecurity Lessons from Ukraine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this blog in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html&quot;&gt;Ukrainian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you walk into a room full of government officials, civil society organizations, and private companies discussing cybersecurity, you expect to hear disagreement. The exact opposite happened during the recent DAI- &lt;a href=&quot;http://socialboost.com.ua/&quot;&gt;SocialBoost&lt;/a&gt; Cybersecurity Roundtable and Workshop in Kyiv, Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event started with a panel discussion with representatives from a myriad of government institutions working to address Ukraine’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.eu/article/ukraine-cyber-war-frontline-russia-malware-attacks/&quot;&gt;cybersecurity challenges&lt;/a&gt;. Representatives came from the Ministry of Energy, the Pension Fund of Ukraine, State Service of Special Communications and Information Protection of Ukraine, the Presidential Administration, Ministry of Infrastructure, and National Information Systems. Joining them were representatives from the company Information Systems Security Partners (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.issp.com/&quot;&gt;ISSP&lt;/a&gt;) and the law firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://sk.ua/&quot;&gt;Sayenko Kharenko&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://ua.linkedin.com/in/denisgursky">Denis Gursky</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
