<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 10:55:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 10:55:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20Munni%20Akhter_PC%20Atanu%20Bhattacharjee_Bangladesh%20Digital%20Activity.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons Learned in Bangladesh: Engaging Women in Digital Agriculture Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The role of women in agriculture is crucial, especially in countries such as Bangladesh where they make up almost half of the sector’s labor force. However, women often have limited access to resources and assets that could improve their livelihoods, including information that can be accessed through technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital agriculture tools, such as mobile apps and texting services, can help overcome the information disparity between men and women. But first, it is essential to understand the unique challenges that women face in agriculture and how digital tools can address those challenges. Women often have limited access to land, capital, and information, which hinders their participation. Moreover, they have limited mobility, which makes it difficult for them to physically access markets and other agricultural services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Plantix_BNA_Patuakhali_Sador_Add%20On%20%20Farmer_Ayesha%20Begum_16Mr22.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Plantix_BNA_Patuakhali_Sador_Add On  Farmer_Ayesha Begum_16Mr22.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: BDAA.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tasnuba/">Tasnuba Sinha</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-in-bangladesh-engaging-women-in-digital-agriculture-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-in-bangladesh-engaging-women-in-digital-agriculture-tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Digital Ecosystem Country Assessment (DECA) has Spurred Innovative Digital Development Around the World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the Government of Colombia and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) brokered a peace accord that ended nearly five decades of internal armed conflict. After years of reconciliation and peacebuilding efforts, however, new emerging threats to civil society, while digital, have the potential to incite physical violence, according to findings in a 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-strategy/implementation-tracks/track1-adopt-ecosystem/digital-ecosystem-country-assessments&quot;&gt;Digital Ecosystem Country Assessment&lt;/a&gt; (DECA) report published by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalfrontiersdai.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project. The report recommended that USAID invest in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/cybersecurity&quot;&gt;cyber hygiene programming&lt;/a&gt; in Colombia to assess and improve online and offline safety. Today, USAID Colombia has partnered with USAID’s Digital APEX project to build just this type of capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more USAID Missions like Colombia’s grapple with the emerging opportunities and challenges of our digital world, the Digital Strategy is shaping the Agency’s response. To design policies and programs that take advantage of technology, stakeholders need to first understand the building blocks of a country’s digital landscape. The DECA, a cornerstone of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-strategy&quot;&gt;Digital Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, is helping development practitioners to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/deca%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;deca 1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Hanz Rippe/Paramo Films for USAID.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Patrick Malone
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-digital-ecosystem-country-assessment-deca-has-spurred-innovative-digital-development-around-the-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-digital-ecosystem-country-assessment-deca-has-spurred-innovative-digital-development-around-the-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CSISPhotoBlog2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Preparing International Development Professionals for the Digital Age</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/preparing-international-development-professionals-digital-age&quot;&gt;originally appeared&lt;/a&gt; on the Center for Strategic and International Studies’ website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in technology are transforming every industry in the global economy. In particular, the disruption created by the COVID-19 pandemic pushed governments, companies, and citizens to adopt a wide range of digital solutions. Many activities—including government services, work, schooling, and retail—shifted online. The pandemic also revealed that workers and regular citizens were not equipped with the right skills to operate in the digital age. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/web/products-eurostat-news/-/ddn-20220330-1&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; conducted by the European Commission in 2021 revealed that only 54 percent of Europeans possess basic digital skills. In 2022, Salesforce’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforce.com/news/press-releases/2022/01/27/digital-skills-index-update/&quot;&gt;Digital Skills Index&lt;/a&gt; found that three out of four workers globally did not feel ready to operate in a digital-first world. Most worrisome is the fact that the same study revealed only 28 percent of respondents were actively engaged in training programs or pursuing learning opportunities to acquire digital skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CSISPhotoBlog2-702fe0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CSISPhotoBlog2-702fe0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: FADEL SENNA/AFP/Getty Images.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 08:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.csis.org/people/romina-bandura">Romina Bandura</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/preparing-international-development-professionals-for-the-digital-age.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/preparing-international-development-professionals-for-the-digital-age.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/LiberiaConnectivityImage.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Realizing Inclusive Connectivity in Liberia Through a Trusted Technical Engagement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Transmitting data through transparent fibers barely thicker than a human hair, the Africa Coast to Europe (ACE) optical-fiber submarine cable system revolutionized Liberia’s information and communications technology (ICT) sector. Landing off the shore of Liberia’s capital, Monrovia, in 2011, this 17,000-kilometer cable that stretches from France to South Africa marked the country’s introduction to high-speed internet. Providing connectivity to 24 countries, the cable also demonstrated a commitment to reduce the digital divide and democratize internet access in Africa through secure, diverse, and resilient ICT infrastructure investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While ACE, made possible through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ace-submarinecable.com/en/members/&quot;&gt;landmark agreement&lt;/a&gt; between a consortium of telecommunications companies and member countries, significantly increased connectivity in Monrovia, the lack of optical fiber cables beyond the capital resulted in low connectivity in Liberia’s rural areas. Moreover, Liberia lacks a much-needed system of high-speed networks linked together with fiber-optic connections to establish what is formally known as a fiber backbone—a critical prerequisite to fully maximize the ACE cable’s potential.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 07:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-connectivity-in-liberia-through-a-trusted-technical-engagement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-connectivity-in-liberia-through-a-trusted-technical-engagement.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20olumide-bamgbelu-Ciba8rvHYng-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Downsides: The Economic Impact of Misinformation and Other Digital Harms on MSMEs in Kenya, India, and Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: The full report is now available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/digital-downsides.pdf&quot;&gt;download here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitalization presents both opportunities and challenges for micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) in emerging markets. Digital tools can increase business efficiency and reach, but also increase exposure to misinformation, fraud, and cyber attacks. Such “digital downsides” can lead to financial losses, reputational damage, loss of customer trust, and other challenges that hinder MSMEs’ ability—and desire—to participate in the digital economy. In this post, we’re previewing a soon-to-be-released report that DAI authored about the economic impact of misinformation and other digital harms on MSMEs in Kenya, India, and Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our research, and with the help of our in-country local partners, we asked 85 business owners about their understanding and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/building-resilience-against-disinformation.html&quot;&gt;awareness of misinformation&lt;/a&gt; and other digital downsides and the impact of these experiences on their businesses. We further wanted to understand the types of digital tools (social media platforms, messaging services, digital payment devices, etc.) that business owners in lower- and middle-income countries (LMICs) use and what gaps exist that could be filled through training or by government, private sector, nonprofit and other actors. Lastly, we uncovered how misinformation factors into a business context, rather than an electoral or public health context (which is how misinformation has typically been studied).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 07:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/nancy-haugh">Nancy Haugh</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/priya-sethi-96ba3025/">Priya Sethi</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/komal-bazaz-smith-3a56b5/">Komal Bazaz Smith</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristenroggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-downsides-the-economic-impact-of-misinformation-and-other-digital-harms-on-msmes-in-kenya-india-and-cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-downsides-the-economic-impact-of-misinformation-and-other-digital-harms-on-msmes-in-kenya-india-and-cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Digital Communications</category>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Misinformation</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20DAI%20LLC-182.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Call to Action: Igniting the Digital Revolution in International Development Studies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/call-action-igniting-digital-revolution-international-development-studies&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on the Center for Strategic and International Studies’ website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technological advancements are transforming every sector of the global economy, opening the way for governments, businesses, and individuals to drastically reframe how they engage with one another. The field of international development is not immune to these changes and has, in fact, seen a marked shift in new approaches and business models in response to today’s digital age. Development practitioners are actively responding to the increased role of tools like artificial intelligence, digital identity, digital financial services, and geospatial visualization in project design and implementation. However, the increased use of digital technology also carries real risks to users. Beyond cybersecurity and data privacy breaches, the rise in disinformation and misinformation, the increased risk of misuse, bias, and discrimination, and the growing trend of digital authoritarianism around the world are all causes for concern.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Romina Bandura and Christopher Burns
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-call-to-action-igniting-the-digital-revolution-in-international-development-studies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-call-to-action-igniting-the-digital-revolution-in-international-development-studies.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>USAID</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202022-11-30%20at%201.31.17%20PM-03871e.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Year in Review: Top 10 Posts of 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we do annually, it is time for the Top 10 Posts of 2022. What a year! A bit of a return to normalcy after the hardships of 2021, with a welcome return to childcare (not joking), in-person meetings, and travel to connect with colleagues and do technical work globally. In the digital development world, a continued reckoning with the complex challenges of advanced technologies and the multitude of benefits—and risks—of widespread digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily, it seems our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2022.html&quot;&gt;predictions&lt;/a&gt; for what we’re thinking about in 2022 were largely correct. Through Digital@DAI, we covered topics as varied as &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cda-insights-2022-toward-ethical-artificial-intelligence-in-international-development.html&quot;&gt;ethical artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt; (AI) and its importance in international development, a robust &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-literacy-series-closing-the-gap-for-semi-literate-and-illiterate-populations.html&quot;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on digital literacy, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html&quot;&gt;disability divide&lt;/a&gt; in ICT. Interestingly, the top two most-read posts published in 2022 were &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=climate&quot;&gt;climate tech-focused&lt;/a&gt;. Climate tech has been called the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/sustainability/how-we-help-clients/cop/the-cop26-daily/climate-technology-a-new-frontier-for-innovation-and-growth&quot;&gt;new frontier for innovation and growth&lt;/a&gt;” and investments in the sector are at an all-time high. Our readers’ engagement with these posts aligns with the expanding focus on this area in digital development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2022.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2022.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>ai</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Chatbots for the International Development and Humanitarian Sectors: What Works?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed chatbots becoming more commonplace in your life. Buying yourself a new sound system online? A chatbot pops up offering help. Need to confirm flight details? The airline’s chatbot can do that for you. Chatbots can offer a quick and easy way to get the information you need on the platform you are already using, whether that be a website, Facebook Messenger, or WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they operate with low bandwidth and are simple to use, chatbots seem like they could be a beneficial technology to engage with recipients of our development and humanitarian programs, don’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any technology, the use of chatbots is migrating from the private sector and becoming more prevalent in crisis and conflict response. However, documentation of lessons learned, successes and failures, and best practices of the use of chatbots in the development and humanitarian sectors are still few and far between. Through our work with Sesame Workshop, DAI conducted desk research and key informant interviews to examine use cases and review lessons learned for the use of chatbots in the international development and humanitarian sectors. In this blog, we summarize our key findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1-dc4d49.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture1-dc4d49.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image: Pixabay/Mohamed Hassan.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Carrington
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/chatbots-for-the-international-development-and-humanitarian-sectors-what-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/chatbots-for-the-international-development-and-humanitarian-sectors-what-works.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/system-g3f0828b60_640.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Look Into the Future: Rwanda’s Road to Digital Transformation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, my family was visiting me in Rwanda. We were traveling two hours outside of the capital, in a rural, forested area, on what seemed to be the only straight patch of road in the mountainous country. As we were admiring the landscape, in my rearview mirror, I saw a flash. I knew she got me. Sophia—one of Rwanda’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ktpress.rw/2021/11/rwanda-police-drivers-in-traffic-fines-controversy/&quot;&gt;notorious traffic cameras&lt;/a&gt; (jokingly called “Sophia” by Rwandans and named after a humanoid robot that spoke at the Transform Africa Summit in 2019) cruelly captured me going over the speed limit. Within 15 minutes, I received a speeding ticket via text message. I quickly paid the fine through Rwanda’s mobile money app, MoMo, and we continued our trip. Despite the ticket, I had to marvel at the technology that underpinned the entire exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 08:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Ben Harguth
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/rwandas-road-to-digital-transformation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/rwandas-road-to-digital-transformation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/solen-feyissa-3aLMXGvH4GA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Rewind: The Rise of TikTok—How One App is Making Waves in the Global Development Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recently, I’ve been thinking about how the organizational shifts at Twitter will affect TikTok. With Tesla CEO Elon Musk now owning one of the world’s most high-profile information systems, there are bound to be changes in user satisfaction. While TikTok and Twitter have different features and purposes, a few questions have popped up for me. Will we see more users flocking to TikTok due to Musk’s acquisition (or vice versa)? Will TikTok’s brand, ownership, or features change to compete with Twitter’s upcoming changes? Will communities find new ways to organize and communicate beyond both apps? Is it a matter of time before a more unique, more innovative platform rides the wave (and hopefully, betters all of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://oakparktalon.org/15364/opinion/tiktok-is-shortening-our-attention-spans/&quot;&gt;attention spans&lt;/a&gt;)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While I don’t have the answers to any of these questions, I do have the answer to one question: Is TikTok really that influential?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Afua Owusu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
