<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:23:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20kevin-ku_unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Have We Learned in the Past Five Years about Cybersecurity?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third in a series of blog posts about cybersecurity to mark Cybersecurity Awareness Month in October.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For digital development practitioners, cybersecurity is now in the digital development zeitgeist. Over the past five years or so, it has become an important standalone technical area, as well as a critical building block of all our interventions. In honor of Cybersecurity Awareness Month, I wanted to revisit Digital@DAI’s earliest posts about cybersecurity from 2018 to see how our initial thinking holds up against a 2023 mindset. Our first-ever series on cybersecurity introduced the concept of cybersecurity to digital development practitioners by doing three things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-series-part-1-trust-is-why-cyber-security-matters-to-digital-development.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;Providing a technical explanation&lt;/a&gt; of cybersecurity and linking it to the concept of trust;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-2.html&quot;&gt;Examining cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; through the lens of regulations, skills, and institutions, aligned to the World Bank’s 2016 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://documents1.worldbank.org/curated/en/896971468194972881/pdf/102725-PUB-Replacement-PUBLIC.pdf&quot;&gt;Digital Dividends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; report, and;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-series-part-3-pirated-software.html&quot;&gt;Examining the topic&lt;/a&gt; of pirated software at the micro level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-have-we-learned-in-the-past-five-years-about-cybersecurity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-have-we-learned-in-the-past-five-years-about-cybersecurity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20vote.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Cybersecurity Literacy Can Help People Counter Disinformation and Exercise their Human Rights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second in a series of blog posts about cybersecurity to mark Cybersecurity Awareness Month in October.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enisa.europa.eu/publications/enisa-threat-landscape-2022&quot;&gt;2022 Threat Landscape Report&lt;/a&gt; published by the European Union Agency for Cybersecurity (ENISA) highlights the spread of disinformation as one of the top eight cybersecurity &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/headlines/society/20220120STO21428/cybersecurity-main-and-emerging-threats&quot;&gt;threats&lt;/a&gt;. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/2023-01/Disinformation-Primer.pdf&quot;&gt;Disinformation Primer&lt;/a&gt; defines disinformation as information that is shared with the intent to mislead people. As the world becomes more digitally connected and as digital technologies become more integrated into different aspects of daily life, it is important to understand the impact of digital disinformation. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disinformation can cause people to stop trusting the institutions and systems that assist them in exercising their fundamental human rights.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citizens who do not trust their electoral systems will be deterred from exercising their right to vote.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business owners who are hesitant to use digital technologies will find it harder to earn a good income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rachel Chang
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-cybersecurity-literacy-can-help-people-counter-disinformation-and-exercise-their-human-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-cybersecurity-literacy-can-help-people-counter-disinformation-and-exercise-their-human-rights.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/goldsteinunsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Unlocking the Potential of Generative AI in Cybersecurity: A Roadmap to Opportunities and Challenges</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in a series of blog posts about cybersecurity to mark Cybersecurity Awareness Month in October.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is a fascinating field that is taking the world by storm. It is a cutting-edge technology that allows algorithms to create new and unique data, which was unimaginable just a few years ago. While traditional AI models are designed to recognize and classify existing patterns, generative AI models are trained to generate new patterns and unique output data. With generative AI, the possibilities are endless—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midjourney.com/home/?callbackUrl=%2Fapp%2F&quot;&gt;MidJourney&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/dall-e-2&quot;&gt;DALL-E&lt;/a&gt; create art, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/auth/login&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; writes compelling pieces of text that are nearly indistinguishable from those created by humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the potential of this technology in industries such as healthcare and cybersecurity, where it can be used to create new and innovative solutions to existing problems. The possibilities are truly endless, and we are only at the beginning of this exciting journey. However, despite offering exciting opportunities and applications in cybersecurity, generative AI comes with its challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 08:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/unlocking-the-potential-of-generative-ai-in-cybersecurity-a-roadmap-to-opportunities-and-challenges.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/unlocking-the-potential-of-generative-ai-in-cybersecurity-a-roadmap-to-opportunities-and-challenges.html</guid>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ICTforag.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Call for Sessions: ICTforAg 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark your calendars for November 7-9, because ICTforAg is back and bigger than ever. The recent online launch event unveiled the theme for 2023: “Cultivating Inclusion.” This annual gathering, now hosted by CGIAR in partnership with the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), Feed the Future, DevGlobal, and DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project, will be a global hub where technology and agriculture intersect. Sign up now and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictforag.com/events/ictforag-2023/suggest-a-session/&quot;&gt;submit your session ideas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Juliet Terrill
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/call-for-sessions-ictforag-2023.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/call-for-sessions-ictforag-2023.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-09-21%20at%2010.00.36%20AM.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Government-Run Digital Tools to Combat Corruption: Can They Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Originally &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-developments.com/articles/government-run-digital-tools-to-combat-corruption-can-they-work/&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; on DAI’s Developments blog.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 and early 2015, more than 3,000 volunteers peered into their monitors to try and decipher poorly handwritten and scanned &lt;a href=&quot;https://star.worldbank.org/focus-area/asset-declarations?ref=pubs.ghost.io&quot;&gt;annual asset declarations&lt;/a&gt; from Ukrainian officials that described their properties, vehicles, land, commercial venues, bank accounts, and cash. It was a tedious task. At times, it seemed that civil servants deliberately used bad handwriting to comply with the requirements of paper-based transparency. By 2022, before the full-scale war, any internet user would have free access to more than 2.5 million asset declarations searchable through the public registry of the National Agency for Prevention of Corruption of Ukraine and at least one advanced civil society powered instrument that worked on the data-fuel from this registry. The difference was night and day. Now, instead of peering into illegible scans of handwritten scribbles, with a click of a button you can check whether a company owned by civil servant John Doe won any government contracts last year, and whether his elderly parents bought a mansion close to the capital or a new luxury car—and ask questions to the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments worldwide are rushing to use digital technology to reduce corruption. Over the past decade, state agencies have increasingly used digital systems to conduct anti-corruption investigations, gather and analyze asset declarations, automate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/E-Procurement%20pages.pdf?ref=pubs.ghost.io&quot;&gt;electronic procurement processes&lt;/a&gt;, and analyze open data. Despite initial implementation difficulties in many countries, these digital tools have &lt;a href=&quot;https://star.worldbank.org/publications/automated-risk-analysis-asset-and-interest-declarations-public-officials?ref=pubs.ghost.io&quot;&gt;proven effective&lt;/a&gt;. Many governments that benefit from donor assistance are now asking to prioritize resources for upgrading or building new IT systems to help counter corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/maksym-klyuchar">Maksym Klyuchar</a> and <a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/miriam-stankovich">Miriam Stankovich</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/government-run-digital-tools-to-combat-corruption-can-they-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/government-run-digital-tools-to-combat-corruption-can-they-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Digital Government</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20Cambodia%20DI%20Khmer%20Keyboard%20with%20Vanna%20Kruy.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What Do You Get When You Combine Digital Infrastructure, Skills, and Trust with Affordability and Device Access? Introducing Our Concept of Digital Readiness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) has done many deep dives about different topic areas on &lt;em&gt;Digital@DAI&lt;/em&gt; over the years, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html&quot;&gt;digital skills&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-frontier-insights-findings-user-perceptions-of-trust-and-privacy-on-the-internet.html&quot;&gt;digital trust&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-connectivity-in-liberia-through-a-trusted-technical-engagement.html&quot;&gt;digital infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/covid-19.html&quot;&gt;affordability&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/embracing-the-unlikely-resilience-of-feature-phones.html&quot;&gt;access&lt;/a&gt;. For the first time ever, I am going to bring them all together under the umbrella of “digital readiness.” Before we get there, however, I want to acknowledge that CDA is not the first organization to come up with its own definition for this term. How have others defined digital readiness?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-do-you-get-when-you-combine-digital-infrastructure-skills-and-trust-with-affordability-and-device-access-introducing-our-concept-of-digital-readiness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-do-you-get-when-you-combine-digital-infrastructure-skills-and-trust-with-affordability-and-device-access-introducing-our-concept-of-digital-readiness.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>digital divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5545435994_acd18f073c_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>As Democracy Goes Digital, Cybersecurity Takes Precedence: 5 Critical Resources For Protecting Elections Against Digital Threats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From introducing biometric voter verification machines in Kenya to testing an internet voting pilot in Norway, election management bodies (EMBs) have increasingly digitized elections in efforts to increase efficiency, promote transparency, and encourage greater voter participation. While many elections have increasingly involved technology, including digital voter rolls, biometric voter registration, and electronic voting machines, these critical democratic processes have become more susceptible to a rapidly evolving threat—cyberattacks. Failure to address cybersecurity risks inherent to a digitized electoral process can pose a grave threat to electoral integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/as-democracy-goes-digital-cybersecurity-takes-precedence-5-critical-resources-for-protecting-elections-against-digital-threats.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/as-democracy-goes-digital-cybersecurity-takes-precedence-5-critical-resources-for-protecting-elections-against-digital-threats.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm_VZR9145.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Playing the Short and Long Game: The Importance of Adaptability in Cybersecurity Programming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: This post is adapted from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaldevforum.com/agenda/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming&quot;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; presented at the recent Global Digital Development Forum (GDDF) 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, DAI has expanded its cybersecurity portfolio to cover regions including Asia-Pacific, Eastern Europe, and the Western Balkans. Designing and delivering programs that focus on building the resilience of cybersecurity stakeholders and ecosystems involves investments in three key elements of cybersecurity: people, process, and technology. It also demands that we apply this approach with local existing conditions. Importantly, cybersecurity programming also requires flexibility for rapid responses in case of unforeseen and new threats, political turnover, or major geopolitical developments expanding cyber or hybrid warfare. This is naturally dictated by realities and conditions in the geographies where we work, where local actors and beneficiaries often face external shocks requiring adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/VZR9145.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VZR9145.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Stock.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 06:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-odisheli-a2a56494/">Alexander Odisheli</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-short-and-long-game-the-importance-of-adaptability-in-cybersecurity-programming.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sm%20Photo%20Credit_Mawingu.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Bridging the Gender Digital Divide: Four Approaches to Bringing Women Online From the USAID/Microsoft Airband Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Globally, women are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/r/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The-Mobile-Gender-Gap-Report-2022.pdf&quot;&gt;18 percent&lt;/a&gt; less likely than men to own a smartphone. This statistic illustrates—particularly in low-income, rural households—the “gender digital divide,” where women are less likely to be connected to the internet and lack access to important tools that could improve their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gender digital divide limits women and girls’ opportunities on all fronts—from gaining an education to accessing their finances online to participating in politics and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing how digital inclusion empowers women and boosts the economies of rural communities, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/usaid-microsoft-airband-initiative&quot;&gt;USAID/Microsoft Airband Initiative&lt;/a&gt; has partnered with six private companies in five countries to provide women and girls with meaningful connectivity, internet access, and the skills necessary to navigate the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Photo%20Credit_%20New%20Sun%20Road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo Credit_ New Sun Road.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: New Sun Road.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 08:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Lana Alnesany
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/bridging-the-gender-digital-divide-four-approaches-to-bringing-women-online-from-the-usaid-slash-microsoft-airband-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/bridging-the-gender-digital-divide-four-approaches-to-bringing-women-online-from-the-usaid-slash-microsoft-airband-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>digital platforms</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Digital Skills</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/smCambodia%20DI.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Kids are Alright: Reframing “Digital Natives”  for International Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is adapted from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaldevforum.com/agenda/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development&quot;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; presented at the 2023 Global Digital Development Forum (GDDF).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term digital native was coined by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Prensky&quot;&gt;Mark Prensky&lt;/a&gt; in 2001. The writer and educator used it to broadly describe a generation that grew up in an era shaped by the internet and digital technology. Digital natives are believed to possess a mastery of technological skills that are inherently different from prior generations. Prensky referred to the arrival of the digital age as a “singularity” that caused students of the time to “think and process information fundamentally differently than their predecessors.” These skills were attributed to the early introduction of digital tools into the homes, schools, and social lives of young people and the perception that this technology is seamlessly integrated into their daily interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-kids-are-alright-reframing-digital-natives-for-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
