<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:28:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:28:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blockchain for Development Part 1: Understanding the Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin has launched the term “blockchain” into the world’s tech vernacular. Unfortunately for blockchain as a technology and a theory, it is often, for better or worse, synonymized with Bitcoin. Because of this, the ideas of public, transparent, and unchangeable information immediately come to mind as soon as someone mentions blockchain. While this is true for Bitcoin, this is not necessarily the case for all blockchains.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Trevor Olexy
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/blockchain-for-development-part-1-understanding-the-tech.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/blockchain-for-development-part-1-understanding-the-tech.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Putting Liberian Cities on the Map With OpenStreetMap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the world becomes more urbanized, data on cities and the residents who inhabit them is key to building and governing sustainable communities. Yet this data is simply not available for many rural and urban areas around the world. Many cities lack base data sets—such as accurate maps of their cities that identify key infrastructure, services, and human settlements. In some cases, these maps exist on paper, but in other cases, are only available in closed, proprietary systems or not at all. This was the case in the Liberian cities of Ganta, Gbarnga, and Zwedru.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 13:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Emmanuel Greene and Koakun Emmanuel Myers, with contributions from Tyler Radford
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/weve-got-to-map-our-city-putting-three-liberian-cities-on-the-map-using-openstreetmap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/weve-got-to-map-our-city-putting-three-liberian-cities-on-the-map-using-openstreetmap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Sub-Saharan Africa</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How a Pilot Project in Haiti Brings Optimism for Digitally Enabled Health System</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently presented during a TechChange course titled “The Future of Digital Health.” I was asked to discuss the implementation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/haiti-strategic-health-information-system-his-program&quot;&gt;Haiti Strategic Health Information System&lt;/a&gt; (HIS) program, a five-year, U.S. Agency for International Development-funded initiative that is consolidating and integrating Haiti’s disconnected health information assets. Preparing for this presentation gave me a chance to reflect on the past year—the progress we have made, the challenges we have encountered, and the future of digital health in Haiti.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 13:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nernst-atwood-raphael-5a46ba6a/">Atwood Raphael</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/haitis-digital-health-future-how-a-pilot-project-brings-optimism-for-a-digital-enabled-health-system.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/haitis-digital-health-future-how-a-pilot-project-brings-optimism-for-a-digital-enabled-health-system.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Engage and Support Local Innovators: 3 Takeaways from the Digital Development Forum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 9, I moderated a workshop called “How to Engage and Support Local Innovators” at the USAID &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitaldevelopment.org/digital-development-forum-2018&quot;&gt;Digital Development Forum&lt;/a&gt;. I was joined by three expert panelists: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielle-dhillon-a82a9859/&quot;&gt;Danielle Dhillon&lt;/a&gt; from the Digital Impact Alliance (DIAL) at the UN Foundation; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonieliasz/&quot;&gt;Toni Eliasz&lt;/a&gt; from the World Bank’s Digital Entrepreneurship Program; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tylerradford/&quot;&gt;Tyler Radford&lt;/a&gt; from the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team (HOT). All three are focused on nurturing local technologists and innovators. Toni and Danielle support local startup ecosystems and Tyler builds communities of volunteer mappers. What have they learned through these efforts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Capture.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Capture.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 11:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-engage-and-support-local-innovators-three-take-aways-from-the-digital-development-forum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-engage-and-support-local-innovators-three-take-aways-from-the-digital-development-forum.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Playing The Right Role In Haiti’s Growing Mobile Sector: 4 Key Principles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital financial services have been a robust part of the development sector for over a decade and their impact continues to grow. This blog post is part of a series produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mstarproject.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;mStar&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on successful projects that achieve results-driven impact in people’s lives. This post was originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mstarproject.wordpress.com/2018/03/12/haitis-growing-mobile-sector/&quot;&gt;mStar digital development blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/rsz_haiti_dfs_photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rsz_haiti_dfs_photo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an exciting time for mobile money expansion in Haiti. Digicel’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bDQQFqoHzdo&quot;&gt;MonCash&lt;/a&gt;—Haiti’s largest mobile money deployment—has reached nearly 1 million customers and $400 million in yearly transacted value in 2017. This customer base represents a +1500 percent increase from 2015, the same year Digicel rebooted its strategy, marketing approach, product offering, and sales and training force.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 13:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/john-jepsen">John Jepsen</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/elodie-manuel-a751b768/">Elodie Manuel</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-right-role-in-haitis-growing-mobile-sector-4-key-principles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/playing-the-right-role-in-haitis-growing-mobile-sector-4-key-principles.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting ICT Into the Hands of More Women</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 8 is International Women’s Day! To celebrate, we’ll look at a course on women and ICT inclusion developed by USAID Digital Inclusion, mSTAR, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/&quot;&gt;Panoply Digital&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/gender-and-ict-online-course/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to access the course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/catherine-highet-a924094/">Katie Highet</a> &amp; <a href="https://www.panoplydigital.com/our-team/#/alex-tyers-2/">Alex Tyers</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-ICT-Into-the-hands-of-more-women.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-ICT-Into-the-hands-of-more-women.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Resilience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICT for Citizen Engagement and Advocacy: Lessons Learned from Mozambique DIÁLOGO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/mozambique-democratic-governance-support-programme-dgsp&quot;&gt;Mozambique Democratic Governance Programme&lt;/a&gt;, DIÁLOGO, funded by the U.K. Department for International Development, worked with citizens, civil society, local media, and municipal government to engage more effectively on local issues. DIÁLOGO supported innovative solutions, including mobile- and web-based technologies, to amplify the voices of citizens and help governments respond to their demands. The programme ran from 2012 in the five urban municipalities of Beira, Maputo, Nampula, Quelimane, and Tete, and ended last December.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/icts-for-citizen-engagement-and-advocacy-lessons-learned-from-mozambique-dialogo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/icts-for-citizen-engagement-and-advocacy-lessons-learned-from-mozambique-dialogo.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DFID’s Digital Strategy: What Does it Mean for DAI?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the U.K. Department for International Development (DFID) launched its much-anticipated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dfid-digital-strategy-2018-to-2020-doing-development-in-a-digital-world&quot;&gt;Digital Strategy 2018-2020: Doing Development in a Digital World&lt;/a&gt;, outlining its vision and approach towards using technology to have a bigger, faster, and more cost-effective impact on the lives of poor people—particularly those who are marginalised.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/dfids-digital-strategy-what-does-it-mean-for-dai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/dfids-digital-strategy-what-does-it-mean-for-dai.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Past the Blockchain Hype Cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Distributed Ledger Technologies (DLTs), commonly referred to as blockchain applications, are possibly the most talked about innovation of the day. And the most commonly discussed DLT applications are those that involve financial transactions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptocurrency&quot;&gt;cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Fortune Magazine&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/12/26/4-technology-trends-2018/&quot;&gt;recently listed&lt;/a&gt; “The Fintech Renaissance” as the second-most important technology trend of 2018, and with good reason. Last month Bitcoin saw more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockchain.info/charts/n-transactions?timespan=all&quot;&gt;400,000 transactions&lt;/a&gt; per day. Despite warnings of Bitcoin’s volatility, the increased investment in cryptocurrencies is hard to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about all of the other promises of DLTs? There are no shortage of articles written about their impact on data security, the value of smart contracts to create efficient online transactions, and the value of data democratization and transparency through shared ledgers. While there are case studies for each of these promising areas, distributed application developers are in short supply, and active implementations for global development projects are rare. As a result, I get the sense that blockchain may be entering the peak if its hype cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-past-the-blockchain-hype-cycle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-past-the-blockchain-hype-cycle.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why is DAI Investing in a Coding School?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI and Rockville, Maryland-based United Solutions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/dai-hosts-launch-of-new-coding-school-in-montgomery-county&quot;&gt;recently launched&lt;/a&gt; a business called Code Partners to provide classroom instruction in software development. Code Partners will rely on the proven curriculum and teaching methods of Seattle-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codefellows.org/&quot;&gt;Code Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, starting with beginner-level courses in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 10:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/bobby-jefferson">Bobby Jefferson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/why-is-dai-investing-in-a-coding-school.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/why-is-dai-investing-in-a-coding-school.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
