<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:04:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:04:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Sample_JReport_Dashboards.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What the Food Systems Dashboard Taught Me About Data for Decision Making</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I began working with DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration, I have had the chance to explore many of the exciting opportunities presented by our quickly digitizing world. Though I spend most of my time researching how digital tools and service platforms impact economic empowerment and productivity in the agriculture sector, an area that I am eager to explore further is the role of data in policy and decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 07:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-the-food-systems-dashboard-taught-me-about-data-for-decision-making.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-the-food-systems-dashboard-taught-me-about-data-for-decision-making.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Kosovo%20blog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development in the Western Balkans: Kosovo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the talented, globe-trotting &lt;a href=&quot;http://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/&quot;&gt;Chloe Messenger&lt;/a&gt; posted the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-the-western-balkans-bosnia-and-herzegovina.html&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; on DAI’s activities in Bosnia and Herzegovina in our six-part series about digital development in the Western Balkans. If you haven’t read it, you should. If you did, you’ll know that the United Kingdom’s Foreign Commonwealth Office (FCO) funded DAI to map digital ecosystems across the Western Balkans, with a focus on identifying areas where the FCO can support the technology sector in closing the digital skill supply-demand gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bosnia and Herzegovina, check. Next up—Kosovo!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-the-western-balkans-kosovo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-the-western-balkans-kosovo.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Design%20Thinking%20Session_cropped.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Citizen-Centered Governance App Launches in Kabul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This follows an earlier &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that covers our pre-development human-centered design (HCD) phase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Kabul residents have lamented the hours-long queue to access services at their municipal office. Several weeks ago, Kabul Municipality’s solution was hard to ignore. News of a new citizen engagement app was seen displayed on 21 billboards throughout the city, broadcast on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vqLA8GD-33I&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;local television&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outlookafghanistan.net/national_detail.php?post_id=25808&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; sites, shared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/KabulMunicipality/posts/2194828510813555&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, and proudly showcased by the Mayor of Kabul at a launch event that drew 250 attendees and local media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/App%20Billboard-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;App Billboard-03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Advertisement for the Kabul Municipality mobile app.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/addie-ryan/">Addie Ryan</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/trevor-olexy/">Trevor Olexy</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-governance-app-launches-in-kabul.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-governance-app-launches-in-kabul.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/innovation%20averbug.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>6 Ways Innovation and Entrepreneurship Promote Prosperity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not a coincidence that the most developed nations are also the ones with the highest levels of entrepreneurial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/economic-development-innovation-and-entrepreneurship_b_593167b7e4b00573ab57a28b&quot;&gt;activity and innovation&lt;/a&gt;. While starting from a minimal level of development helps the latter two, for example, through basic access to capital and institutional stability, the impact of innovation and entrepreneurship on the economy and society more broadly cannot be overstated. In fact, the impact goes beyond usual suspects such as increased productivity, competitiveness, and job creation, and spills over into areas as diverse as regulation, infrastructure, the environment, and social inclusion. Below I provide a (certainly nonexhaustive) list of six such effects. While every issue deserves an article (or even a book!) of its own, these are brief overviews of each point.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 08:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/averbug?trk=author_mini-profile_title">Andre Averbug</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/6-ways-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-promote-prosperity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/6-ways-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-promote-prosperity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5e29aca9a055b1488ea32c12.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Trends in Hardware to Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the fast pace of technological change, it can be difficult for development practitioners to keep up with tomorrow’s opportunities and risks. Even for more technologically sophisticated members of the community, the focus on technology often overlooks hardware and exclusively focuses on software. As we begin 2020, I wanted to share the five trends in hardware that I think international development stakeholders—implementers, policymakers, civil society, the private sector, and others—should be watching for changes in the near term.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-trends-in-hardware-to-watch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-trends-in-hardware-to-watch.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/person-holding-phone-taking-picture-of-served-food-693267.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How the Digital Marketplace is Changing the Way We Eat</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s the new year and you know what that means…New Year’s resolutions! If you’ve ever uttered the words “New year, new me,” you are far from alone. In 2019, approximately 60 percent of Americans set resolutions and according to a recent survey, the top three were all related to diet and exercise: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/peter-economy/10-top-new-years-resolutions-for-success-happiness-in-2019.html&quot;&gt;eating better, exercising more, and losing weight.&lt;/a&gt; Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While self-help gurus and exercise enthusiasts may tell us that a little self-discipline is all it takes to achieve these goals, research in the field of health and nutrition has shown that one’s food environment—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncceh.ca/sites/default/files/Food_Environments_Public_Health_Practice_Dec_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;the physical, social, economic, cultural, and political factors that impact the accessibility, availability, and adequacy of food within a community&lt;/a&gt;—can have a larger impact on our health outcomes than we think.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/food-and-health-in-a-digital-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/food-and-health-in-a-digital-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/BiH.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development in the Western Balkans: Bosnia and Herzegovina</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, DAI has been working closely with the United Kingdom’s Foreign Commonwealth Office (FCO) to map digital ecosystems across the Western Balkans, and to identify areas where the FCO can support the technology sector in closing the digital skill supply-demand gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our research, we found a region that is well-placed to increase its share of the dividends of global digital expansion and interconnectedness. The Western Balkans boasts promising digital ecosystems, which are well on their way to creating significant economic growth opportunities, but that in many cases need investment and support to do so. With each country having its own specific trajectory and different operating environment, we have created a series of blogs, each outlining key findings from the six countries in the region: Bosnia and Herzegovina, Albania, Serbia, Montenegro, Kosovo, and North Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, beautiful Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/BiH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BiH.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Baščaršija square.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-the-western-balkans-bosnia-and-herzegovina.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-the-western-balkans-bosnia-and-herzegovina.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Ecosystem Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2020.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In our last post from 2019, we reviewed our top posts from the past year. The most-read articles covered a myriad of digital development topics—bridging the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-learned-from-cambodia.html&quot;&gt;digital gender divide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/visualizing-remotely-sensed-data-true-color-and-false-color.html&quot;&gt;visualizing remote sense data&lt;/a&gt;, and insights into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html&quot;&gt;digital lives of Kabul’s residents&lt;/a&gt; to design an open source transparency and citizen participation app. Over the last few years, we’ve seen a sea change in how digital tools and services impact people’s lives globally. Expect 2020 to be no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we get ready for the new decade, here are some topics we’re thinking about when it comes to digital development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/2020-looking-ahead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/2020-looking-ahead.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Trust</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2019%20in%20review.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Year in Review: Top 10 Posts of 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, Digital@DAI published more than 60 posts covering everything from trends in entrepreneurship ecosystems to the importance of user education for digital development programming and building on user insights to develop an open-source transparency and citizen participation application for the municipality of Kabul, Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We featured digital experts from organizations such as Massachusetts Institute for Technology (MIT)’s D-Lab and information sciences and technology experts from across DAI and from our partner organizations. In addition, we featured program work we do with clients including the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; program. Key topics of interest this year included artificial intelligence, agriculture, citizen engagement, decision support, cyber and trust, and ICT policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2019%20in%20review.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;2019 in review.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Eleanor_roosevelt_human_rights_english_-_Resize_548w.jpg-f6b73d.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Resources on Human Rights and Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week marked the 71st anniversary of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/en/universal-declaration-human-rights/&quot;&gt;Universal Declaration of Human Rights&lt;/a&gt; (UNDHR)—a founding document which set out, for the first time, fundamental human rights to be universally protected. Working in international development, most of us are committed to the 30 rights laid out in the UNDHR. As the digital revolution evolves, countries have adopted a myriad of legal frameworks to protect citizens in the digital space. These laws include those focused on privacy and data protection. However, often, these policies are not aligned with the most recent technological advancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the humanitarian and development sectors, we are digitising faster than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://reliefweb.int/report/world/future-financial-assistance-outlook-2030-enaresfr&quot;&gt;legal and ethical frameworks&lt;/a&gt; governing this digitisation. Some fear that the technology sector remains virtually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/EN/NewsEvents/Pages/DisplayNews.aspx?NewsID=25156&quot;&gt;human rights-free zone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 12:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-resources-on-human-rights-and-tech.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-resources-on-human-rights-and-tech.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
