<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:02:09 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:02:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture%20digital%20upskilling%20pwd.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Realizing Inclusive Digital Development Through Boosting the Digital Skills of People Living with Disabilities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five percent of the nearly 1 billion people living with disabilities around the world live at or below the poverty line. Unfortunately, these roughly 250 million people are more likely to face obstacles ranging from finding employment to outright discrimination. However, digital technologies offer the potential to expand employment opportunities for people living with disabilities, allowing them to realize their capabilities, expand their networks, and increase their mobility through digital accessibility. DAI, implementing activities under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP)&lt;/a&gt;, is designing activities that create employment opportunities and support networks for people living with disabilities in countries such as Cambodia and India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its work with the Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) and the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI), DAI recognizes disability as a cross-cutting issue and strives to provide equitable access to digital tools for people with a wide array of abilities, including those who are hard of hearing, have visual impairments, speech impediments, or other learning, developmental, and psychosocial disabilities. DAI’s grantee organizations, consultants, and partners are making significant steps towards digital inclusion through the facilitation of trainings, workshops, and mentoring groups specifically targeted and tailored for people living with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-anderson-2b69391b6/">Jeremy Anderson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/michal-dziekonski-21e67o9NxAA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Technology and Design Podcasts to Explore this Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the weather gets warmer in the Mid-Atlantic region, I’ve been doing my best to get outside more during the day. Podcasts have been a pleasant addition to my walk, runs, and bike rides. Below are five can’t-miss tech podcasts that you should follow—all of which are insightful, engaging, and informative.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%204%20-%20Mali-health-soap-cooperative-hero.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 4—Designing Creative, Women-Centric Technology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Women Connect Challenge is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round of the Challenge, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole/">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-4-designing-creative-women-centric-technology.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-4-designing-creative-women-centric-technology.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Aerobotics%20drone-8057e3.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Q&amp;A: Drone Technology, Climate Adaptation, and Aerobotics—An Interview with Benji Meltzer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Benji%20Meltzer,%20Co-Founder%20and%20CTO%20of%20Aerobotics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Benji Meltzer, Co-Founder and CTO of Aerobotics.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benji Meltzer is the co-founder and chief technology officer of Aerobotics, a South African ag-tech startup that uses artificial intelligence to support the world’s agriculture industry—specifically, farmers in managing their farms, trees, and fruits. We recently spoke with Benji on Aerobotics’ drone technology, the impact of digital tools in climate adaptation and mitigation, and more. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 15:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julian-kesler/">Julian Kesler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-drone-technology-climate-adaptation-and-aerobotics-an-interview-with-benji-meltzer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-drone-technology-climate-adaptation-and-aerobotics-an-interview-with-benji-meltzer.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>AgTech</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/510e45ab-eb96-465c-a85b-eeb1e67d20e2.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Teach Digital Upskilling to Small Firms in Sri Lanka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) is seeking applications from organizations to provide cybersecurity capacity building to small- and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SARDI aims to increase the digital capacity of the private sector and civil society through digital upskilling and by strengthening firms’ ability to engage in digital and ICT policy issues. SARDI implements activities focused on digital upskilling, policy awareness, and cyber capacity-building with entrepreneurs and small firms across South Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermetkabylova/?originalSubdomain=kg">Bermet Kabylova</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-digital-upskilling-sri-lanka.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-digital-upskilling-sri-lanka.html</guid>
        
        <category>SME</category>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%203%20-%20Viamo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 3—Cultivating Women’s Confidence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Women Connect Challenge is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%203%20-%20Viamo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strategy 3 - Viamo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WCC Grantee Viamo works to bridge the gender digital divide and bring vital tools and information to women in Pakistan. Photo: Viamo.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-3-cultivating-womens-confidence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-3-cultivating-womens-confidence.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Jamie%20blog.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Getting Subnational: Combining Large Scale Surveys with Geospatial Data to Produce Better Small Area Estimation (Part I)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collecting granular location data on key socioeconomic indicators for strategic planning is an increasingly important topic in international development. Given the limitations of national-level data, many analysts and policymakers now focus on obtaining subnational data to identify pockets of poverty in a country, select priority sites for poverty alleviation programs, establish subnational benchmarks for monitoring and evaluation purposes, and cross-validate data collected by country governments on indicators such as child mortality and basic literacy rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Jamie%20blog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jamie blog.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 07:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-subnational-combining-large-scale-surveys-with-geospatial-data-to-produce-better-small-area-estimation-part-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-subnational-combining-large-scale-surveys-with-geospatial-data-to-produce-better-small-area-estimation-part-i.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Geospatial Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Marketlinks%20piece.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 2—Creating Economic Opportunities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge (WCC)&lt;/a&gt; is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round of the Challenge, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no revelation that the global economy has been permanently digitized. Now, the internet is not just “the marketplace of ideas” but also the world’s largest marketplace of commodities, crafts, and services. Exclusion from this vast and dynamic market limits one’s opportunities in countless ways—socially and economically. Across the world, many women are unable to engage with the digital economy, and many “real life” economic opportunities—even those traditionally available to women—are moving online, rendering them inaccessible and necessitating new approaches to development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 11:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-2-creating-economic-opportunities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-2-creating-economic-opportunities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Coverage%20of%20USAID%20TradeHub-7bf72c.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Trade in Southern Africa: How Firms Have Adapted to Digital Trade During COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the COVID-19 pandemic, companies in Southern Africa—like elsewhere in the world—have been forced to adapt to remote working: moving their business and communications online, conducting virtual business to business (B2B) meetings, and attending online trade expos and webinars. Between September and December 2021, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration worked with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.satihub.com/&quot;&gt;USAID Southern Africa Trade and Investment Hub&lt;/a&gt; (USAID TradeHub) to understand how these businesses have adapted, what the long-term effects of the pandemic might be, and the support that firms need to adapt to the new normal. During this study, we spoke to three types of firms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exporters:&lt;/strong&gt; A firm—in the case of the USAID TradeHub, in Southern Africa—that sells its goods to a market other than its national domestic market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers&lt;/strong&gt;: An entity (firm, person, or association) that purchases goods from a vendor—in the case of the USAID TradeHub, the vendor is an exporter from the Southern African region. These firms may be based in the region or in the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trade promotion service providers (TPSPs):&lt;/strong&gt; An organization (public or private) that provides services to assist firms to trade—and in many cases, export—their products. Services include supporting firms to meet market entry and buyer requirements, supporting trade investment events where firms showcase their products and meet buyers, identifying demand and potential buyers and creating mutually beneficial relationships between exporters and buyers for long-term business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-trade-in-southern-africa-how-firms-have-adapted-to-digital-trade-during-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-trade-in-southern-africa-how-firms-have-adapted-to-digital-trade-during-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Digital Trade</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture1-be05cb.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Path to a Sustained Network for Women Entrepreneurs in South Asia: Insights from the SARDI Strengthening Women in Tech Symposium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you take your chai or coffee? These opening words welcomed participants from all around the world for the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) Strengthening Symposium, a series of conversations about the most pressing barriers to investment in women-owned enterprises. Covering tremendous ground in 10 hours over four days, this virtual event connected finalists for potential partnerships, inspired applicants by clearly articulating the goals of the activity, and strengthened phase two applications in the process for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-strengthening-women-in-tech-in-south-asia.html&quot;&gt;Strengthening Women in Tech in South Asia&lt;/a&gt; Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SARDI initiative, implemented under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP),&lt;/a&gt;aims to address barriers for women entrepreneurs seeking to expand their business by connecting women across the region for peer-learning opportunities, providing mentorship, investment, and capacity-building support, and building awareness around the ICT policy environment that governs their businesses. The finalists participating in the symposium, ranging from large international organizations to consortia made up of local accelerators and industry associations, are in the running to ultimately design and implement this important regional network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SARDI designed the symposium to bring together the best and brightest, selecting the top 10 out of more than 40 applicants.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christincoster/">Christiy Coster</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-path-to-a-sustained-network-for-women-entrepreneurs-in-south-asia-insights-from-the-sardi-strengthening-women-in-tech-symposium.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-path-to-a-sustained-network-for-women-entrepreneurs-in-south-asia-insights-from-the-sardi-strengthening-women-in-tech-symposium.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
