<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:03:03 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:03:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3891388b-1a22-493b-bce0-2847a0ee9ca0.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>What is Agile? Part Two: A Primer on Different Frameworks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed in part one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-one-the-story-behind-the-buzzword.html&quot;&gt;this series&lt;/a&gt;, agile is an umbrella term that encapsulates a number of frameworks, strategies, and tools. In this second installment, we dive a bit deeper into what agile is in practice by highlighting some of the most common frameworks used by agile teams. This primer on agile frameworks and methods will by no means be comprehensive (there are entire courses, websites, and certifications dedicated to each), but it can serve as a good starting point for better understanding which flavor of agile might be best suited to your teams’ needs if you are considering adopting agile in your organization. This post will cover two of the most popular types of agile in more depth: Scrum and Kanban. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wrike.com/project-management-guide/faq/what-are-the-different-types-of-agile-methodologies/&quot;&gt;several others&lt;/a&gt; that are widely used as well, but these two have many components that can be flexible and adaptable for use in non-software development contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Samantha Weinberg
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-two-a-primer-on-different-agile-frameworks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/what-is-agile-part-two-a-primer-on-different-agile-frameworks.html</guid>
        
        <category>agile</category>
        
        <category>software development</category>
        
        <category>Agile Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/arpad-czapp-wS250FJl5Uw-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Rise of TikTok: How One App is Making Waves in the Global Development Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TikTok—the popular short video-sharing app—is now the fastest-growing social media platform on the internet. Rivaling companies such as Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and Netflix, the controversial platform has amassed more than 2 billion &lt;a href=&quot;https://sensortower.com/blog/tiktok-downloads-2-billion&quot;&gt;downloads&lt;/a&gt; in more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hootsuite.com/tiktok-stats/&quot;&gt;200 countries&lt;/a&gt; and 75 languages in just the past four years. And while the app has had success in diverse markets, its principles have been challenged by individuals and governments globally. In 2018, the Indonesian government enacted a one-week &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-indonesia-bytedance-ban/indonesia-bans-chinese-video-app-tik-tok-for-inappropriate-content-idUSKBN1JU0K8&quot;&gt;restriction on the app&lt;/a&gt; due to allegations of inappropriate content and blasphemy. The Indian government banned the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/01/15/957371287/a-look-at-the-fallout-of-tiktok-ban-in-india&quot;&gt;in 2020&lt;/a&gt; on the grounds of geopolitical rationale. Former U.S. President Donald Trump attempted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2020/08/07/why-is-the-trump-administration-banning-tiktok-and-wechat/&quot;&gt;ban TikTok&lt;/a&gt; due to U.S. national security concerns. Yet amidst these challenges, TikTok’s popularity continues to proliferate amongst diverse communities and influence international markets and the future development of domestic internet companies overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/solen-feyissa-QKEeVYu0d7U-unsplash%20(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;solen-feyissa-QKEeVYu0d7U-unsplash (1).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 14:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Afua Owusu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-rise-of-tiktok-how-one-app-is-making-waves-in-the-global-development-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/markus-spiske-Skf7HxARcoc-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Is Intellectual Property Ready for Blockchain?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With its relatively low maintenance cost, increased transparency, reduced administrative burden, and resilience to fraud, blockchain is a versatile technology deployed in many sectors and businesses. So, what is blockchain, and could this disruptive technology have any application for managing intellectual property (IP) rights such as patents, copyrights, trademarks, industrial designs, and more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/markus-spiske-Skf7HxARcoc-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;markus-spiske-Skf7HxARcoc-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Blockchain Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/6555466127_96972a78fa_o.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Choosing the Right Digital Platform for Learning and Training Needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the world familiarizes itself with online learning in our COVID-19-affected times, we have been exposed to many seamless ways to experience remote learning. However, when we switch roles—from learning to developing different types of courses—this generalized exposure and all the technical terms for ways digital learning material is presented can become overwhelming. This blog explains the two most common platforms used to present eLearning material: Content Management Systems (CMS) and Learning Management Systems (LMS). Understanding these ways to structure and present eLearning material is key to determining which is more beneficial for a project’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anne Hand
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/choosing-the-right-digital-platform-for-learning-and-training-needs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/choosing-the-right-digital-platform-for-learning-and-training-needs.html</guid>
        
        <category>eLearning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/35601065925_5c9a9376dd_c.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Adults Teaching Children Digital Literacy in a Digitally Growing Society</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital literacy goes beyond knowing how to create a TikTok account. True digital literacy is the ability to find, evaluate, comprehend, and use technology. Engaging with online content while simultaneously knowing the risks and limitations of technology is vital when participating in the digital world. Children today are using technology, now more than ever, to connect with peers and explore, search, and create content. Analyzing information, identifying patterns, and forming educated conclusions are invaluable digital skills for children to start building. Below are essential topics to cover when introducing children to digital literacy:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 13:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Temi Olatunji
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/adults-teaching-children-digital-literacy-in-a-digitally-growing-society.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/adults-teaching-children-digital-literacy-in-a-digitally-growing-society.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/blockchain-3019120_1920.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Blockchain: Are We Beyond the Peak of The Hype Cycle?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A combination of mainstream media attention and Elon Musk’s Twitter feed has reignited the public interest in distributed ledger technologies, commonly referred to as the blockchain. CDA is no stranger to this technology; check out our blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/blockchain-for-development-part-1-understanding-the-tech.html&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; and how we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-past-the-blockchain-hype-cycle.html&quot;&gt;applied these concepts in-house&lt;/a&gt;. Blockchain-based applications leverage technology’s ability to decrease transaction costs, maintain immutable records, and provide users with privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, international donors and the private sector have used blockchain across financial inclusion, digital government, and supply chain management. Recently, we revisited blockchain’s role in these various technical areas to assess its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/research/methodologies/gartner-hype-cycle&quot;&gt;hype cycle&lt;/a&gt; and long-term deployment sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connor-mackenzie/">Connor MacKenzie</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/blockchain-are-we-beyond-the-peak-of-the-hype-cycle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/blockchain-are-we-beyond-the-peak-of-the-hype-cycle.html</guid>
        
        <category>Blockchain Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Identity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/0_HVcjTHN6PjiszK0H.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Can Regulators Keep up with Artificial Intelligence?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) presents one of the most difficult challenges to traditional regulation. Three decades ago, software was programmed; today, it’s trained. AI itself is not one technology or singular development. It is a bundle of technologies whose decision-making mode is often not fully understood even by AI developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI solutions can help address critical global challenges and deliver significant benefits; however, the technology could lead to unforeseeable outcomes absent clear regulations and ethical guidelines. AI can have damaging repercussions for data privacy, information, and cybersecurity, providing hackers with ways to access sensitive personal data, hijack systems, or manipulate devices connected to the Internet. Self-learning algorithms already anticipate human needs and wants, govern our newsfeeds, and drive our cars. How can we ensure that this technology benefits people widely? If AI and autonomous machines play a crucial role in our everyday lives, what sort of normative and ethical frameworks should guide their design?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 15:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/can-regulators-keep-up-with-artificial-intelligence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/can-regulators-keep-up-with-artificial-intelligence.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>AI Bias</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Internet%20Connectivity%20diagram%20Blog%20Pic%201.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Emerging Technologies Provide New Opportunities to Bridge the Digital Divide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;New investments in emerging technologies offer transformational opportunities in developing countries—particularly for rural and remote populations benefiting from internet connectivity. This blog highlights three developments for potential donor interventions to work with the private sector, governments, and users to bridge the digital divide. These efforts may be complementary to planned or completed infrastructure, specifically for last-mile connectivity solutions to expand inclusive and affordable access for people across various regions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alexander Sekhniashvili
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-technologies-provide-new-opportunities-for-bridging-the-digital-divide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-technologies-provide-new-opportunities-for-bridging-the-digital-divide.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        <category>Digital Platforms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sound%20blog%20photo%203.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Asia Accelerator Cultivates Digital Skills for Cambodia’s Creative Sector</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread digitalization has revolutionized almost every industry, including music and sound production. While rarely the focus of digital development initiatives, creative entrepreneurs such as artists and musicians in emerging economies have also found themselves scrambling to adapt to the ever-changing technology and social media landscapes. As such, this year, with funding from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/Digital_Asia_Accelerator_Fact_Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s Digital Asia Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; (DAA) initiative and as a part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digital-development/digital-connectivity-cybersecurity-partnership&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesoundinitiative.com/&quot;&gt;The Sound Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (TSI)—a vocational program for musicians—launched the “Music 4.0” program to support Cambodian entrepreneurs striving to excel in this dynamic industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/sound%20blog%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sound blog 1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Source: TSI.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole/">Kendra Poole</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/irene-hang-81b817194/">Hangveng Horng</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/music-4-dot-0-digital-skills-for-the-creative-sector.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/music-4-dot-0-digital-skills-for-the-creative-sector.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/50267038282_392bac077d_o-843190.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New Report Offers Guidance to Support Agriculture Market Systems Actors During COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital tools and services such as short message services (SMS), digitally enabled extension services, and artificial intelligence have helped market system actors in developing countries overcome common challenges in the agriculture sector, such as accessing weather information and diagnosing pest or disease outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openknowledge.worldbank.org/bitstream/handle/10986/35216/9781464816574.pdf?sequence=2&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&quot;&gt;documented value&lt;/a&gt; of these innovations, uptake of digital agriculture technology still is not widespread. A lack of affordable and accessible technologies, poor connectivity, high costs of data, and social stigmas around digital technology can be major barriers to potential users. With COVID-19 making digital connectivity critical to economic activities, development stakeholders have spent the past year and a half assessing the relationship between the pandemic and the adoption and use of digital agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-report-offers-guidance-to-support-agriculture-market-systems-actors-during-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-report-offers-guidance-to-support-agriculture-market-systems-actors-during-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Mobile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
