<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:40:42 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:40:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAA.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Digital Inclusion Challenge Seeks to Advance Skills of Women-Led Firms Across Southeast Asia, Mongolia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) is launching the Women’s Digital Inclusion Challenge to find partners across the Southeast Asia region that have delivered successful digital upskilling programs for women and micro-, small and medium-sized enterprises (MSMEs). The Challenge targets organizations looking to scale their operations to reach new countries and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 16:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jirada-phetlam">Jirada Phetlam</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kate-heuisler-1745326">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-inclusion-challenge-seeks-to-advance-skills-of-women-led-smes-across-southeast-asia-and-mongolia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-inclusion-challenge-seeks-to-advance-skills-of-women-led-smes-across-southeast-asia-and-mongolia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202022-01-26%20143227.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>CDA Insights 2022: Toward Ethical Artificial Intelligence in International Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we conceived the idea of research on ethics and artificial intelligence (AI), we were—and still are—inundated with news about the detrimental impacts of AI from around the globe. Concerns about facial recognition technologies making false identifications and discriminatory hiring tools were amongst the many themes and headlines we saw. DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration does its best to stay updated with the latest trends in technology and recognizes the benefits of automation and AI. However, these recent disturbing trends made it clear that the development sector needs to exercise greater caution when building and applying AI tools. AI is being adopted quickly in development, and we must act to prevent the adverse effects of these tools in the communities we work alongside.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 14:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cda-insights-2022-toward-ethical-artificial-intelligence-in-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cda-insights-2022-toward-ethical-artificial-intelligence-in-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>AI Bias</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/francois-le-nguyen-pouTfHUG430-unsplash-f63dbf.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Let’s Talk Fashion: How Digital Technology Can Support the Circular Economy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fashion industry drives a significant part of the global economy. Valued north of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.uri.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1026&amp;amp;context=mgdr&quot;&gt;$3 trillion&lt;/a&gt;, the fashion business—defined by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unfashionalliance.org/&quot;&gt;United Nations Alliance&lt;/a&gt; as clothing, leather, and footwear—accounts for 2 percent of the world’s gross domestic product. The sector responsible for employing more than 300 million people worldwide—many of whom are women—and providing goods indispensable to human welfare is also responsible for around 8 to 10 percent of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/340635670_The_environmental_price_of_fast_fashion&quot;&gt;carbon emissions&lt;/a&gt;, nearly 20 percent of global &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.un.org/en/story/2019/03/1035161&quot;&gt;wastewater production&lt;/a&gt;, and about 9 percent of microplastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fashionrevolution.org/our-clothes-shed-microfibres-heres-what-we-can-do/&quot;&gt;losses&lt;/a&gt; to the ocean annually. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ellenmacarthurfoundation.org/topics/circular-economy-introduction/overview&quot;&gt;circular economy in design&lt;/a&gt; that tackles climate change and biodiversity loss is based on three principles: eliminate, circulate, and regenerate. Although retail companies have increased their sustainable investments over the past five years, the progression remains slow in shifting to transparent and sustainable fashion standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While climate change threatens all populations, communities in low- and middle-income countries feel its impact first and worst. The onset of the COVID-19 crisis has powered global eco-awakenings; consumers are now, more than ever, urging fashion players to be more socially and environmentally responsible through all stages of the fashion production life cycle. While far from the target of taking urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts, digital technologies offer innovative solutions to tackling climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/francois-le-nguyen-pouTfHUG430-unsplash-f63dbf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;francois-le-nguyen-pouTfHUG430-unsplash-f63dbf.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Francois Le Nguyen, Unsplash.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 23:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Afua Owusu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lets-talk-fashion-how-digital-technology-can-support-the-circular-economy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lets-talk-fashion-how-digital-technology-can-support-the-circular-economy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Digital Identity</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>E-Commerce</category>
        
        <category>Digital Economy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202022-01-12%20010731.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>5 Secret Sauces for Your Next Digital Safety Campaign: Insights from Thailand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/five-fresh-tips-to-make-digital-safety-cool-again-a-case-study-from-thailand.html&quot;&gt;Five Fresh Tips to Make Digital Safety Cool Again: A Case Study from Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed lessons learned from implementing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://th.usembassy.gov/united-states-celebrates-young-leaders-of-digital-literacy-in-thailand/&quot;&gt;‘Wai Kid Digital’&lt;/a&gt; Challenge, a series of virtual training bootcamps with university students on digital safety and creative video production. Looking back two months after the activity wrapped up, here are our top suggestions for your next digital safety campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Build private sector partnerships that create shared value&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use hybrid approaches to engage Gen Z&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Embed experience-based learning and networking opportunities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Localize your content to pave way for sustainability&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Evolve your approach to capture the real story&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Digital Asia Accelerator, part of the U.S. Government’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, partnered with Facebook Thailand and Love Frankie (a local social change agency) to design and launch the Challenge. We then collaborated with nearly 400 university students around the country to demystify digital safety and educate the public about digital safety and identity, positive online communication, news literacy, and critical thinking through creative videos.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 01:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thaniya-theungsang/?originalSubdomain-th">Thaniya Theungsang</a> and Panita Plangprayoon and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jirada-phetlam/?originalSubdomain=th">Jirada Phetlam</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thanasinee/?originalSubdomain=th">Thanasinee Auksonthongsutti</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-secret-sauces-for-your-next-digital-safety-campaign-insights-from-thailand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-secret-sauces-for-your-next-digital-safety-campaign-insights-from-thailand.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Copy%20of%20DIGITAL@DAI%20(2).png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we head into 2022 and reflect on two years of a global pandemic, new ways of connecting with colleagues and partners, and new areas of work, we at DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) feel as though we’ve been both sprinting and diving deep at the same time. The last couple of years gave us thrilling new work, new research areas, and opportunities to use both established and emerging digital tools in ways we could not have imagined. Below are five themes and trends that are likely to impact our work in 2022 and beyond. I welcome your additional thoughts and ideas as we explore these throughout the year on the &lt;em&gt;Digital@DAI&lt;/em&gt; blog; tweet us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/daiglobal&quot;&gt;@DAIGlobal&lt;/a&gt; or email us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ict@dai.com&quot;&gt;ict@dai.com&lt;/a&gt; to engage in the conversation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Copy%20of%20DIGITAL@DAI%20(2).png&quot; alt=&quot;Copy of DIGITAL@DAI (2).png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 09:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2022.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2022.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>AI Bias</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DIGITAL@DAI%20(1).png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Year in Review: Top 10 Posts of 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I do at the end of each year, I’d like to take the opportunity to reflect on the topics that were most read by you, our readers. This year had many ups and downs, from moments where we felt the pandemic might allow us to return to some sense of normalcy, followed by periods where we experienced continued isolation. The COVID-19 pandemic highlighted the continued importance of digital technology, reliable internet connection, and digital literacy as critical components to education, business, and family engagements. We’ve also seen the potential for the digital transformation that is underway around the globe to improve our lives &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; disrupt them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Digital@DAI, we covered global trends in digital tool usage and key takeaways from work we are implementing globally. In total, we published 60 blogs that amassed more than 100,000 page views and covered topics from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-is-looking-up-satellites-for-development.html&quot;&gt;satellites for development&lt;/a&gt; to providing access to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/meaningful-connectivity-providing-access-to-life-enhancing-digital-services.html?utm_source=daidotcom&quot;&gt;life-enhancing digital services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In past years, we’ve summarized the top 10 posts of the year. This year, we noticed a pattern that I think is worth highlighting, especially given the renewed importance and pace of learning in the digital sector that the COVID-19 response requires. While readers enjoyed our most recent posts, our posts from previous years were quite popular, as well! Below, we feature the most read blogs published in 2021 and the most read blogs of 2021 overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DIGITAL@DAI%20(1).png&quot; alt=&quot;DIGITAL@DAI (1).png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 10:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/krista-baptista">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>, and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/afua-owusu/">Afua Owusu</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Miranda%20Blog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Hidden Costs of Online Shopping</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember when my family first got an Amazon Prime membership. At the time, I was a freshman in college living on campus with no car. A trip to the grocery store was a half-day adventure involving multiple bus rides, weaving through weekend shoppers, and then lugging all my purchases back to my room. This all changed with two-day shipping. With Amazon, everything I could possibly need or want—ranging from toiletries and groceries to textbooks and school supplies—was at my fingertips with just a few clicks and two-day delivery. My half-day quests for essentials turned into a five-minute walk to the on-campus post office.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Miranda Walls
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-hidden-costs-of-online-shopping.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-hidden-costs-of-online-shopping.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital economy</category>
        
        <category>E-Commerce</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/MDI%20Blog%20Photo.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building Resilience Against Disinformation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of user-generated content enabled by improved connectivity and access to digital platforms is unlocking new economic opportunities, while also fomenting disinformation and falsehoods with potentially deleterious effects on society. Misinformation and disinformation can erode the trust and credibility of our public institutions, inflict financial harm, embolden nefarious actors, and jeopardize governance. While misinformation and disinformation are not new phenomena, the emergence of new digital platforms has enabled accelerated proliferation and reach, with implications across diverse sectors. Misinformation and disinformation can be omnipresent and not limited to politics, as they target value chains, consumers, and minority-owned businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 13:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/komal-bazaz-smith/">Komal Bazaz Smith</a>, and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/priya-sethi/">Priya Sethi</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/building-resilience-against-disinformation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/building-resilience-against-disinformation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Misinformation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Literacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/LastMileConnectivity2.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Meaningful Connectivity: Providing Access to Life-Enhancing Digital Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lack of digital connectivity is a prelude to exclusion in today’s rapidly changing world. Yet, more than 600 million people worldwide remain uncovered by mobile networks and broadband services. COVID-19 exacerbated the effects of this deep digital divide that continues to leave many communities disconnected, uninformed, and without access to life-enhancing digital services. Internet connectivity in the most remote places is essential to ensure that the most vulnerable populations do not get left behind. Moreover, these communities need effective connectivity that is consistent, safe, reliable, and accessible with enough bandwidth to allow for information access, news, government resources, telehealth, and educational instruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/LastMileConnectivity2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;LastMileConnectivity2.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Women entrepreneurs accessing digital services in Guna, Madhya Pradesh, India. Photo: Digital Empowerment Foundation.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riabovalexander/">Alexander Riabov</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/meaningful-connectivity-providing-access-to-life-enhancing-digital-services.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/meaningful-connectivity-providing-access-to-life-enhancing-digital-services.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>digital divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/251529551_3057514881152684_6929689380512171727_n.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The AI Age Presents New Challenges in Cybersecurity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) can be used to strengthen cybersecurity by detecting cyber threats more quickly and effectively. Imagine, for instance, if embedded malware meant to disrupt a hospital system’s operation was detected within minutes of its installation, rather than after it disrupted access to electronic medical health records, delaying medical treatments? In such a scenario, the use of AI to detect a cyber-attack could literally mean life or death. Despite these benefits, the use of AI also introduces its own set of cybersecurity vulnerabilities that bad actors can exploit. For example, it can amplify the exploitation of vulnerabilities across digital systems. Additionally, the use of Internet of Things (IoT) coupled with AI will further densify the potential cyber-attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/webinar-cybersecurity-challenges-in-the-ai-age.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/webinar-cybersecurity-challenges-in-the-ai-age.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
