<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 10:13:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 10:13:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1579368606627.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Shaping History Series: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation—Dr. Joy Buolamwini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aligned with the Center for Digital Acceleration’s commitment to fostering equity and inclusion within our team and the broader international development sector, Digital@DAI is launching a new series during Black History Month called Shaping History: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation. The series aims to spotlight racially diverse leaders in the tech space at home and in the countries where we work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, meet our first profile subject: Dr. Joy Buolamwini.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 08:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Inta Plostins
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-dr-joy-buolamwini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-dr-joy-buolamwini.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Shaping History Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Security.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: SARDI MSME Cybersecurity Awareness Campaign Design and Implementation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) activity is seeking applications from organizations interested in conducting an awareness campaign for micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) in Bangladesh to help them improve their personal and business digital hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Security.png&quot; alt=&quot;Security.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo: Pixelcreatures, Pixabay.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 20:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermetkabylova/?originalSubdomain=kg">Bermet Kabylova</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-cybersecurity-awareness-campaign-design-and-implementation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-cybersecurity-awareness-campaign-design-and-implementation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/20181023_2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Help Assess Guatemala’s Digital Financial Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; seeks applications from firms to assess market conditions and identify gaps and opportunities in the use of financial services in Guatemala among low-income and marginalized populations, particularly women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-income and marginalized populations, especially women, are more susceptible to shocks, whether economic, climate, or other, leading them to fall into poverty and sometimes migrate within or outside of their country. Often, individuals lack digital and financial literacy and skills, which prevents them from using financial services to help them better deal with shocks and build their resilience and incomes. This activity will better assess demand and supply-side market conditions to understand Guatemalan customer segments’ financial needs better. The partner will also develop a new or improved financial service prototype to target customer needs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-falso-99474a103/">Andrea Falso</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-help-assess-guatemalas-digital-financial-services.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-help-assess-guatemalas-digital-financial-services.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Intro%20Blog%20-%20EAI.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“All technology has potential when modeled in the vacuum of our whiteboards and proposals,” remarks Revi Sterling, Director of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge&lt;/a&gt; (WCC). Shrewdly cutting to the chase, Sterling adds: “[But] rural smallholder farmer women do not live in vacuums.” In other words: for digital technologies to be part of any development solution, practitioners must first address the myriad of real-life barriers and inequities surrounding technology use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agrilinks.org/post/why-women-arent-using-your-ag-app&quot;&gt;recent blog&lt;/a&gt; on the low uptake of digital agriculture applications by women, Sterling explains how digital development programming often fails to grapple with the inherent gender biases imbued in many software platforms and services. Many digital interventions also fail to investigate the unique social and cultural circumstances that may bar women from participation in the digital sphere. Social norms surrounding intersectional identities such as class, disability, caste, indigenous identity, gender identity, sexual orientation, language minority, and other factors can further intensify these barriers to technology access and use. These oversights in program or software design often unintentionally exacerbate poverty and inequality, deepening the &lt;a href=&quot;https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/8cf03f8fcb374af8849cb95dc5e47931&quot;&gt;gender digital divide&lt;/a&gt; and undermining the development effort’s good intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 02:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-introducing-strategies-for-closing-the-gender-digital-divide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-introducing-strategies-for-closing-the-gender-digital-divide.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Global%20Forced%20Displacement.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Technology and Displacement: The Role of Digital Tools Among Displaced Persons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/in-honor-of-womens-history-month-exploring-the-gender-digital-divide.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; from last March, I wrote about the reality of the gender digital divide, in which I noted the difference in digital access and usage among women and men globally and the lost potential that results from women’s lack of access. When able to access, understand, and leverage digital tools, women can use these tools to better their economic outcomes and those of their families and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, women are not the only group facing the reality of the digital divide. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/en/content/digital-cooperation-roadmap/assets/pdf/Roadmap_for_Digital_Cooperation_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;United Nations Secretary-General’s Roadmap for Digital Cooperation,&lt;/a&gt; a report presenting strategies for inclusive, equitable adoption of digital technologies, notes some of the many other groups affected by similar challenges, including “migrants, refugees, internally displaced persons, older persons, young people, children, persons with disabilities, rural populations, and indigenous peoples.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/technology-and-displacement-the-role-of-digital-tools-among-displaced-persons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/technology-and-displacement-the-role-of-digital-tools-among-displaced-persons.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/South%20Asia.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: SARDI India MSME Tech Policy Fellowship Program</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) activity seeks applications from organizations interested in arranging one-year fellowships for up to five fellows in up to five different Indian think tanks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermetkabylova/?originalSubdomain=kg">Bermet Kabylova</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-india-msme-tech-policy-fellowship-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-india-msme-tech-policy-fellowship-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        <category>MSMEs</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/agriculture%202.svg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID and the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation to Assess the Implications of Artificial Intelligence and Automation on Employment and Inclusive Economic Development in Agri-Food Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) technologies advance and potential benefits continue to grow, much remains unknown on the long-term implications AI and ML will have on employment and inclusive economic development in agri-food systems in lower- and middle-income countries. Various studies conducted by global consulting firms predict a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/artificial-intelligence/notes-from-the-AI-frontier-modeling-the-impact-of-ai-on-the-world-economy&quot;&gt;14 to 16 percent&lt;/a&gt; increase in gross domestic product growth due to AI, with a significantly higher expected benefit for developed economies. With increased interest and investment in AI, the automation revolution appears to be driven and owned primarily by a small group of multinational companies, governments, and universities. By understanding who is likely to gain and who is likely to be left out, donors and governments can develop more responsible and inclusive programming that considers how these technologies will translate onto agri-food systems of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Feed the Future priority countries and the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation’s (BMGF) focus regions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lilyana-gabrielse-8bb40b1bb/">Lilyana Gabriesle</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-and-the-bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-assess-the-implications-of-artificial-intelligence-and-automation-on-employment-and-inclusive-economic-development-in-agri-food-systems.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-and-the-bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-assess-the-implications-of-artificial-intelligence-and-automation-on-employment-and-inclusive-economic-development-in-agri-food-systems.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital agriculture</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fda43a06-c94d-474f-8951-95a95c71c949.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: ProICT Seeks Technical and Policy Advisory Support for ASEAN AI Research Brief and Roadmap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ ProICT activity seeks a consultant or team of consultants to write a research brief and a subsequent artificial intelligence (AI) roadmap for member countries of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN). The research brief and AI roadmap will be shared at two convenings—or as required to incorporate substantive feedback and generate buy-in—and will be used to regularly and proactively solicit and incorporate input from relevant stakeholders. Proposals will be accepted from organizations, firms, or independent consultants.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 12:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-kourgialis-bbb6a150/">Jonathan Kourgialis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-proict-technical-and-policy-advisory-support-for-asean-ai-research-brief-and-roadmap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-proict-technical-and-policy-advisory-support-for-asean-ai-research-brief-and-roadmap.html</guid>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        <category>RFP</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAA.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Digital Inclusion Challenge Seeks to Advance Skills of Women-Led Firms Across Southeast Asia, Mongolia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) is launching the Women’s Digital Inclusion Challenge to find partners across the Southeast Asia region that have delivered successful digital upskilling programs for women and micro-, small and medium-sized enterprises (MSMEs). The Challenge targets organizations looking to scale their operations to reach new countries and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 16:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jirada-phetlam">Jirada Phetlam</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kate-heuisler-1745326">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-inclusion-challenge-seeks-to-advance-skills-of-women-led-smes-across-southeast-asia-and-mongolia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-inclusion-challenge-seeks-to-advance-skills-of-women-led-smes-across-southeast-asia-and-mongolia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Screenshot%202022-01-26%20143227.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>CDA Insights 2022: Toward Ethical Artificial Intelligence in International Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we conceived the idea of research on ethics and artificial intelligence (AI), we were—and still are—inundated with news about the detrimental impacts of AI from around the globe. Concerns about facial recognition technologies making false identifications and discriminatory hiring tools were amongst the many themes and headlines we saw. DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration does its best to stay updated with the latest trends in technology and recognizes the benefits of automation and AI. However, these recent disturbing trends made it clear that the development sector needs to exercise greater caution when building and applying AI tools. AI is being adopted quickly in development, and we must act to prevent the adverse effects of these tools in the communities we work alongside.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 14:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Gratiana Fu
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cda-insights-2022-toward-ethical-artificial-intelligence-in-international-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cda-insights-2022-toward-ethical-artificial-intelligence-in-international-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>AI Bias</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
