<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 13:18:14 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 13:18:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take it to the Farmer: Behind the Scenes of the Fall Armyworm Tech Prize Co-Creation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with human-centered design and lean startup, co-creation is an approach arising to prominence in the development lexicon over the past five years. Some of us (myself included) have used “co-creation” without  understanding what it means, simply assuming it was an event that brings together a variety of partners to brainstorm ideas to solve a problem. Only when I attended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fallarmywormtech.challenges.org/&quot;&gt;Fall Armyworm Tech Prize&lt;/a&gt; co-creation workshop June 26–29 in Kampala, Uganda, did I grasp the nuances of co-creation and realize the significant benefits it holds for the end users of co-created products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/FAW_img1_SM.png&quot; alt=&quot;FAW_img1_SM.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo Credit: DAI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seeking-innovators&quot;&gt;Seeking Innovators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall armyworm is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/food-chain-crisis/how-we-work/plant-protection/fallarmyworm/en/&quot;&gt;devastating pest&lt;/a&gt; that can destroy potentially millions of tons of crop yield across Africa, drastically reducing the incomes of smallholder farmers and those who rely on crops for their livelihoods. In response to the 2016 fall armyworm outbreak, Feed the Future and partners &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.landolakes.org/&quot;&gt;Land O’Lakes International Development&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundationfar.org/&quot;&gt;Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research (FFAR)&lt;/a&gt;, created the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/what-we-do/agriculture-and-food-security/increasing-food-security-through-feed-future/fall-armyworm&quot;&gt;Fall Armyworm Tech Prize&lt;/a&gt; competition. This open event has attracted developers of digital tools and approaches from across Africa and beyond, each vying to provide the best solution for procuring timely, targeted information that smallholder farmers can use to identify, remedy, and track incidence of fall armyworm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty &lt;a href=&quot;https://fallarmywormtech.challenges.org/finalists-2/&quot;&gt;finalists&lt;/a&gt;—out of 228 applicants—were selected to attend the workshop, participate in feedback sessions about their prototypes, and further develop these for the next phase of the competition. The workshop also convened partners from the private sector and government; experts and mentors in agriculture, technology, and business development; and, most importantly, future users of these new tools and approaches—the farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;collaboration-overtakes-competition&quot;&gt;Collaboration Overtakes Competition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rudimentary understanding of co-creation within the prize process wrongfully pushed me to assume that although co-creation encourages collaboration, at its core this prize is a &lt;em&gt;competition&lt;/em&gt;, and with five prizes totaling $400,000 on the line, the idea of “co”-creating could only be taken so far. I was very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-creation creates an environment that &lt;em&gt;unites&lt;/em&gt; competitors. Our three-and-a-half days were filled with sessions that unpacked the problem of fall armyworm, incorporated human-centered design in prototype development, developed business plans (including fundraising, costing models, and communications), considered ways to measure impact, and hosted practice sales pitches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sessions helped the finalists understand how to improve their ideas, but what happened behind the scenes was where the spirit of co-creation really took flight. It seemed that competition was replaced by a strong focus on &lt;em&gt;collaboration&lt;/em&gt; to solve an endemic problem. This might be at a coffee break where someone recommended a data analytics tool to integrate into a potential solution, or at a lunch where two finalist groups decided to join forces—the heartbeat of co-creation emerged when I least expected it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Several finalists proposed digital tools that use machine learning to help farmers and extension workers identify the pest. Early on, they realized that their tools lacked the ample imagery needed to reliably recognize fall armyworm. In response, those innovators brainstormed over dinner how to create an image bank to train their classification models. These finalists might not win the top prize, but this co-creative effort could ultimately result in a tool that decreases or prevents damage to farm yields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Day 2, finalists pitched their ideas to partners, potential investors, and farmers at an exhibition-like  Marketplace. Many finalists used this opportunity to have farmers test their digital tools and provide feedback on how to make them more user friendly and helpful given farmers’ technological constraints. Continual interaction with farmers during the workshop allowed participants to appreciate farmers’ needs as they built and iterated their tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, on the last day, one of the finalists collected the phone numbers of the others and created a WhatsApp group for all to bounce ideas off one another and share approaches during the remainder of the prize process, which concludes in mid-November when our five winners will be announced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together these examples embody the key to a successful co-creation: &lt;strong&gt;Give people the space and time to go beyond a structured program and work together in their own way to achieve a common goal.&lt;/strong&gt; As we move toward the next phase of the prize process, I look forward to seeing how the solutions are fueled by this collaboration and farmer engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before he died at age 95, agricultural development pioneer Dr. Norman Borlaug made a request to developers of technology: “Take it to the farmer.” FFAR Executive Director Dr. Sally Rockey (pictured above) cited this quote in her closing remarks. This sentiment was taken to heart by the Fall Armyworm Tech Prize finalists, who looked past the prize money to focus on co-creating solutions alongside some of the very farmers who need their help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/FAW_img2.png&quot; alt=&quot;FAW_img2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo Credit: Addmaya&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/take-it-to-the-farmer-behind-the-scenes-of-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-co-creation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/take-it-to-the-farmer-behind-the-scenes-of-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-co-creation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Co-creation</category>
        
        <category>Fall Armyworm</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Time of Change. And Reflection.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember exactly what I was doing when the grenade went off up the street—probably brushing my teeth or something mundane like that. I was halfway through my two-week visit to Ethiopia and looking forward to getting out in the field. I was also completely unaware of what had just happened. It was a sobering day. I spent all afternoon watching the news. First one person confirmed dead, then two. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/06/23/622855931/grenade-attack-tears-through-rally-for-ethiopian-prime-minister&quot;&gt;One-hundred and fifty or so wounded&lt;/a&gt;. Fear on the faces of a populace that had recently been so full of hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Bomb-attack-Addis-Ababa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bomb-attack-Addis-Ababa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Image credit: AddisBiz.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 09:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rachel Clad
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-time-of-change-and-reflection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-time-of-change-and-reflection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration Featured on Podcast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thsishcd.com/&quot;&gt;This is HCD&lt;/a&gt;—a podcast that explores what human-centered design (HCD) looks like in practice—featured DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-launches-human-centered-design-whitepaper.html&quot;&gt;work in Guatemala&lt;/a&gt; on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisishcd.com/episodes/24-adam-fiveson-using-a-human-centered-design-approach-to-design-foreign-aid-programs/&quot;&gt;most recent episode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog%20header.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;blog header.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 18:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-featured-on-this-is-hcd-podcast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-featured-on-this-is-hcd-podcast.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Health in International Development: Using Tried &amp; Tested Technology Innovatively</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Abi-7981e9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Abi-7981e9.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently took part in the DAI panel discussion on “Digital Health in International Development: Current Realities and Future Trends” in London. It delivered fascinating perspectives from across the health, tech, and development sectors. Here’s a few key points I shared during the discussion and hope to stimulate a continued conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Abi Gleek
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-health-in-international-development-using-tried-and-tested-technology-innovatively.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-health-in-international-development-using-tried-and-tested-technology-innovatively.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deadline Extended! Apply Now: Support USAID Missions to Improve Broadband Connectivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project has extended the deadline to &lt;strong&gt;July 3&lt;/strong&gt; for proposals from interested organizations to help the U.S. Agency for International Development implement the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/Better_Connectivity_Better_Programs_April2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Better Connectivity, Better Programs: How to Implement a Demand Aggregation Program (How-to Guide)&lt;/a&gt;. The initial Request for Proposals (RFP) and related information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answers to RFP questions were emailed to interested offerors and can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1GU_SL8XGcN-KpjUoZkBT5B0SVKlolZDq/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have questions? Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:DigitalFrontiers@dai.com&quot;&gt;DigitalFrontiers@dai.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Yasmine Williams
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/deadline-extended-apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/deadline-extended-apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Catching Up with the Winners of MIT’s Grand Hack for Health</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start by saying that the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s (MIT) Grand Hack is &lt;em&gt;kind of a big deal.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t make the point as an affront to other hackathons—certainly not &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/top-3-climate-change-concepts-from-the-2016-nasa-space-apps-challenge-bogota.html&quot;&gt;DAI’s own&lt;/a&gt;—but not many other hackathons can claim to have generated more than $150 million in venture capital and spawned more than 40 viable companies. Those two facts qualify the Grand Hack for royalty status among hackathons, which makes it even more surprising that the event is run entirely by students, MIT’s Hacking Health group. It’s also the reason why I was so excited to get a taste of MIT’s secret innovation sauce from the inside—as a mentor, alongside my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kristen-roggemann&quot;&gt;Kristen Roggemann&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/MIT-hacking-health-winners.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/MIT-hacking-health-winners.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coffee Cloud: The Digital Project for  Central American Coffee Growers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From 2010 to 2014, the Central American coffee bean suffered from a disease that rocked the economies of the region. Exports declined by 55 percent. From 2012 to 2013 some 374,000 jobs were lost—17 percent of the labor force. &lt;strong&gt;Roya&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20171106-the-disease-that-could-change-how-we-drink-coffee&quot;&gt;coffee rust&lt;/a&gt; threatened the livelihoods of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oxfam.org/sites/www.oxfam.org/files/file_attachments/ib-coffee-rust-employment-collapse-central-america-140814-en.pdf&quot;&gt;nearly 2 million&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee rust is a fungal disease that covers the leaves and prevents photosynthesis, slowly constricting plants’ ability to process sunlight, reducing bean yield and eventually starving the plant to death. The warmer, wetter conditions wrought by climate change creates a better ecosystem for the fungus to grow. Its impact on Central American economies is significant as coffee exports are the region’s largest source of foreign income and coffee supports a vast supply chain, in turn supporting dozens of adjacent industries.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 08:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-the-digital-project-for-central-american-coffee-growers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-the-digital-project-for-central-american-coffee-growers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trends in Digital Health: 4 Takeaways From Our UK Event</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In comparison to other development sectors, health programs have historically been early adopters of digital tools. What have we learned over the last 10 years, and where are we heading? How can we build systems that integrate data from independent actors across the health ecosystem? How can we use lessons learned to support innovation? How can we adapt to expanding digital access and support the growth of local capacity?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anand-varghese/">Anand Varghese</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/trends-in-digital-health-four-take-aways-from-our-second-uk-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/trends-in-digital-health-four-take-aways-from-our-second-uk-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apply Now: Support USAID Missions to Improve Broadband Connectivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid expansion of mobile and internet access in the developing world holds the promise of catalyzing resilient economic and social growth. However, the availability and cost of connectivity is a significant barrier to fully realizing that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help address this challenge, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s Center for Digital Development developed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/Better_Connectivity_Better_Programs_April2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Better Connectivity, Better Programs: How to Implement a Demand Aggregation Program (How-to Guide)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 17:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="mailto:digitalfrontiers@dai.com">Yasmine Williams</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-support-usaid-missions-to-improve-broadband-connectivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working With Tech Service Providers: It’s About More Than Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a nonprofit focused on improving maternal health outcomes? Or maybe you’re a civic engagement organization that encourages young people to become more involved with their local governments. No matter the objective, technology can both help you be more efficient internally and more impactful externally. The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of tech is often easy: “Oh, we’ll just build an app for that!” But relationships with technical service providers are fraught with pitfalls that can jeopardize outcomes and derail even the best intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/working-with-tech-service-providers-its-about-more-than-tech.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/working-with-tech-service-providers-its-about-more-than-tech.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
