<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 13:03:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 13:03:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Group%20Photo%20GIZ.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Human-Centered Design for a Digital Farmer Business School Application: A One-Day Roadmap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Human-centered design (HCD) is a central focus of DAI’s. We’ve written extensively about how we work with our partners to follow this complex and time-consuming (but very important) process and even came up with a more concise, budget-friendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-launches-human-centered-design-whitepaper.html&quot;&gt;Lean HCD approach.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our continued commitment to the approach, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/&quot;&gt;Karim Bin-Humam&lt;/a&gt; and I recently traveled to Ghana to run a workshop on HCD for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssab-africa.net/&quot;&gt;Sustainable Smallholder Agribusiness Programme (SSAB),&lt;/a&gt; implemented by Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ) GmbH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was lean HCD on steroids: We asked participants to produce a HCD roadmap in just one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GIZ%20blog%201.jfif&quot; alt=&quot;GIZ blog 1.jfif&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Participants chose their methods from the ideo.org design kit.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 09:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/human-centered-design-for-a-digital-farmer-business-school-application-a-strategy-built-within-1-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/human-centered-design-for-a-digital-farmer-business-school-application-a-strategy-built-within-1-day.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/WomenConnectSmall-e39657.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Meet the 9 WomenConnect Winners Who Are Using Tech for Good</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing just nine shining examples from more than 500 applicants of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/wcc&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge&lt;/a&gt; was no easy task. The global call—put out in March by Ivanka Trump and USAID Administrator Mark Green—sought examples of the changing ways in which women and girls’ access and use of technology help drive quality health, better education, and improved livelihoods for themselves and their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/8223644611_82458aa076_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8223644611_82458aa076_o.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/komal-bazaz-smith-3a56b5/">Komal Bazaz Smith</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/meet-the-womenconnect-challenge-winners.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/meet-the-womenconnect-challenge-winners.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ReportCover.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Inclusion and a Trusted Internet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ReportCover-d03d70.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;ReportCover-d03d70.PNG&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt; Back in 2014, when I was leading USAID’s Digital Inclusion Practice, I was invited by the U.S Department of State to present on the importance of information and communication technology (ICT) in driving economic growth. The cyber training was intended to equip foreign service officers with the knowledge and tools to represent the broad range of policy priorities enumerated in the President’s International Strategy for Cyberspace: Prosperity, Security, and Openness in a Networked World.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanjdolan">Jonathan Dolan</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-inclusion-and-a-trusted-internet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-inclusion-and-a-trusted-internet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/abacus-2-1529691-1278x730.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Getting the Basics of ICT4D Right</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a tendency in any field of business (and life!) to focus on the newest, shiniest objects. Just like obsession over the release of the latest iPad, the ICT4D community holds a special place in its heart for the newest technology offerings. Machine learning, blockchain, and the internet of things (IoT) come to mind today, whereas in years past it was crowdsourcing, social media, or smart phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/abacus-2-1529691-1278x730.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;abacus-2-1529691-1278x730.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-the-basics-right.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-the-basics-right.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FinancialInclusion.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Financial Sector Deepening Mozambique: The Regulatory Sandbox Startups</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All over the world, digital tools are creating opportunities for the those without bank accounts and expanding the array of financial services, known as fintech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/fsd%20moz%20logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fsd moz logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The Financial Sector Deepening project is increasing financial inclusion in Mozambique.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozambique is no exception—whilst literacy rates there are low, and the ICT infrastructure and regulatory framework are underdeveloped, traditional banking is still not serving people’s needs. The financial inclusion rate is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/catalog/3324&quot;&gt;42% (Work Bank Findex 2017)&lt;/a&gt; and there is a clear need for financial services to be available for poorer, more rural and marginalised populations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 11:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="http://fsdmoc.com/team/carlos-valente-mondle/">Carlos Valente Mondle</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/financial-sector-deepening-mozambique-the-regulatory-sandox-start-ups.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/financial-sector-deepening-mozambique-the-regulatory-sandox-start-ups.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/reasonably-sized-photo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Business Concepts from KIC’s 2018 Agritech Entrepreneurs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;award-winning&lt;/a&gt; Kosmos Innovation Center in Ghana has completed its final round of pitches for the 2018 cohort, and as with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;previous years&lt;/a&gt;, the program’s (very) early-stage young entrepreneurs continue to impress. Unlike previous years, the eight finalists this year were given six weeks and a small stipend to develop their minimum viable products (MVP), in addition to nine months of KIC-funded capacity building and market research. This meant that each team had the chance to meet with users, tweak their revenue models and designs, and even raise revenue to demonstrate proof-of-concept. As a result, I found that this year’s teams were well ahead of their 2017 and 2016 counterparts—their pitches were more compelling; they were more confident in their ability to answer judges’ questions; and their nose for entrepreneurship opportunities was keener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a run-down of each team’s business concepts for technology-driven Ghanaian agribusinesses.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/business-concepts-from-kics-2018-agritech-entrepreneurs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/business-concepts-from-kics-2018-agritech-entrepreneurs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Economic Growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Puzzle%20Cyber.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cyber Security Series Part 2: Understanding Cyber Security as Part of the Digital Development Conversation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-series-part-1-trust-is-why-cyber-security-matters-to-digital-development.html?utm_source=related-box&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; in the 2018 Cyber Security Series, I discussed why cyber security should be a key consideration in the design of digital tools that help support sustainable development efforts. I highlighted that trust in digital tools should not be taken for granted, but rather constantly invested in by designing digital tools with user input, but also with security in mind. Now I will take a look at some of the other key analog complements that need to be considered when deploying secure, integrated digital systems for sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 12:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-security-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/trevor%201.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>DFID and DAI Host Malawi’s First Digital Development Forum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration has been working closely with the U.K. Department for International Development (DFID)’s Malawi office to conduct a digital scoping study of its portfolio. Building on some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-malawi-communication-among-rural-communities.html&quot;&gt;user research&lt;/a&gt; we’ve conducted in Malawi, we’re identifying areas where DFID can make small, focused investments in digital innovations to improve the impact of its programs. And we’re also helping the team build relationships with the small, but growing, group of Malawian technologists tackling development challenges with digital tools. As part of this effort, we put together DFID’s first-ever Malawi Digital Development Forum last week, which brought together local technologists, development implementers, government decision-makers, and DFID staff for a day-long technology exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 10:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anand-varghese/">Anand Varghese</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/dfid-and-dai-host-malawis-first-digital-development-forum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/dfid-and-dai-host-malawis-first-digital-development-forum.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/blog.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Fishing with Smartphones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Much has been written about the digital divide and the failure of ICT to meet the needs of the poorest users. As World Bank President &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/speech/2018/02/26/speech-by-world-bank-group-president-jim-yong-kim-at-the-gsma-2018-mobile-world-congress&quot;&gt;Jim Kim says&lt;/a&gt;, “We must continue to connect all people so that no one is left behind … because the loss of opportunities has a very high cost.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Central America, some of those ‘left behind’ include more than 135,000 fishermen. Without access to vital information about how climate change affects fishing, their very livelihoods are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nacion.com/ciencia/medio-ambiente/cambio-climatico-golpea-pesca-artesanal-en-litorales-centroamericanos/PMD2I4PAQRAJVPHFR6MCYBDDCY/story/&quot;&gt;under threat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/fishing-with-smartphones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/fishing-with-smartphones.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ict4drinks2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>September 2018 ICT4D Happy Hour Roundup: Were You There?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy hours are the sinew of the ICT4D community: They are how we connect. For a few hours each month, we put aside the titles, affiliations, competition, and enjoy each other’s company over a few drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September was a particularly busy month on the ICT4D happy hour calendar, so let’s take a quick look back on what happened. Hopefully, you’ll join us for the next one!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 18:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/september-2018-ict4d-happy-hour-roundup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/september-2018-ict4d-happy-hour-roundup.html</guid>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
