<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 16:27:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 16:27:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyber Violence Against Women and Girls Creates Digital Exclusion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Raise your hand if you have experienced online harassment. I am sure the response is a virtual flurry. Although digital technologies have the ability to empower, connect, and liberalise, they can also serve as platforms for marginalisation and abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent news stories such as those from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2017/sep/05/diane-abbott-more-abused-than-any-other-mps-during-election&quot;&gt;UK General Election&lt;/a&gt; have shone a light on the targeting of female politicians and journalists and high-profile cases of cyber bullying of young girls have shocked people world over. Whilst we know well the veracity of online violence, a less prominent issue is how it can exacerbate levels of digital exclusion for already marginalised populations. Let’s take a look at how online violence against women and girls—or “cyber VAWG”—further impedes digital inclusion and prevents women and girls from enjoying digital dividends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Cambodia%20DI%201-c83e49.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cambodia DI 1-c83e49.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo from the USAID Development Innovations Cambodia project.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 06:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-vawg-what-are-the-implications-for-digital-inclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-vawg-what-are-the-implications-for-digital-inclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Podcasts for Human-Centered Designers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In international development, human-centered designer (HCD) is charged with rapidly developing empathy with a specific, targeted marginalized population, a social challenge that group faces, and parlaying that understanding into a local solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/headphones.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;headphones.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so successfully requires one primary skill: &lt;strong&gt;listening.&lt;/strong&gt; That means listening in the traditional sense: to an individual, as DAI does in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/rwanda-digital-insights.html&quot;&gt;Digital Insights&lt;/a&gt; work. But, more broadly, listening for design in the international development space means listening to an entire population to identify social challenges as well as the cultural, political, and economic dynamics that affect them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The podcasts below are all about people who know how to listen. They’ve expanded my understanding of design and sharpened my ability to listen closely when I’m designing a solution. I hope they’ll do the same for you, should you take the time to &lt;em&gt;listen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-podcasts-for-human-centered-designers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-podcasts-for-human-centered-designers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Insights: Would Haitians use Mobile Money for Banking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late September, I traveled to Haiti to conduct research on how Haitians engage with financial institutions and mobile technology to explore the feasibility of introducing mobile money as an avenue for the provision of financial services. Together with the team from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/haiti-finance-inclusive-fininc&quot;&gt;USAID/Haiti Finance Inclusive project&lt;/a&gt;, implemented by DAI, and with support from our sister USAID/Haiti project Finance Pour Tous and two key credit unions—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/CPFRATERNITE/&quot;&gt;Caisse Populaire Fraternite (CPF)&lt;/a&gt; and Socolavim—I visited nine locations through the northern and central provinces of the country to interview 181 credit union customers as they went about their business.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 09:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-would-haitians-use-mobile-money-for-banking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-would-haitians-use-mobile-money-for-banking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why a Dashboard Isn’t Just a Dashboard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember an early conversation with colleagues when I began working in digital development in which a peer dismissively waved his hand at the idea of implementing a live data dashboard, saying “A dashboard is a dashboard is a dashboard!” The finality of that line stuck with me. I assumed that the dismissal came from a person who was bored with dashboards, like a kid who opens a birthday present to find he has received yet ANOTHER dashboard. Well, interactive data dashboards—just like automobile dashboards—may not be the newest, hottest, shiniest thing in the ICT4D toolbox, but they’re still important and their often hidden values go unappreciated by many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dashboards.png&quot; alt=&quot;dashboards-81776e&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 14:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/why-a-dashboard-isnt-just-a-dashboard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/why-a-dashboard-isnt-just-a-dashboard.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Do’s and Don’ts in Adaptive Management and Learning in ICT4D</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler&quot;&gt;Kate Heuisler&lt;/a&gt;, Chief of Party of DAI’s USAID-funded Cambodia Development Innovations project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.development-innovations.org/&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; supports innovators and boosts the use of information and communication technologies for the overall development of Cambodia. The project is structured to be flexible and adaptive—because we need to. Really, most creative development programs &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; build themselves to be learning organizations, to be ready for big pivots, regardless if you and your partners use digital innovations. The development world is regularly disrupted—by political changes, natural disasters, new technologies such as social media—and is no longer built for static, five-year plans. Donors and funders need partners that can learn by doing, and are not afraid to adapt strategies and implementation plans to continually improve.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 10:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/adaptive-management-and-learning-in-ict4d-dos-and-donts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/adaptive-management-and-learning-in-ict4d-dos-and-donts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GeekFest 2017: Delving into Public Access with Duduzile Mkhwanazi of Project Isizwe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/geek%20fest%20smallest.jpg?download&quot; alt=&quot;geek fest logo&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;
Welcome to GeekFest 2017, a series of interviews featuring ICT4D thought leaders. Our goals for #geekfest2017 are: to highlight the people and organizations who are pushing the field in new directions, to feature their work and show how it’s different or new, and to support the overall growth of the ICT4D community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we are focusing on public access as a solution to closing the Digital Divide. Being able to access free public wifi can be crucial for those who cannot afford internet subscriptions: It can be the difference between finally finding that job, getting the training you need or linking up with a valuable investor for your new venture. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://a4ai.org/affordability-report/report/2017/&quot;&gt;2017 A4AI  Affordability Report&lt;/a&gt; noted the importance of public wifi for engendering use of the internet: Research shows public wifi as one of the most popular options for online access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down with Duduzile Mkhwanazi, CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projectisizwe.org/&quot;&gt;Project Isizwe&lt;/a&gt;-an organization making great strides in providing free public wifi in South Africa, a country where inequality is rife and the affordability of mobile data is just out of reach for many, despite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobileconnectivityindex.com/#year=2016&amp;amp;zoneIsocode=ZAF&quot;&gt;99 percent 3G coverage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blog1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 11:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-delving-into-public-access-with-duduzile-mkhwanazi-project-isizwe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest-2017-delving-into-public-access-with-duduzile-mkhwanazi-project-isizwe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Geekfest 2017</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Practicing the Principles for Digital Development in East Africa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by Mustapha Issa, Field Manager and MAST Coordinator and Gilead Mushaija, GIS Database Specialist, both from DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/tanzania-feed-future-tanzania-land-tenure-assistance-lta&quot;&gt;Feed the Future Land Tenure Assistance project.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa-tickets-37822273438&quot;&gt;Practicing the Principles for Digital Development&lt;/a&gt; event on October 12 in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania, 80 participants from organizations including DAI, the Ministry of Works, Transport, and Communications, and private organizations from Ethiopia, Kenya, Malawi, Rwanda, Tanzania, and Uganda attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalimpactalliance.org/&quot;&gt;Digital Impact Alliance&lt;/a&gt; (DIAL) and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hdif-tz.org/&quot;&gt;Human Development Innovation Fund Tanzania&lt;/a&gt; (HDIF-UKAid) stewarded the event and were joined by leading organizations in endorsing the Digital Principles. DAI is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/endorse/endorsers/&quot;&gt;signatory to the Principles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 11:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gilead-mushaija-b015aa33/">Gilead Mishaija</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mustapha-issa-93b3a014a/">Mustapha Issa</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/practicing-the-principles-for-digital-development-in-east-africa.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Key Takeaways from USAID’s New Gender and ICT Survey Toolkit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week USAID’s Global Development Lab and mStar project released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/Gender_and_ICT_Toolkit.pdf&quot;&gt;Gender and ICT Survey Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;. In an informative webinar (you can listen to the recording &lt;a href=&quot;http://solutionscenter.nethope.org/webinars/view/introducing-usaids-gender-and-ict-toolkit&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), the team that produced the report discussed both the content and the context surrounding the genesis of the toolkit. I tuned in and spent the majority of the time silently cheering, thrilled to hear USAID promoting research tactics and information needs that align with what we on DAI’s ICT team are doing with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/tags/?tag=digital-insights&quot;&gt;Digital Insights&lt;/a&gt; work. In between cheers, I feverishly took notes and captured these three key takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/three-key-takeaways-from-usaids-new-gender-and-ict-survey-toolkit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/three-key-takeaways-from-usaids-new-gender-and-ict-survey-toolkit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Testing Data Collection with OpenDataKit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Primary data collection: One of the most challenging, but necessary, components of any research project. Mobile and browser-based technologies have revolutionized the speed and efficiency of collecting data, enabling teams to work together on a centralized database without the headache of managing paper forms, or multiple excel documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this article, it’s likely you’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/forms/about/&quot;&gt;Googleforms&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/&quot;&gt;Survey Monkey&lt;/a&gt; for your work. But what if you need to collect data in regions without 3G or LTE coverage? You’ll need a tool to manage offline data collection, and load the data once you access a wireless internet connection. Fortunately, there are several tools designed to do just that, and one of them is completely free and open source. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendatakit.org/&quot;&gt;OpenDataKit&lt;/a&gt; (ODK). Let’s take a look at how this technology works.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/data-collection-with-opendatakit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/data-collection-with-opendatakit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Innovation in 60 Minutes or Less</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we do “open innovation,” it’s essential to define the problem we are trying to solve. And crucial to that process is crafting a good “Call.”  Can this be done in 60 minutes or less?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/workshop-5df2eb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workshop-5df2eb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAI facilitated workshop on open innovation at the Triangle Global Health Conference in Raleigh, North Carolina.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 16:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-innovation-in-60-minutes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-innovation-in-60-minutes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
