<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:59:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:59:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KIC-Mauritiana.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>KIC Mauritania: Winners Announced!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, DAI has provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;support to the Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC), which got its start in Ghana and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html&quot;&gt;expanded its work Mauritania in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, KIC Mauritania’s 2018 cohort of young entrepreneurs pitched concepts to a panel of judges, competing for more than $85,000 in total seed funding. Unlike KIC Ghana, which focuses solely on support to agritech startups, KIC’s Mauritanian startups have built a wide range of solutions across various sectors, from waste recycling to healthcare. Here’s an overview of this year’s finalists, their business concepts, and the final winners of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3%20USAID%20Development%20Innovations%20project.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building a Culture of Innovation in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many in international development want to be “innovative,” but how do workplaces develop cultures that promote useful innovation? The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) launched Development Innovations (DI) in 2013 to help Cambodian civil society organizations and tech companies leverage technology to address social needs. This objective would &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; new ways of thinking to create new ways for solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tiffany-tsang-05b33241/">Tiffany Tsang</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Phish.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Machine Learning Changes the Business Case for Automated Phishing Attacks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers have demonstrated the capability of machine learning to help with everything from &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/01/lets-save-the-bees-with-machine-learning/&quot;&gt;saving honeybees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/9/1/e024018.abstract&quot;&gt;tracking flu vaccine uptake&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-machine-learning-could-keep-dangerous-dna-out-of-terrorists-hands/&quot;&gt;aiding in the fight against bioterrorism&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20181219-what-to-do-with-your-leftover-christmas-food&quot;&gt;plenty in between&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But machine learning can also be put to less-scrupulous uses just as easily. Social engineering is a type of cyber attack that deceives users into creating security breaches, typically through emails and phone calls (often called ‘phishing’), and the marriage of machine learning with social engineering is poised to be a burgeoning issue in the near future. This issue is a global problem, but developing markets are often at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/02/technology/hackers-find-ideal-testing-ground-for-attacks-developing-countries.html&quot;&gt;highest risk for cyberattacks&lt;/a&gt; due to the lack of capacity to defend against and track such attacks. As such, they often find themselves as the testing grounds for novel attack methods before they reach more developed markets.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 08:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zachgieske/">Zach Gieske</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-changes-the-business-case-for-automated-phishing-attacks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-changes-the-business-case-for-automated-phishing-attacks.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FAW.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from the Fall Armyworm Tech Prize: The Importance of Ensuring Goals Align</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the attractions of awarding prizes in global development is that the prize sponsor shifts the responsibility of achieving results onto competitors. While this approach can inspire a range of creative solutions and spur a nascent market, it also means many finalists will develop something valuable whether they win the award or not. For a prize to be valuable to both sponsors and competitors, sponsors must clearly communicate prize objectives so that competitors have the best chance at success and can assess whether devoting resources to achieve those objectives makes sense for them, win or lose.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meredith-beth-perry-01882236/">Meredith Perry</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-the-importance-of-ensuring-goals-align.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-the-importance-of-ensuring-goals-align.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KarimFI.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The (Missing) Digital Principle: Educate the User</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We in the international development community talk a lot about privacy and security in digital development. We try to think through privacy and security in terms of the data we collect, what we do with it, and even how we address issues of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lindaraftree.com/2017/02/06/responsible-data-case-studies/&quot;&gt;consent around data collection&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/principle/address-privacy-security&quot;&gt;entire digital principle&lt;/a&gt; about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In discussions like these, privacy and security are framed entirely in terms of the paradigm of extraction—collecting and gathering data &lt;em&gt;from end users&lt;/em&gt; to organizations. This is an entirely valid and important discussion to continue having. However, there’s a discussion we’re not having that’s arguably even more important, and that’s around the privacy and security of users.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/kristen-roggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a> &amp; <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Working in Agriculture? Using Digital Ag Tools? Please Fill Out This Survey!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/&quot;&gt;U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)&lt;/a&gt; has worked with Missions to integrate digital tools and technologies into Feed the Future activities since 2015, first through the U.S. Global Development Lab-led &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digitalag&quot;&gt;Digital Development for Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt;(D2FTF) initiative and now through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-food-security&quot;&gt;Bureau for Food Security (BFS)&lt;/a&gt; (BFS). BFS works with DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project, a buy-in mechanism that allows Missions to receive digital solutions for resilience and food security assessments as well as program, project, activity design, and implementation support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;a phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo credit: CABI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this work, DAI-led Digital Frontiers is conducting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;survey of agriculture projects&lt;/a&gt; to understand their experiences using digital tools in their work. These findings will be used to inform BFS’s digital strategy. If you are working on an agriculture project, we are very interested in hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please take 10 minutes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;fill out our survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank you in advance for taking the time to complete this survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Please email DigitalFrontiers@dai.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SDG9%20small-f44723.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Access as an Assumption: The Unintended Consequence of Increasing Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SDG9%20small-23e62a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SDG9 small-23e62a.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt; In our quest to increase digital access, we tend to focus on the dividends, rather than the negatives that can arise. We are understandably excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itu.int/en/mediacentre/Pages/2018-PR40.aspx&quot;&gt;edging closer to universal access&lt;/a&gt; and the new business opportunities and improvements to service provision that accompany it. But while we are improving in our endeavor to promote online safety and security, bridge the gender digital divide, and include people with disabilities (all great stuff!), we could be overlooking some negative consequences of increased digital access.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/access-as-an-assumption-the-unintended-consequence-of-increasing-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/access-as-an-assumption-the-unintended-consequence-of-increasing-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/peru-mercury-emergency.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Digital Tools Help Combat Illegal Mining and Logging in the Amazon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent report prepared by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazoniasocioambiental.org/es/&quot;&gt;Amazonian Geo-referenced Socio-Environmental Information Network (RAISG) &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://infoamazonia.org/es/&quot;&gt;InfoAmazonia&lt;/a&gt;, in coordination with eight other Latin American institutions, published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mineria.amazoniasocioambiental.org/&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; that shows more than 2,000 data points across the Amazon where illegal activity is occurring. This includes illegal mining and logging in 96 protected areas. Most of the illegal activity is taking place in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mineria.amazoniasocioambiental.org/&quot;&gt;Venezuela&lt;/a&gt; where there are a reported 1,899 data points documenting illegal mining or logging. Venezuela is followed by Brazil where 321 cases of illegal activity are recorded. In Ecuador, the number drops to 68, and in Peru, 24. For organizations, governments, or advocates looking to protect the Amazon, this digital tool seems like a blessing. Yet, based on my experience it’s unclear whether these information-streamlining tools are actually limiting illegal activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-tools-against-illegal-mining-and-logging-in-the-amazon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-tools-against-illegal-mining-and-logging-in-the-amazon.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Satellite</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20head%20shot-0bcd9c-d7d5b5.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Resolution to Support the Tech Sector Where We Need It Most</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 5, I posted the message below on Facebook to hold myself accountable to my New Year’s resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20blog%20pic-3811e6.png&quot; alt=&quot;hanson blog pic-3811e6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple. I want tech businesses to grow and thrive in Nigeria &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of Lagos. I want to support someone who grew up in, works in, and wants to continue working in my hometown, Uyo. This is not just my resolution, but has been my life’s work since I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://starthub.com.ng/&quot;&gt;Start Innovation Hub&lt;/a&gt; five years ago. Start Innovation Hub is an ICT firm and innovation lab that works to expand the tech industry by supporting tech startups and talented individuals in Uyo. We build skills and connect entrepreneurs to economic opportunities, as well as support local businesses by developing software solutions. You can’t deny that the tech sector in Nigeria is growing rapidly, but the concentration of firms in Lagos means that places like Uyo are left behind. Through Start Innovation Hub, I hope to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nextdeegit/">Hanson Johnson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5.%20uganda%20cookstoves%20study.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Four Rs: An Interview With the Lean Research Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are huge fans of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research&quot;&gt;Lean Research&lt;/a&gt; initiative at DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration&lt;/a&gt;. I recently went to the Massachusetts Institute for Technology’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT D-Lab&lt;/a&gt; and sat with &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research/lean-research-community&quot;&gt;Elizabeth, Kendra, and Kim&lt;/a&gt;, the team behind Lean Research, to learn more about the genesis of the initiative and what tools and resources they offer ICT4D practitioners eager to “right-size” their own research approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
