<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:17:36 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:17:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID1-e80035.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Identity Series Part 1: Digital Identity and Informed Consent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital ID1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;This post marks the launch of a Digital Identity series here on Digital@DAI. It is a pivotal topic to many of our technical areas: from health service provision, to cash transfers, and voter registration. It is also a topic garnering increased attention with the debate over privacy and data security—and the global refugee crisis reinforcing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/213581486378184357/pdf/112614-REVISED-English-ID4D-IdentificationPrinciples-Folder-web-English-ID4D-IdentificationPrinciples.pdf&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; that there is “no single factor that affects a person’s ability to share in the gains of global development as much as having an official identity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, we will look at some of the issues and opportunities around Digital ID in the development space. Today, we look at informed consent: what it means to the development sector, the difficulty of getting it, and what we can do to make sure we aren’t leaving people behind, while respecting their privacy and the security of their data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 05:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-1-digital-identity-and-informed-consent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-1-digital-identity-and-informed-consent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Digital Identity Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/computers.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Nobody Cares What Tech You Use</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technologists and developers love to talk about the best tools for building new technology. MERN or MEAN stack, functional vs. object-oriented programming, vanilla development or frameworks. The internet is ripe with these discussions and attend any tech meetup and you’ll easily find multiple discussions comparing one tool to another. The performance and usability of one over the other, as if that is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fzachary-diehl-7b466b174&amp;data=01%7C01%7CGalia_Nurko%40dai.com%7Cf67a56aa590843a77e1b08d6a72fbf8e%7C7107113de20b4c20a4ce553cabbf686d%7C0&amp;sdata=AzUi%2BFO6MhNA7fBkVFoMVM%2F8vH8tuOQ1S38SioYFncc%3D&amp;reserved=0">Zach Diehl</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/nobody-cares-what-tech-you-use.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/nobody-cares-what-tech-you-use.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/1_KiGsfO6WD6_sn1Qx70w3vA.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Is Your Data in a Lake or Water Treatment Plant?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They say to write about what you know. For the first part of my career and through my formal education, my work was all based in the world of water and sanitation. Glamorous stuff—pipes and pumps, fecal coli-forms and treatment options, toilets and activated sludge. It made for great dinner conversation (or so says my wife). At some point, I made the transition from a water guy who worked with a lot of data to a data scientist who knows about water. And as I dive deeper into the analogies and lingo of modern data systems and tools, I lean on my engineering training to make sense of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-mann-13012513/">Ben Mann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/is-your-data-in-a-lake-or-water-treatment-plant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/is-your-data-in-a-lake-or-water-treatment-plant.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/CABI%20Group%20photo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to Support Digital Tools and Approaches for USAID’s Bureau for Food Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rapidly changing access to digital tools such as basic mobile phones is changing the landscape for how we can address the challenges to ending global hunger, undernutrition, and extreme poverty. “Despite our collective progress in global food security and nutrition over recent years, a projected 702 million people still live in extreme poverty; nearly 800 million people around the world are chronically undernourished; and 159 million children under five are stunted. Food security is not just an economic and humanitarian issue; it is also a matter of security, as growing concentrations of poverty and hunger leave countries and communities vulnerable to increased instability, conflict, and violence.” (U.S. Government Global Food Security Strategy 2017-2021).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-digital-tools-and-approaches-for-usaids-bureau-for-food-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-to-support-digital-tools-and-approaches-for-usaids-bureau-for-food-security.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KIC-Mauritiana.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>KIC Mauritania: Winners Announced!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, DAI has provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;support to the Kosmos Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt; (KIC), which got its start in Ghana and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-expands-its-support-of-tech-driven-entrepreneurship-to-mauritania.html&quot;&gt;expanded its work Mauritania in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, KIC Mauritania’s 2018 cohort of young entrepreneurs pitched concepts to a panel of judges, competing for more than $85,000 in total seed funding. Unlike KIC Ghana, which focuses solely on support to agritech startups, KIC’s Mauritanian startups have built a wide range of solutions across various sectors, from waste recycling to healthcare. Here’s an overview of this year’s finalists, their business concepts, and the final winners of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/kic-mauritania-winners-announced.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/3%20USAID%20Development%20Innovations%20project.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building a Culture of Innovation in Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many in international development want to be “innovative,” but how do workplaces develop cultures that promote useful innovation? The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) launched Development Innovations (DI) in 2013 to help Cambodian civil society organizations and tech companies leverage technology to address social needs. This objective would &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; new ways of thinking to create new ways for solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tiffany-tsang-05b33241/">Tiffany Tsang</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cambodia.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Phish.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Machine Learning Changes the Business Case for Automated Phishing Attacks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers have demonstrated the capability of machine learning to help with everything from &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/01/lets-save-the-bees-with-machine-learning/&quot;&gt;saving honeybees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/9/1/e024018.abstract&quot;&gt;tracking flu vaccine uptake&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-machine-learning-could-keep-dangerous-dna-out-of-terrorists-hands/&quot;&gt;aiding in the fight against bioterrorism&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20181219-what-to-do-with-your-leftover-christmas-food&quot;&gt;plenty in between&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But machine learning can also be put to less-scrupulous uses just as easily. Social engineering is a type of cyber attack that deceives users into creating security breaches, typically through emails and phone calls (often called ‘phishing’), and the marriage of machine learning with social engineering is poised to be a burgeoning issue in the near future. This issue is a global problem, but developing markets are often at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/02/technology/hackers-find-ideal-testing-ground-for-attacks-developing-countries.html&quot;&gt;highest risk for cyberattacks&lt;/a&gt; due to the lack of capacity to defend against and track such attacks. As such, they often find themselves as the testing grounds for novel attack methods before they reach more developed markets.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 08:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zachgieske/">Zach Gieske</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-changes-the-business-case-for-automated-phishing-attacks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/machine-learning-changes-the-business-case-for-automated-phishing-attacks.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FAW.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lessons from the Fall Armyworm Tech Prize: The Importance of Ensuring Goals Align</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the attractions of awarding prizes in global development is that the prize sponsor shifts the responsibility of achieving results onto competitors. While this approach can inspire a range of creative solutions and spur a nascent market, it also means many finalists will develop something valuable whether they win the award or not. For a prize to be valuable to both sponsors and competitors, sponsors must clearly communicate prize objectives so that competitors have the best chance at success and can assess whether devoting resources to achieve those objectives makes sense for them, win or lose.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meredith-beth-perry-01882236/">Meredith Perry</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-the-importance-of-ensuring-goals-align.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/lessons-from-the-fall-armyworm-tech-prize-the-importance-of-ensuring-goals-align.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KarimFI.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The (Missing) Digital Principle: Educate the User</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We in the international development community talk a lot about privacy and security in digital development. We try to think through privacy and security in terms of the data we collect, what we do with it, and even how we address issues of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lindaraftree.com/2017/02/06/responsible-data-case-studies/&quot;&gt;consent around data collection&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/principle/address-privacy-security&quot;&gt;entire digital principle&lt;/a&gt; about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In discussions like these, privacy and security are framed entirely in terms of the paradigm of extraction—collecting and gathering data &lt;em&gt;from end users&lt;/em&gt; to organizations. This is an entirely valid and important discussion to continue having. However, there’s a discussion we’re not having that’s arguably even more important, and that’s around the privacy and security of users.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/kristen-roggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a> &amp; <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Working in Agriculture? Using Digital Ag Tools? Please Fill Out This Survey!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/&quot;&gt;U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)&lt;/a&gt; has worked with Missions to integrate digital tools and technologies into Feed the Future activities since 2015, first through the U.S. Global Development Lab-led &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digitalag&quot;&gt;Digital Development for Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt;(D2FTF) initiative and now through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-food-security&quot;&gt;Bureau for Food Security (BFS)&lt;/a&gt; (BFS). BFS works with DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project, a buy-in mechanism that allows Missions to receive digital solutions for resilience and food security assessments as well as program, project, activity design, and implementation support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;a phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo credit: CABI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this work, DAI-led Digital Frontiers is conducting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;survey of agriculture projects&lt;/a&gt; to understand their experiences using digital tools in their work. These findings will be used to inform BFS’s digital strategy. If you are working on an agriculture project, we are very interested in hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please take 10 minutes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;fill out our survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank you in advance for taking the time to complete this survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Please email DigitalFrontiers@dai.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
