<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 11:38:05 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 11:38:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GSMA.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Mobile Technologies Push Latin America Forward</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Esta entrada también está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html&quot;&gt;Español&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital ecosystem in Latin America is pushing countries to accelerate public-private collaboration on digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobile360series.com/latin-america/agenda/&quot;&gt;GSMA Mobile 360 LATAM conference&lt;/a&gt;, we heard a lot about how 5G networks will bring about a technological, economic, and social revolution around the world. Many speakers—including GSMA CEO Mats Granryd—urged authorities and industry representatives to work jointly to accelerate the adoption of 5G networks in the region so that Latin America is not left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Internet of Things</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GSMA.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Las Tecnologías Móviles Empujan a América Latina Hacia Adelante</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is also available in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El ecosistema digital en la región de América Latina está presionando a los países para acelerar la colaboración público-privada en la transformación digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En la &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobile360series.com/latin-america/agenda/&quot;&gt;conferencia Mobile 360 LATAM de GSMA&lt;/a&gt;, escuchamos constantemente cómo se espera que las redes 5G traigan una revolución tecnológica, económica y social en todo el mundo. La pregunta fue planteada por muchos oradores, entre ellos Mat Granryd, CEO de GSMA, quien instó a las autoridades y la industria a trabajar conjuntamente para acelerar la adopción de redes 5G en la región para que América Latina no se quede atrás.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> y <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandtro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Internet of Things</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/PhoneUse.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Open Source Versus Proprietary Data Management Stack—Which One is Best for Your Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product development team, we spend a lot of time listening to the needs of users, particularly when it comes to their desire to collect and analyze data. And while projects have unique needs, they often ask for a common set of technology solutions. These include the ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Digitally collect and manage data - offline or online as mobile bandwidth permits.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn as much as they can from their data, often through a series a dashboards or reports.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload products and share learnings with a public audience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintain an internal system for data sharing, so that people only have access to certain information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, these tools should be easy to use, and ideally not too expensive to build or maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are reasonable requests. If prioritized, organizations should be able to develop and maintain highly functional data management and analysis solutions. So why do so many organizations struggle to maintain these kinds of systems?
In this article, I’d like to outline two very different routes that organizations can take when trying to build out their systems: 1) completely proprietary solutions v. 2) open source technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/convening%201-a4e466.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Power Beyond the Prize</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation recently hosted a convening between two sets of challenge prize winners: Feed the Future’s, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fallarmywormtech.challenges.org/&quot;&gt;Fall Armyworm Tech Prize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; finalists and the Grand Challenges Explorations (GCE)’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcgh.grandchallenges.org/challenge/tools-and-technologies-broad-scale-disease-surveillance-crop-plants-low-income-countries&quot;&gt;Tools and Technologies for Broad-Scale Pest and Disease Surveillance of Crop Plants in Low-Income Countries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcgh.grandchallenges.org/challenge/tools-and-technologies-broad-scale-disease-surveillance-crop-plants-low-income-countries&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;winners. The objective was to catalyze collaboration between the two groups of innovators working in digital agriculture, engineering, modeling, remote sensing, pathology, and chemistry for the benefit of farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/talia-dweck/">Talia Dweck</a> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/komal-bazaz-smith-3a56b5/">Komal Bazaz Smith</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/power-beyond-the-prize.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/power-beyond-the-prize.html</guid>
        
        <category>Co-creation</category>
        
        <category>Fall Armyworm</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID%20small-1-ab2324.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Identity Series Part 3: Barriers to Inclusion for All</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID%20small-1-97efcb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital ID small-1-97efcb.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;Any ID—whether state-issued or purpose-made for services such as cash transfers—in some way reflects levels of equality, whether these are inherent in the technology or prevalent in the social ecosystem. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Digital-identity-opportunities-for-women-Insights-from-Nigeria-Bangladesh-and-Rwanda-Web.pdf&quot;&gt;research from the GSM Association (GSMA)&lt;/a&gt; in Bangladesh, Nigeria, and Rwanda showed that citizens feel that equality in national ID is important as it reflects equality in citizenship status for men and women. If a biometric-based ID card is created in a refugee camp to facilitate cash transfers, every person living in that camp can rightfully expect to be registered regardless of age, gender, or ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We list a number of ways in which bias can manifest in digital identities to kick off some discussion and move toward solutions. While reading this, I encourage you to think how we can make sure digital ID systems are inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-3-digital-identity-and-exclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-3-digital-identity-and-exclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Identity Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/iot-technology-concept-city-transport-smart-1575603-pxhere.com.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Changes in Open-Data Policy in Global Development are a Game Changer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You saw it coming. You’ve been collecting geospatial data on your projects for years. Maybe uploading it to a faraway server or sharing it with local partners…or stashing it away on your laptop or external hard drive. But no one else was ever able to use it. And you were sort of irritated that you had to ask a million people for the same data every time you started a new development project in a different country.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/carmen-tedesco">Carmen Tedesco</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/changes-in-open-data-policy-in-global-development-are-a-game-changer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/changes-in-open-data-policy-in-global-development-are-a-game-changer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KICPaper.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building the Future of Tech-Enabled Agriculture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, Digital@DAI has kept its readers updated on the latest from the Kosmos Innovation Center (KIC) in Ghana, from young entrepreneurs’ agritech &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;product concepts&lt;/a&gt; to international &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;awards&lt;/a&gt; it has received. In the three years since the KIC’s launch, funders of all sorts—from bilateral donors to corporate social investors—have embraced the potential of Africa’s growing startup ecosystem to support socio-economic development and create new solutions to some of the continent’s most persistent challenges. In that time, KIC and DAI have learned a lot about what it means to support youth-led technology entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve compiled our findings in the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration-solutions/cda-insights&quot;&gt;CDA Insights&lt;/a&gt; paper titled, ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/kic-27672d.pdf&quot;&gt;Building the Future of Tech-Enabled Agriculture.&lt;/a&gt;’ In addition to providing lessons for both funders and implementers in this sector, we created profiles of select KIC entrepreneurs and captured their journeys.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-cda-insights-publication-building-the-future-of-tech-enabled-agriculture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-cda-insights-publication-building-the-future-of-tech-enabled-agriculture.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cover1.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>El desarrollo de Coffee Cloud: Una herramienta de precisión utilizada por agricultores en la región centroamericana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is also available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durante más de un siglo, la roya ha representado una seria amenaza para la industria cafetalera mundial, especialmente en la era del cambio climático. No obstante, la toma de acciones eficaces y de forma coordinada entre los países centroamericanos productores de café ha sido una tarea difícil de lograr. En consecuencia, esta enfermedad ha continuado propagándose y sus efectos han sido devastadores. Entre 2012 y 2013, la roya ocasionó que la región centroamericana experimentara una reducción del 15 por ciento de su producción de café, lo que incluyó un alarmante 31 por ciento en Honduras. El gráfico siguiente muestra las pérdidas que experimentó cada país durante este período.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 13:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a> y <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>diseño centrado en el humano</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cover1.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building Coffee Cloud: A Precision Ag Tool Used by Farmers Across Central America</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Esta entrada también está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html&quot;&gt;español&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee rust has menaced the global coffee industry for more than a century, but particularly in the era of climate change. Nevertheless, effective, coordinated action between coffee producing countries across Central America has remained elusive, and as a result the disease has spread—to devastating effect. In 2012 and 2013, coffee rust reduced the region’s coffee production by 15 percent, including a staggering 31 percent in Honduras. The figure below shows the losses each country suffered during that season.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Tepmachcha%20flood%20early%20warning.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>You Keep Using That Word: Why “Scale” Doesn’t Mean What You Think It Means</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Merriam-Webster Dictionary offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/scale&quot;&gt;seven&lt;/a&gt; definitions of “scale,” involving variously weight, fish, climbing, maps, music, and—unexpectedly—lumber. Notably, none of these meanings is a synonym for “to embiggen,” the usage favored in the tech and development worlds. In these environments, which share little else, taking something “to scale” always seems to evoke Carl Sagan-esque notions of quantity. What this reductionist approach to vocabulary loses (in addition to small stiff plates that cover much of the body of some animals) is the range that makes this word truly useful. In English, if not in Silicon Valley, you can scale &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt;, but you can also scale &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Sylva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/you-keep-using-that-word-why-scale-doesnt-mean-what-you-think-it-means.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/you-keep-using-that-word-why-scale-doesnt-mean-what-you-think-it-means.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
