<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:21:40 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:21:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GettyImages-1379895972.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Potential Value of AI—and How Governments Could Capture It, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-and-social-sector/our-insights/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-look-to-capture-it&quot;&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Company&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) could have a significant impact on individuals, businesses, and governments. Here is what countries need to know about its benefits—and the first steps toward realizing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long-term potential of AI to change key aspects of the way we live and to support the operations of businesses, governments, and other organizations is hard to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, AI has contributed to improvements in quality of life for all segments of society through innovations such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/healthcare-systems-and-services/our-insights/transforming-healthcare-with-ai&quot;&gt;predictive healthcare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/education/our-insights/how-artificial-intelligence-will-impact-k-12-teachers&quot;&gt;adaptive education&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/artificial-intelligence/applying-artificial-intelligence-for-social-good&quot;&gt;optimized crisis response&lt;/a&gt;. The National Health Service in the United Kingdom, for instance, set up a National COVID-19 Chest Imaging Database containing a shared library of chest X-rays, computerized tomography (CT) scans, and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) images to support the testing and development of AI technologies to treat COVID-19 and a variety of other health conditions. Businesses have seen increased productivity and operational efficiency using autonomous robotics in manufacturing, AI-optimized supply chains, and intelligent cargo routing with autonomous vehicles, among other initiatives. For example, many logistics companies are using AI-powered sorting robots to optimize their warehouse operations. Governments can also harness the power of AI through personalized services and automated processes. Consider Singapore’s “Ask Jamie,” a virtual assistant that helps citizens and businesses navigate government services across roughly 70 government agencies through AI-powered chat and voice.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 08:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/niklas-berglind-92571231/?originalSubdomain=se">Niklas Berglind</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankit-fadia/">Ankit Fadia</a> and <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/our-people/tom-isherwood">Tom Isherwood</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-potential-value-of-ai-and-how-governments-could-capture-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/guerrillabuzz-crypto-pr-T9rKvI3N0NM-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital @ DAI Rewind: Is Intellectual Property Ready for Blockchain?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re an avid reader of the Digital@DAI blog, then by now you’ve surely heard of blockchain technology. For those in need of a refresher, blockchain is a decentralized database system that records information in a way that makes it near-to-impossible to change, breach, or cheat the system. International donors and the private sector have deployed blockchain towards furthering financial inclusion, digital government, and improved supply chain management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More recently, governments and the private sector are exploring how this technology can be applied toward the building of secure and data-preserving e-governance systems. Governments across the &lt;a href=&quot;https://irishtechnews.ie/global-blockchain-adoption-which-countries-are-leading-the-charge/&quot;&gt;globe&lt;/a&gt;, such as in Chile, Estonia, Singapore, Uzbekistan, and Venezuela, to name a few, are using blockchain and other emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, the Internet of Things and smart contracts to build digital governance systems. An exciting feature of blockchain is that it can support the creative industry by serving as intellectual property rights register and enforcement tool. For instance, the European Union Intellectual Property (IP) Office, in collaboration with participating offices, launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scintilla-ip.com/blockchain-ip-register-at-the-euipo/&quot;&gt;Blockchain IP register&lt;/a&gt;, which has the ability to automatically store data about registered IP rights in various IP offices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As blockchain is a versatile technology that impacts many sectors from cryptocurrency to creative industries and IP management, it is crucial that the digital development sector stays abreast of blockchain’s impact on digital transformation. This week, we will revisit a post from 2021 from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/miriam-stankovich&quot;&gt;Dr. Miriam Stankovich&lt;/a&gt; about blockchain’s applicability to patents, copyrights, trademarks, and industrial designs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 07:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-rewind-is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-rewind-is-intellectual-property-ready-for-blockchain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Blockchain Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/dan-cristian-padure-BxgVEo_rF-o-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital@DAI Rewind: Right to Repair is a Development Issue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.repair.org/stand-up&quot;&gt;Right to Repair&lt;/a&gt;” is a concept and advocacy movement centered around the idea that anyone who owns a device, machinery, or piece of equipment should have the right to repair it themselves or take it to a repair person or shop of their choosing. While this has been a subject in tech news for the last several years, the concept is back in the spotlight. Last week, Apple unveiled its new, more repairable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/09/19/apple-iphone-14-easiest-to-fix-since-2016-ifixit.html&quot;&gt;iPhone 14&lt;/a&gt; and in June, the New York state legislature &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/3/23153504/right-to-repair-new-york-state-law-ifixit-repairability-diy&quot;&gt;passed&lt;/a&gt; the United States’ first Right to Repair bill. With the movement picking up steam, we are reminded that there are linkages to our work in digital development. This week, we will revisit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html&quot;&gt;2021 post&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/robert-ryan-silva&quot;&gt;Rob Ryan-Silva&lt;/a&gt;, Director of DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/dai-maker-lab&quot;&gt;Maker Lab&lt;/a&gt;, about why this movement is an issue the development community needs to care about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 07:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Silva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/right-to-repair-is-a-development-issue.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ukraine%20cross%20post.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Starting Now on Digital Transformation for Ukraine Reconstruction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ictworks.org/digital-transformation-ukraine-reconstruction/&quot;&gt;ICTworks blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the war in Ukraine comes to an end (hopefully with Ukraine having recovered all of its territories, including Crimea), Western countries are likely to provide a massive aid package to help rebuild Ukrainian infrastructure, buildings, and lives. This moment in history will offer an opportunity for Ukraine to engage in rapid digital transformation. We should already begin deploying digital tools that will help Ukraine as it continues to fight bravely against the invaders, with the intention of seeing the country emerge from war on the right foot for a quick recovery. As President Volodymyr Zelenskyy himself &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anews.com.tr/world/2022/07/03/zelensky-calls-for-international-assistance-to-rebuild-ukraine&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the post-war reconstruction should use the moment to build “a new foundation for our lives: … accessible new technologies, best practices, new institutions and, of course, reforms.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 12:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/troyetulain/">Troy Etulain</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/starting-now-on-digital-transformation-for-ukraine-reconstruction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/starting-now-on-digital-transformation-for-ukraine-reconstruction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Disinformation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Government</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Thumbnail%20MFA.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Authentication Dilemma: Can a Single Solution Guarantee Security for Small Firms?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the rapid rate of digitalization catalyzed by the COVID-19 pandemic, cyber-attacks have become ubiquitous, presenting opportunities to improve cybersecurity practices for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs). SMEs contribute up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/smefinance&quot;&gt;40 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the gross domestic product in emerging economies, make up 90 percent of all businesses, and provide more than 50 percent of employment worldwide, making them significant economic drivers and digital supply chain actors. They also endure unprecedented malicious cyber activity, such as ransomware, phishing, password targeting, and advanced persistent threat attacks. In Nigeria, cyber attacks against SMEs have increased by &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardian.ng/business-services/cyber-attack-on-nigerian-smes-up-by-89-per-cent-in-2022/&quot;&gt;89 percent&lt;/a&gt;, in 2022 alone, and in India, more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/more-than-60-of-mid-sized-indian-organizations-surveyed-fell-victim-to-a-cyberattack-in-2021-sophos-research-shows/articleshow/90517626.cms&quot;&gt;60 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all SMEs experienced attacks last year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-odisheli-a2a56494/">Alexander Odisheli</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-authentication-dilemma.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-authentication-dilemma.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Security</category>
        
        <category>SME</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/austin-distel-x1J0zj63ZjM-unsplash%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Future of Work: A Review on the Trending Phenomenon of Digital Nomads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020, the world witnessed and experienced the COVID-19 pandemic reshape organizational cultures and how people define work in their lives. Companies shifted their models to accommodate working from home, and that trend continues, as an Upwork &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/press/releases/upwork-study-finds-22-of-american-workforce-will-be-remote-by-2025&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; estimated that by 2025, 22 percent of the U.S. workforce will be remote workers. The reshaping of work also pushed further the phenomenon of digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/afua-owusu/">Afua Owusu</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/temi-olatunji/">Temi Olatunji</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-of-work-a-review-on-the-trending-phenomenon-of-digital-nomads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-future-of-work-a-review-on-the-trending-phenomenon-of-digital-nomads.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Economy</category>
        
        <category>Social Media</category>
        
        <category>Digital Communications</category>
        
        <category>Digital Transformation</category>
        
        <category>Future of Work</category>
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/pexels-pixabay-60504.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Lack of Cybersecurity Talent Poses a Global Challenge and Opportunity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The limited supply of a skilled workforce is one of the major challenges plaguing the technology ecosystems of countries around the world. The field of cybersecurity is an excellent case study. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/2021/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Workforce-Study-2021.ashx&quot;&gt;2021 (ICS)2Cybersecurity Workforce Study&lt;/a&gt;, the cybersecurity workforce gap—the number of people needed to help organizations protect their critical assets from cybersecurity threats—is 2.72 million worldwide. Although down from 3.12 million the previous year, this is still a significant gap. The true shortfall is likely greater, as the study does not account for the public policy, diplomatic, or business talent in small and medium-sized enterprises. This post explores opportunities to enhance the cybersecurity literacy of policymakers, diplomats, and business leaders, and makes the case for cybersecurity workforce development across these professions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Galia Nurko
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyberworkforce.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyberworkforce.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/tariq%20image.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Emerging eLearning Series: Accessible Training at Scale to Increase Local Governance Capacity in Libya</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration (CDA) has been at the forefront of supporting international development projects to understand, apply, and implement eLearning solutions in settings that had not initially considered their wide-scale use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second in a series of posts that seek to capture some of these efforts, celebrate innovative successes, consider critical lessons learned, and support practitioners who continue to do this work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 23:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/trevor-oxley">Trevor Olexy</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/anne-hand/">Anne Hand</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-accessible-training-at-scale-to-increase-local-governance-capacity-in-libya.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/emerging-elearning-series-accessible-training-at-scale-to-increase-local-governance-capacity-in-libya.html</guid>
        
        <category>eLearning</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>Emerging eLearning Series</category>
        
        <category>eTraining</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Neema%20Iyer%20Headshot.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Shaping History Series: Innovative Leaders Driving Digital Transformation—Interview with Neema Iyer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ineema/&quot;&gt;Neema Iyer&lt;/a&gt; is a trailblazer. Iyer is an artist and technologist influencing the digital development sector with her innovative lens on the intersection of data, technology, and design to improve government service delivery. The East African native is the founder and director of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pollicy.org/&quot;&gt;Pollicy&lt;/a&gt;, a feminist collective of technologists, data scientists, and creatives. After graduating with a master’s degree in global epidemiology from Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, Iyer returned to Africa, where she was exposed to the lack of gendered perspectives in the information and communications sector on the continent. Simultaneously, she was also experiencing and witnessing frustrations at various touch points with the government, such as securing important documents, information, or services.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 10:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/afua-owusu/">Afua Owusu</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/inta-plostins/">Inta Plostins</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-series-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-interview-with-neema-iyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/shaping-history-series-innovative-leaders-driving-digital-transformation-interview-with-neema-iyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        <category>Shaping History Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare for Development 4.0: Recommendations for Policymakers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, artificial intelligence (AI) is broadly understood to include not only long-term efforts to simulate the general intelligence humans exhibit, but also fast-evolving technologies—such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/cloud/learn/convolutional-neural-networks&quot;&gt;convolutional neural networks&lt;/a&gt;—that affect many facets of modern society, such as healthcare, national security, social media, agriculture, and more. The sweeping changes caused by AI have significantly increased the gap between government policy and innovative business models that rely on AI deployment. AI is changing norms and business models throughout society, demanding new and effective policy responses from governments on subjects with little real precedence. While governments struggle to adapt to the rapid pace of change, AI brings new solutions and offers the potential to transform how policy is made by providing new tools and methods of policy development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 12:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Miriam Stankovich
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare-for-development-4-dot-0-recommendations-for-policymakers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare-for-development-4-dot-0-recommendations-for-policymakers.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>ICT Policy</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>industry 4.0</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
