<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 10:53:37 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 10:53:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KarimFI.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The (Missing) Digital Principle: Educate the User</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We in the international development community talk a lot about privacy and security in digital development. We try to think through privacy and security in terms of the data we collect, what we do with it, and even how we address issues of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lindaraftree.com/2017/02/06/responsible-data-case-studies/&quot;&gt;consent around data collection&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalprinciples.org/principle/address-privacy-security&quot;&gt;entire digital principle&lt;/a&gt; about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In discussions like these, privacy and security are framed entirely in terms of the paradigm of extraction—collecting and gathering data &lt;em&gt;from end users&lt;/em&gt; to organizations. This is an entirely valid and important discussion to continue having. However, there’s a discussion we’re not having that’s arguably even more important, and that’s around the privacy and security of users.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/kristen-roggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a> &amp; <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-missing-digital-principle-educate-the-user.html</guid>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        <category>Digital Principles</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Working in Agriculture? Using Digital Ag Tools? Please Fill Out This Survey!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/&quot;&gt;U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)&lt;/a&gt; has worked with Missions to integrate digital tools and technologies into Feed the Future activities since 2015, first through the U.S. Global Development Lab-led &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/digitalag&quot;&gt;Digital Development for Feed the Future&lt;/a&gt;(D2FTF) initiative and now through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/who-we-are/organization/bureaus/bureau-food-security&quot;&gt;Bureau for Food Security (BFS)&lt;/a&gt; (BFS). BFS works with DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project, a buy-in mechanism that allows Missions to receive digital solutions for resilience and food security assessments as well as program, project, activity design, and implementation support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/aphone.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;a phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo credit: CABI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this work, DAI-led Digital Frontiers is conducting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;survey of agriculture projects&lt;/a&gt; to understand their experiences using digital tools in their work. These findings will be used to inform BFS’s digital strategy. If you are working on an agriculture project, we are very interested in hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please take 10 minutes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QSMW65V&quot;&gt;fill out our survey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank you in advance for taking the time to complete this survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Please email DigitalFrontiers@dai.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/working-in-digital-agriculture-please-full-out-this-survey.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SDG9%20small-f44723.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Access as an Assumption: The Unintended Consequence of Increasing Digital Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SDG9%20small-23e62a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SDG9 small-23e62a.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt; In our quest to increase digital access, we tend to focus on the dividends, rather than the negatives that can arise. We are understandably excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itu.int/en/mediacentre/Pages/2018-PR40.aspx&quot;&gt;edging closer to universal access&lt;/a&gt; and the new business opportunities and improvements to service provision that accompany it. But while we are improving in our endeavor to promote online safety and security, bridge the gender digital divide, and include people with disabilities (all great stuff!), we could be overlooking some negative consequences of increased digital access.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/access-as-an-assumption-the-unintended-consequence-of-increasing-digital-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/access-as-an-assumption-the-unintended-consequence-of-increasing-digital-access.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/peru-mercury-emergency.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Digital Tools Help Combat Illegal Mining and Logging in the Amazon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent report prepared by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazoniasocioambiental.org/es/&quot;&gt;Amazonian Geo-referenced Socio-Environmental Information Network (RAISG) &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://infoamazonia.org/es/&quot;&gt;InfoAmazonia&lt;/a&gt;, in coordination with eight other Latin American institutions, published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mineria.amazoniasocioambiental.org/&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; that shows more than 2,000 data points across the Amazon where illegal activity is occurring. This includes illegal mining and logging in 96 protected areas. Most of the illegal activity is taking place in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mineria.amazoniasocioambiental.org/&quot;&gt;Venezuela&lt;/a&gt; where there are a reported 1,899 data points documenting illegal mining or logging. Venezuela is followed by Brazil where 321 cases of illegal activity are recorded. In Ecuador, the number drops to 68, and in Peru, 24. For organizations, governments, or advocates looking to protect the Amazon, this digital tool seems like a blessing. Yet, based on my experience it’s unclear whether these information-streamlining tools are actually limiting illegal activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Alejandro Solis
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-tools-against-illegal-mining-and-logging-in-the-amazon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-tools-against-illegal-mining-and-logging-in-the-amazon.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Satellite</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20head%20shot-0bcd9c-d7d5b5.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>A Resolution to Support the Tech Sector Where We Need It Most</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 5, I posted the message below on Facebook to hold myself accountable to my New Year’s resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/hanson%20blog%20pic-3811e6.png&quot; alt=&quot;hanson blog pic-3811e6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple. I want tech businesses to grow and thrive in Nigeria &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of Lagos. I want to support someone who grew up in, works in, and wants to continue working in my hometown, Uyo. This is not just my resolution, but has been my life’s work since I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://starthub.com.ng/&quot;&gt;Start Innovation Hub&lt;/a&gt; five years ago. Start Innovation Hub is an ICT firm and innovation lab that works to expand the tech industry by supporting tech startups and talented individuals in Uyo. We build skills and connect entrepreneurs to economic opportunities, as well as support local businesses by developing software solutions. You can’t deny that the tech sector in Nigeria is growing rapidly, but the concentration of firms in Lagos means that places like Uyo are left behind. Through Start Innovation Hub, I hope to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nextdeegit/">Hanson Johnson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/a-resolution-to-support-the-tech-sector-where-we-need-it-most.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/5.%20uganda%20cookstoves%20study.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>The Four Rs: An Interview With the Lean Research Initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are huge fans of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research&quot;&gt;Lean Research&lt;/a&gt; initiative at DAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration&quot;&gt;Center for Digital Acceleration&lt;/a&gt;. I recently went to the Massachusetts Institute for Technology’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT D-Lab&lt;/a&gt; and sat with &lt;a href=&quot;https://d-lab.mit.edu/research/lean-research/lean-research-community&quot;&gt;Elizabeth, Kendra, and Kim&lt;/a&gt;, the team behind Lean Research, to learn more about the genesis of the initiative and what tools and resources they offer ICT4D practitioners eager to “right-size” their own research approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/the-four-rs-an-interview-with-the-lean-research-initiative.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI2%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Citizen-Centered Design and Frontier Insights in Kabul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Center for Digital Acceleration is excited to announce that we’re taking &lt;em&gt;MiMuni&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/munis-transparencia-gobierno-abierto/municipalidad-de-chiantla&quot;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; transparency and citizen participation application developed for Guatemalan municipalities, and replicating it for five municipalities in Afghanistan through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/afghanistan-strong-hubs-afghan-hope-and-resilience-shahar&quot;&gt;Strong Hubs for Afghan Hope and Resilience (SHAHAR)&lt;/a&gt; project, which is funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development. The first iteration will be with the Municipality of Kabul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI1%20(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FI1 (1).jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Frontier Insights in Kabul, part of DAI's citizen-centered design process.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/citizen-centered-design-and-frontier-insights-in-kabul-municipality.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Dashboard-b07795.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>6 Tips for Making Great Monitoring and Evaluation Dashboards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology and data are converging in ways that allow monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;amp;E) professionals to more effectively monitor, evaluate, learn, and adapt on their projects. Dashboards are one of the key tools contributing to this trend, having become more accessible and user friendly through platforms such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/get-started/?&amp;amp;OCID=AID719832_SEM_bHb24t0B&amp;amp;lnkd=Google_PowerBI_Brand&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw08XeBRC0ARIsAP_gaQBWS9woBxKkiDNWqYJ1QffUY7fpDoUDQTRkOS4N15amKTJGVg8EmGMaAkDrEALw_wcB&quot;&gt;Microsoft PowerBI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboards are an information management tool that visually track, analyze, and display metrics and data points to monitor the status of a project. DAI is creating dashboards for all new projects to enable teams to learn, evaluate, and adapt to project realities in near real-time. Ultimately, these dashboards make for better monitoring and evaluation and—in turn—better projects. Therefore, it’s important to get it right. So where should you start?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-mataya-6a53373/">John Mataya</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/6-tips-for-making-great-monitoring-and-evaluation-dashboards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/6-tips-for-making-great-monitoring-and-evaluation-dashboards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/FI%20hairi2.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Frontier Insights: Cyber Security Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The headline says it all: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/blog/biggest-data-breaches-2018/&quot;&gt;Over a billion people’s data was compromised in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.” Among the most egregious offenders were some of the most popular tech platforms in the world: Facebook, for example, admitted it had leaked the personal data of nearly 150 million users; Twitter leaked the passwords of nearly all 330 million of its users; and even mighty Google had two of its products hacked: Firebase (an app monitoring tool) leaked the data of more than 100 million users, and Google+ leaked 500,000 users’ personal info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cartography-3244166_640.png&quot; alt=&quot;cartography-3244166_640.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a> &amp; <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/kristen-roggemann/">Kristen Roggemann</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-cyber-security-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontier-insights-cyber-security-edition.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cyber Security Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/2019LookAhead.PNG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Looking Ahead: What We’re Thinking About in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In our last post, we reviewed our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-at-dai-year-in-review-top-10-posts-of-2018.html&quot;&gt;top posts of 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The most-read articles covered a lot of ground—from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/fortnite-for-international-development.html&quot;&gt;Fortnite for development&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-malawi-communication-among-rural-communities.html&quot;&gt;digital lives in rural Malawi&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/facebook-messenger-chatbot-1.html&quot;&gt;making your own chatbot&lt;/a&gt;. We equally expect 2019 to be full of interesting projects, engaging conversations with colleagues, and, as always, meaningful opportunities to keep learning and doing better, more impactful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few topics we’re thinking about as we dive into the year. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DAIGlobal&quot;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you want to collaborate as we explore where they’ll take us—and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai.us19.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9cb0638e1f8d7224ba7058efa&amp;amp;id=67e58edf98&quot;&gt;stay tuned to our blog&lt;/a&gt; for updates throughout the year!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 10:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Krista Baptista
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/looking-ahead-what-were-thinking-about-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
