<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 14:28:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 14:28:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/16697496505_648084a306_o.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How to Responsibly Invest in Digital Development During COVID-19 Response</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has shifted the world to increasingly rely on digital technology to survive. Children are using online platforms to learn. People are using digital payment software to send money to their loved ones, and local businesses are entering the digital space to deliver goods and services that are no longer offered in person.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 06:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rashel-rabinovich-b3469099?challengeId=AQEy5wdzmx-JvQAAAXTgVbP65l_jvqz9qhAPg2VLEh-mJiptq7ldu-geOmVCajVP-AEG4JeFys-mWPPY_42oRnAtXG1ro7U5CA&amp;submissionId=280315a5-13a4-3916-95b1-5178d9f80479">Rashel Rabinovich</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-responsibly-invest-in-digital-development-during-covid-19-response.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-to-responsibly-invest-in-digital-development-during-covid-19-response.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/SAblog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Development in Southern Africa: How SMEs Access Trade Data Amid COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In May, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/erica-behrens/&quot;&gt;Erica Behrens&lt;/a&gt; of DAI’s Center for Digital Acceleration, and I worked with the UK Foreign, Commonwealth &amp;amp; Development Office (FCDO)-funded Trade Forward Southern Africa project to map the use of digital communications (i.e. social media use, messaging apps, websites, mobile phones) for trade-related information amongst a sample of small and medium enterprises (SMEs) and other trade stakeholders across sectors in Southern Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 04:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-southern-africa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-development-in-southern-africa.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Ecosystems</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/chloemisblog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Management Information Systems at the Humanitarian-Social Protection Nexus, Part 2: Risks and Benefits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 and early 2020, DAI and our partner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cariboudigital.net/&quot;&gt;Caribou Digital&lt;/a&gt; worked closely with the former U.K. Department for International Development, now the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-development-office&quot;&gt;Foreign, Commonwealth &amp;amp; Development Office&lt;/a&gt;) to analyse identification and registration systems in protracted and recurrent crises. For those interested in reading more about the research, the report can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/bsic-MIS-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog—the second in the series—we will dig into data protection and the potential consequences of increasing centralisation. Through an assessment of the literature and existing practice, our research team found that implications of fragmented management information systems (MIS) can be grouped into the following thematic areas: political, protection, legal and ethical, commercial, and operational. As there are numerous risks and benefits of increased centralisation of MIS (our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-interoperability.html&quot;&gt;previous blog&lt;/a&gt; outlined some of the arguments), we cannot possibly provide an exhaustive list here. But in this post, we will give an overview of some of the considerations, including where care needs to be taken before proceeding; where the political economy must be assessed; and where more data needs to be collected.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-part-2-risks-and-benefits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-part-2-risks-and-benefits.html</guid>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>interoperability</category>
        
        <category>MIS</category>
        
        <category>humanitarian response</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/RFP_AfricaU_blog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Deadline Extended: Applications for Digital Trade and e-Commerce Technical Assistance for the African Union Commission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project has extended the deadline for proposals for a Digital Trade and e-Commerce Advisor to support the African Union (AU) Commission under its ProICT program activity (initial announcement &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-trade-and-e-commerce-technical-assistance-for-the-african-union-commission.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). ProICT is part of the Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership and is designed to fund intensive, dedicated policy, and regulatory engagements in the areas of telecommunications, internet, and ICT. This activity will provide technical assistance to the AU Commission’s Department of Trade and Industry on digital trade and e-commerce work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 14:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://manage.siteleaf.com/sites/568d4cf73aaede128400000b/collections/posts/new">Andrea Falso</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/deadline-extended-applications-for-digital-trade-and-e-commerce-technical-assistance-for-the-african-union-commission.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/deadline-extended-applications-for-digital-trade-and-e-commerce-technical-assistance-for-the-african-union-commission.html</guid>
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/smSUNTA.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Out of the Conference Room, into the Field: Hosting a Virtual Site Visit in Zambia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), project site visits are essential for country Missions around the world. Site visits are required as part of each Mission’s performance management and provide opportunities for staff to better understand each activity’s unique context and how local communities experience USAID support. This spring, the COVID-19 pandemic brought travel to a halt around the world. USAID project teams hustled to determine what essential activities could be continued safely, and what would have to be put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It quickly became clear that site visits could no longer take place. So how could projects—especially those in remote areas without reliable internet connectivity—replicate the important experience of visiting a project in the field?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 15:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/reginald-ntomba-621a9b130/?originalSubdomain=zm">Reginald Ntomba</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/out-of-the-conference-room-into-the-field-hosting-a-virtual-site-visit-in-zambia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/out-of-the-conference-room-into-the-field-hosting-a-virtual-site-visit-in-zambia.html</guid>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>ICT</category>
        
        <category>Virtual Workshops</category>
        
        <category>Digital</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Araba%20Blog%20-%20BLM.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Defining Digital Justice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;George Floyd. Breonna Taylor. Ahmaud Arbery. By now you know the story of the people behind these names and have learned about the violence that cut their lives short. You have heard their names cried out in the streets along with demands to dismantle systemic racism and you have witnessed how their untimely deaths launched a global &lt;strong&gt;conversation&lt;/strong&gt; about racism, justice, and the value of black lives. For many, these three names reinvigorated a hunger for social justice and kicked off months of protesting, donating, reading, and conversing through confusion, anger, guilt, hurt, and hope. With this &lt;strong&gt;historic and emotional summer drawing to a close&lt;/strong&gt;, I find myself wondering what will become of the hunger. As the shock and outrage subside, and corporate promises to “do better” ease mounting public pressure, I wonder how best to ensure this drive for social change lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Araba Sapara-Grant
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/defining-digital-justice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/defining-digital-justice.html</guid>
        
        <category>digital justice</category>
        
        <category>digital divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/HSNP%20finger%20prints-837a16.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Management Information Systems at the Humanitarian-Social Protection Nexus, Part 1: Interoperability</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 and early 2020, DAI and our partner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cariboudigital.net/&quot;&gt;Caribou Digital&lt;/a&gt; worked closely with the U.K. Department for International Development (now called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-development-office&quot;&gt;U.K. Foreign, Commonwealth, and Development Office&lt;/a&gt;) to analyse identification and registration systems in protracted and recurrent crises. The research explored the feasibility of designing humanitarian aid management information systems (MIS) to link with social protection systems and to support a transition, in the long-term, to state social assistance. Whilst the focus was principally on the interoperability of such systems, our legal, digital, and protection brains also pushed us to focus on the risks associated with data collection, sharing, and storage.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 04:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rachaelsteller/">Rachael Steller</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-interoperability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/management-information-systems-at-the-humanitarian-social-protection-nexus-interoperability.html</guid>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        <category>Electronic Cash Transfer</category>
        
        <category>Interoperability</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DRGRFAblog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Respond Now: USAID Seeks Research Expertise in Responding to Digital Threats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is issuing an expression of interest (EOI) to support the U.S. Agency for International Development’s (USAID) Democracy, Human Rights, and Governance (DRG) office’s Responding to Digital Threats Activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, digital tools increasingly are becoming irreplaceable assets for societies. While digital tools offer an unprecedented opportunity for vulnerable, underserved, and unserved populations to access information and services, they also expose people, organizations, and countries to risks—for instance, the incitement of ethnic cleansing in Myanmar through digital platforms like Facebook, the manipulation of electoral discourse through the spread of disinformation in places like Ukraine, Brazil, and Vietnam, and the reverberating effects of massive ransomware attacks felt in high, middle, and low-income countries alike. These trends pose a threat to rule-of-law, democratic process, and human rights worldwide. In particular, China is exporting to other countries an internet governance model that conflicts with U.S. values of promoting an open, interoperable, free, and secure internet and democratic norms.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 20:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-nicole-leg%C3%A9-5a111845/">Evan Lege</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-seeks-research-expertise-in-responding-to-digital-threats.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/respond-now-usaid-seeks-research-expertise-in-responding-to-digital-threats.html</guid>
        
        <category>Governance</category>
        
        <category>cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/RFP_AfricaU_blog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Digital Trade and e-Commerce Technical Assistance for the African Union Commission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is accepting proposals for a Digital Trade and e-Commerce Advisor to support the African Union (AU) Commission under its ProICT program activity. ProICT is part of the Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP) and is designed to fund intensive, dedicated policy and regulatory engagements in the areas of telecommunications, internet, and ICT. This activity will provide technical assistance to the African Union Commission’s Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) on digital trade and e-commerce work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 08:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-falso-99474a103/">Andrea Falso</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-trade-and-e-commerce-technical-assistance-for-the-african-union-commission.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-digital-trade-and-e-commerce-technical-assistance-for-the-african-union-commission.html</guid>
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/ericablog.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Information Liberation, Part 2: Bringing the Private Sector into the Movement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open-data sharing can offer huge benefits for development. How do we get the private sector to contribute?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog—&lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-what-is-open-data-and-why-does-it-matter.html&quot;&gt;Information Liberation: What is Open Data, and Why Does it Matter?&lt;/a&gt;—posted back in April, I wrote about the Open Data Movement, including its origins, advantages, and relevance to international development. The post referenced Microsoft’s announcement of its support for the movement, vowing to use the company’s resources to address the “data divide” that separates those with access to data and the ability to interpret it, from those without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With data comes power: the power to make better, smarter decisions; to use information to your advantage; to understand trends and predict future ones. No one knows this better than the private sector—experts in collecting, organizing, and interpreting data to improve business decisions and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 17:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Erica Behrens
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-part-2-bringing-the-private-sector-into-the-movement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/information-liberation-part-2-bringing-the-private-sector-into-the-movement.html</guid>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
