<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 15:58:45 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 15:58:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/pexels-sergio-souza-3907943%20(1).jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>How Can the Mexican Automotive Industry Capitalize on Data-Driven Global Value Chains?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smart factories could position Mexico as an Industry 4.0 hub and open doors to data-driven global value chains (GVCs).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mexico is embracing Industry 4.0. The digital factory in Puebla, the aerospace corridors in Querétaro, Guanajuato, Baja California, Sonora, Chihuahua, and Nuevo León showcase Industry 4.0 manufacturing throughout the country. Smart factories are facilities that primarily use automated tools and machines, from production robots to transportation devices or 3D printers. Products are equipped with sensors that allow them to connect and exchange data and communicate with each other. They make up a cyber-physical production system (CPPS) connected via the industrial Internet of Things (IoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data are the smart factory’s blood vessels and the key enabler of modern global value chains (GVCs). In the networked smart factory, identities can be assigned to tools, machines, products, and materials. Items at each level of the GVC can thereby be precisely located and tracked. This networked and automated production environment is supplemented with “big data” (huge amounts of data from millions of nodes within a network, including the ability to process and analyze large amounts of data using cloud computing, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning). Data can be handled, processed, and analyzed in real time and passed on through GVCs. Greater customization is possible while retaining speed and efficiency. Individual products are networked and identifiable; customization is possible by drawing on user data, while customer data is directly transferred to machine data. Cloud computing and additive manufacturing enable decentralized production.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mimistankovic/">Miriam Stankovich</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/agustin-filippo-3586814/">Agustin Filippo</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/how-can-the-mexican-automotive-industry-capitalize-on-data-driven-global-value-chains.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>industry 4.0</category>
        
        <category>Smart Factory</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Main%20Cover%202022%20Digis.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: 2022 USAID Digital Development Awards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you used digital technology to promote locally led development? Have you safeguarded digital ecosystems by facilitating access to digital infrastructure for marginalized populations, securing internet freedom and human rights, exposing violent extremism, countering misinformation and disinformation, or strengthening cybersecurity?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-c-creed/">Stephanie Creed</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-2022-usaid-digital-development-awards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Awards</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Digital Rights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Picture%20digital%20upskilling%20pwd.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Realizing Inclusive Digital Development Through Boosting the Digital Skills of People Living with Disabilities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five percent of the nearly 1 billion people living with disabilities around the world live at or below the poverty line. Unfortunately, these roughly 250 million people are more likely to face obstacles ranging from finding employment to outright discrimination. However, digital technologies offer the potential to expand employment opportunities for people living with disabilities, allowing them to realize their capabilities, expand their networks, and increase their mobility through digital accessibility. DAI, implementing activities under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/digital-connectivity-and-cybersecurity-partnership/&quot;&gt;Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership (DCCP)&lt;/a&gt;, is designing activities that create employment opportunities and support networks for people living with disabilities in countries such as Cambodia and India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its work with the Digital Asia Accelerator (DAA) and the South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI), DAI recognizes disability as a cross-cutting issue and strives to provide equitable access to digital tools for people with a wide array of abilities, including those who are hard of hearing, have visual impairments, speech impediments, or other learning, developmental, and psychosocial disabilities. DAI’s grantee organizations, consultants, and partners are making significant steps towards digital inclusion through the facilitation of trainings, workshops, and mentoring groups specifically targeted and tailored for people living with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-anderson-2b69391b6/">Jeremy Anderson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/realizing-inclusive-digital-development-through-boosting-the-digital-skills-of-people-living-with-disabilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/michal-dziekonski-21e67o9NxAA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Five Technology and Design Podcasts to Explore this Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the weather gets warmer in the Mid-Atlantic region, I’ve been doing my best to get outside more during the day. Podcasts have been a pleasant addition to my walk, runs, and bike rides. Below are five can’t-miss tech podcasts that you should follow—all of which are insightful, engaging, and informative.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/five-technology-and-design-podcasts-to-explore-this-summer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%204%20-%20Mali-health-soap-cooperative-hero.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 4—Designing Creative, Women-Centric Technology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Women Connect Challenge is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round of the Challenge, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole/">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-4-designing-creative-women-centric-technology.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-4-designing-creative-women-centric-technology.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Aerobotics%20drone-8057e3.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Q&amp;A: Drone Technology, Climate Adaptation, and Aerobotics—An Interview with Benji Meltzer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Benji%20Meltzer,%20Co-Founder%20and%20CTO%20of%20Aerobotics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Benji Meltzer, Co-Founder and CTO of Aerobotics.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benji Meltzer is the co-founder and chief technology officer of Aerobotics, a South African ag-tech startup that uses artificial intelligence to support the world’s agriculture industry—specifically, farmers in managing their farms, trees, and fruits. We recently spoke with Benji on Aerobotics’ drone technology, the impact of digital tools in climate adaptation and mitigation, and more. This is an excerpt from that interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 15:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julian-kesler/">Julian Kesler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-drone-technology-climate-adaptation-and-aerobotics-an-interview-with-benji-meltzer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/q-and-a-drone-technology-climate-adaptation-and-aerobotics-an-interview-with-benji-meltzer.html</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>AgTech</category>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Climate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/510e45ab-eb96-465c-a85b-eeb1e67d20e2.jfif" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now: Teach Digital Upskilling to Small Firms in Sri Lanka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;’ South Asia Regional Digital Initiative (SARDI) is seeking applications from organizations to provide cybersecurity capacity building to small- and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SARDI aims to increase the digital capacity of the private sector and civil society through digital upskilling and by strengthening firms’ ability to engage in digital and ICT policy issues. SARDI implements activities focused on digital upskilling, policy awareness, and cyber capacity-building with entrepreneurs and small firms across South Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermetkabylova/?originalSubdomain=kg">Bermet Kabylova</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-digital-upskilling-sri-lanka.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-sardi-sme-digital-upskilling-sri-lanka.html</guid>
        
        <category>SME</category>
        
        <category>RFA</category>
        
        <category>Cyber</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%203%20-%20Viamo.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 3—Cultivating Women’s Confidence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) Women Connect Challenge is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Strategy%203%20-%20Viamo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strategy 3 - Viamo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WCC Grantee Viamo works to bridge the gender digital divide and bring vital tools and information to women in Pakistan. Photo: Viamo.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-3-cultivating-womens-confidence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-3-cultivating-womens-confidence.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Jamie%20blog.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Getting Subnational: Combining Large Scale Surveys with Geospatial Data to Produce Better Small Area Estimation (Part I)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collecting granular location data on key socioeconomic indicators for strategic planning is an increasingly important topic in international development. Given the limitations of national-level data, many analysts and policymakers now focus on obtaining subnational data to identify pockets of poverty in a country, select priority sites for poverty alleviation programs, establish subnational benchmarks for monitoring and evaluation purposes, and cross-validate data collected by country governments on indicators such as child mortality and basic literacy rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Jamie%20blog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jamie blog.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 07:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Jamie Parr
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-subnational-combining-large-scale-surveys-with-geospatial-data-to-produce-better-small-area-estimation-part-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/getting-subnational-combining-large-scale-surveys-with-geospatial-data-to-produce-better-small-area-estimation-part-i.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data Visualization</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        <category>Geospatial Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Marketlinks%20piece.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>WomenConnect Challenge Blog Series: Strategy 2—Creating Economic Opportunities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is part of the WomenConnect Challenge (WCC) Blog Series: Introducing Strategies for Closing the Gender Digital Divide. The U.S. Agency for International Development &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenconnectchallenge.org/&quot;&gt;WomenConnect Challenge (WCC)&lt;/a&gt; is a global call for solutions to improve women’s participation in everyday life by meaningfully changing the ways women access and use technology. In the first round of the Challenge, WCC awarded nine grants to organizations working to identify and change the social and economic circumstances that keep women offline and under-empowered. Through close partnership with local awardee teams and community members, WCC has identified &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectchallenge.s3.amazonaws.com/media/uploads/proven_strategies_digitalgenderdivide_final.pdf&quot;&gt;five proven strategies&lt;/a&gt; for closing the gender digital divide and increasing women’s empowerment. This blog explores one strategy at length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no revelation that the global economy has been permanently digitized. Now, the internet is not just “the marketplace of ideas” but also the world’s largest marketplace of commodities, crafts, and services. Exclusion from this vast and dynamic market limits one’s opportunities in countless ways—socially and economically. Across the world, many women are unable to engage with the digital economy, and many “real life” economic opportunities—even those traditionally available to women—are moving online, rendering them inaccessible and necessitating new approaches to development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 11:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-poole">Kendra Poole</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-2-creating-economic-opportunities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/womenconnect-challenge-blog-series-strategy-2-creating-economic-opportunities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Challenges</category>
        
        <category>Digital Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
