<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 09:41:04 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 09:41:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/PhoneUse.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Open Source versus Proprietary Data Management Stack—Which One is Best for Your Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product development team, we spend a lot of time listening to the needs of users, particularly when it comes to their desire to collect and analyze data. And while projects have unique needs, they often ask for a common set of technology solutions. These include the ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Collect and manage data, often offline or online as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn as much as they can from their data, often through a series a dashboards or reports.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload products and share learnings with a public audience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintain an internal system for data sharing, so that people only have access to certain information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, these tools should be easy to use, and ideally not too expensive to build or maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are reasonable requests. If prioritized, organizations should be able to develop and maintain highly functional data management and analysis solutions. So why do so many organizations struggle to maintain these kinds of systems?
In this article, I’d like to outline two very different routes that organizations can take when trying to build out their systems: 1) completely proprietary solutions v. 2) open source technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;group-a-buy-it&quot;&gt;Group A: Buy It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve made the decision to buy the toolkit of your dreams. Maybe you purchased licenses to mobile data collection tools that run offline on both Android and iOS devices, and paid to have that data cleaned and migrated to a knowledge management system inside of Salesforce. Sure, Salesforce has built in dashboards, but you’re hoping to learn as much as you can from your data, so you’ve purchase Tableau licenses for your staff, and an ArcGIS license for your spatial analyst. And because you want to host your results online and share them with people, you’ve purchased a copy of Tableau Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve just exponentially upped your potential data management game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can build beautiful dashboards without having to keep a team of developers on staff.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If something breaks, you can rely on one of your vendors to investigate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Project management continues to be a priority over technology management.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You just spent hundreds of thousands of dollars on technology, and now you and your staff need to learn how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While you paid for licenses fees for your current staff, you may need to buy more if your organization grows.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if software is easy to use, it still requires maintenance, and you may now need to hire people just to manage these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With proprietary software, often what you see is what you get. While customizable, you’ll have to wait for the next software update to add that dual axis line chart to your report.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s possible that your data is in a system that only really talks to itself, and you don’t have a lot of control over how to get it out later.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your project comes to an end, you can’t hand over aspects of the system without finding funding for annual licenses fees.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/PhoneUse.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;PhoneUse.JPG&quot; /&gt;`A farmer in Central America using the Coffee Cloud application developed by CDA.`&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;group-b-build-it&quot;&gt;Group B: Build it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve made the decision to build your own or leverage open source tools as much as possible. To get started, you’ve installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/data-collection-with-opendatakit.html&quot;&gt;Open Data Kit&lt;/a&gt; (ODK) on cloud servers, and are running &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; with a series of Python scripts to move data around. The ODK graphs aren’t very sophisticated, so you’ve decided to build your dashboards in a couple of different ways. Maybe you have a web developer on staff who is ready to learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://d3js.org/&quot;&gt;D3&lt;/a&gt;, or you’ve learned or hired some R developers who can build you dashboards in &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiny.rstudio.com/&quot;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of ArcGIS, you’ve made use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://qgis.org/en/site/&quot;&gt;QGIS&lt;/a&gt; for spatial analysis and cartographic design. You have several servers running to host your dashboards, and are working your way through &lt;a href=&quot;https://httpd.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nginx.com/&quot;&gt;NGINX&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://oauth.net/&quot;&gt;OAuth&lt;/a&gt;, trying to get your dashboards shared discreetly across your users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-1&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve just exponentially upped your potential data management game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’re not paying license fees and can give people access to your system without paying for additional users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve hired seasoned analysts and developers to build your system, so your data analysis and reporting dashboards are put together by people trained in research methods and quantitative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve learned an absolute ton about technology, and there are no limitations to what your team can have assuming you have enough time to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons-1&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve just spent months of your life looking at documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every time something goes wrong, you and your team need to figure out how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ve become reliant on a whole series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_hell&quot;&gt;dependent packages&lt;/a&gt;, which leaves you at risk for system failure if someone creates a package update without your knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Technology keeps changing, so you often spend the weekend learning how to build something in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are now in a world where you manage technology as much as you manage your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflections&quot;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see from these two case studies, both Group A and Group B have come a long way on their data management journey, and each group is going to experience different challenges along the way. It’s hard to say who spent more money, as the Buy It group spent both time and lots of money on their software, while the Built It group had to hire some analysts and developers, each of whom spent quite a bit of time setting their systems up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-approach&quot;&gt;Our Approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a team, we’ve chosen to live somewhere between these two worlds, with a strong leaning towards the Build It camp. We do our best to leverage open source tools as much as possible, and when it makes sense, we have a team of developers who work in common web development framework (Python/Django). The proliferation of powerful business intelligence solutions means that we do use proprietary software, but when given the time we build dashboards in JavaScript, or by using the amazing R/Shiny framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we know is this – in data management, no matter how you approach the problem set, you’re either going to have to spend time and money on professional data management staff, or spend money on software. There’s no such thing as a free lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/convening%201-a4e466.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Power Beyond the Prize</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation recently hosted a convening between two sets of challenge prize winners: Feed the Future’s, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fallarmywormtech.challenges.org/&quot;&gt;Fall Armyworm Tech Prize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; finalists and the Grand Challenges Explorations (GCE)’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcgh.grandchallenges.org/challenge/tools-and-technologies-broad-scale-disease-surveillance-crop-plants-low-income-countries&quot;&gt;Tools and Technologies for Broad-Scale Pest and Disease Surveillance of Crop Plants in Low-Income Countries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcgh.grandchallenges.org/challenge/tools-and-technologies-broad-scale-disease-surveillance-crop-plants-low-income-countries&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;winners. The objective was to catalyze collaboration between the two groups of innovators working in digital agriculture, engineering, modeling, remote sensing, pathology, and chemistry for the benefit of farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/talia-dweck/">Talia Dweck</a> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/komal-bazaz-smith-3a56b5/">Komal Bazaz Smith</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/power-beyond-the-prize.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/power-beyond-the-prize.html</guid>
        
        <category>Co-creation</category>
        
        <category>Fall Armyworm</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID%20small-1-ab2324.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Identity Series Part 3: Barriers to Inclusion for All</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Digital%20ID%20small-1-97efcb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital ID small-1-97efcb.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;Any ID—whether state-issued or purpose-made for services such as cash transfers—in some way reflects levels of equality, whether these are inherent in the technology or prevalent in the social ecosystem. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Digital-identity-opportunities-for-women-Insights-from-Nigeria-Bangladesh-and-Rwanda-Web.pdf&quot;&gt;research from the GSM Association (GSMA)&lt;/a&gt; in Bangladesh, Nigeria, and Rwanda showed that citizens feel that equality in national ID is important as it reflects equality in citizenship status for men and women. If a biometric-based ID card is created in a refugee camp to facilitate cash transfers, every person living in that camp can rightfully expect to be registered regardless of age, gender, or ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We list a number of ways in which bias can manifest in digital identities to kick off some discussion and move toward solutions. While reading this, I encourage you to think how we can make sure digital ID systems are inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-3-digital-identity-and-exclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-identity-series-part-3-digital-identity-and-exclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Identity Series</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/iot-technology-concept-city-transport-smart-1575603-pxhere.com.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Changes in Open-Data Policy in Global Development are a Game Changer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You saw it coming. You’ve been collecting geospatial data on your projects for years. Maybe uploading it to a faraway server or sharing it with local partners…or stashing it away on your laptop or external hard drive. But no one else was ever able to use it. And you were sort of irritated that you had to ask a million people for the same data every time you started a new development project in a different country.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/carmen-tedesco">Carmen Tedesco</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/changes-in-open-data-policy-in-global-development-are-a-game-changer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/changes-in-open-data-policy-in-global-development-are-a-game-changer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/KICPaper.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building the Future of Tech-Enabled Agriculture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, Digital@DAI has kept its readers updated on the latest from the Kosmos Innovation Center (KIC) in Ghana, from young entrepreneurs’ agritech &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/catalyzing-ghanas-growing-agritech-ecosystem.html&quot;&gt;product concepts&lt;/a&gt; to international &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/kosmos-innovation-center-wins-2018-p3-impact-award.html&quot;&gt;awards&lt;/a&gt; it has received. In the three years since the KIC’s launch, funders of all sorts—from bilateral donors to corporate social investors—have embraced the potential of Africa’s growing startup ecosystem to support socio-economic development and create new solutions to some of the continent’s most persistent challenges. In that time, KIC and DAI have learned a lot about what it means to support youth-led technology entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve compiled our findings in the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/digital-acceleration-solutions/cda-insights&quot;&gt;CDA Insights&lt;/a&gt; paper titled, ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/uploads/kic-27672d.pdf&quot;&gt;Building the Future of Tech-Enabled Agriculture.&lt;/a&gt;’ In addition to providing lessons for both funders and implementers in this sector, we created profiles of select KIC entrepreneurs and captured their journeys.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Anand Varghese
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-cda-insights-publication-building-the-future-of-tech-enabled-agriculture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-cda-insights-publication-building-the-future-of-tech-enabled-agriculture.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cover1.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>El desarrollo de Coffee Cloud: Una herramienta de precisión utilizada por agricultores en la región centroamericana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is also available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durante más de un siglo, la roya ha representado una seria amenaza para la industria cafetalera mundial, especialmente en la era del cambio climático. No obstante, la toma de acciones eficaces y de forma coordinada entre los países centroamericanos productores de café ha sido una tarea difícil de lograr. En consecuencia, esta enfermedad ha continuado propagándose y sus efectos han sido devastadores. Entre 2012 y 2013, la roya ocasionó que la región centroamericana experimentara una reducción del 15 por ciento de su producción de café, lo que incluyó un alarmante 31 por ciento en Honduras. El gráfico siguiente muestra las pérdidas que experimentó cada país durante este período.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 13:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a> y <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>diseño centrado en el humano</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cover1.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Building Coffee Cloud: A Precision Ag Tool Used by Farmers Across Central America</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Esta entrada también está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/el-desarrollo-de-coffee-cloud-una-herramienta-de-precision.html&quot;&gt;español&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee rust has menaced the global coffee industry for more than a century, but particularly in the era of climate change. Nevertheless, effective, coordinated action between coffee producing countries across Central America has remained elusive, and as a result the disease has spread—to devastating effect. In 2012 and 2013, coffee rust reduced the region’s coffee production by 15 percent, including a staggering 31 percent in Honduras. The figure below shows the losses each country suffered during that season.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/adam-fivenson/">Adam Fivenson</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/Tepmachcha%20flood%20early%20warning.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>You Keep Using That Word: Why “Scale” Doesn’t Mean What You Think It Means</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Merriam-Webster Dictionary offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/scale&quot;&gt;seven&lt;/a&gt; definitions of “scale,” involving variously weight, fish, climbing, maps, music, and—unexpectedly—lumber. Notably, none of these meanings is a synonym for “to embiggen,” the usage favored in the tech and development worlds. In these environments, which share little else, taking something “to scale” always seems to evoke Carl Sagan-esque notions of quantity. What this reductionist approach to vocabulary loses (in addition to small stiff plates that cover much of the body of some animals) is the range that makes this word truly useful. In English, if not in Silicon Valley, you can scale &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt;, but you can also scale &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Rob Ryan-Sylva
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/you-keep-using-that-word-why-scale-doesnt-mean-what-you-think-it-means.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/you-keep-using-that-word-why-scale-doesnt-mean-what-you-think-it-means.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/nigeria%20pic-941182.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Access for All in a Digital Economy: A Reflection on DAI Development Matters Roundtables in Nigeria</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The technology revolution in Nigeria is remarkable compared to other countries in Africa (the country completely skipped the landline stage of development!). As one of the top destinations for investment in Africa, Nigeria is home to booming tech startups that provide a collaborative environment for entrepreneurs across sectors. Powered by the Nigerian government’s commitment to digital access, the digital ecosystem in Nigeria is likely to evolve further. Within this context, &lt;a href=&quot;http://&quot;&gt;DAI’s office in Nigeria&lt;/a&gt; recently hosted two roundtables—one in Lagos and one in Abuja, both featuring insights from DAI’s Vice President of Technical Services, Brigit Helms, who recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/news/access-for-all-dais-brigit-helms-launches-her-new-book-on-economic-inclusion&quot;&gt;“Access for All: Building Inclusive  Economic Systems.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="/authors/talia-dweck/">Talia Dweck</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chidera-agwu/">Chidera Agwu</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/access-for-all-in-a-digital-economy-a-reflection-on-dai-development-matters-roundtables-in-nigeria.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/access-for-all-in-a-digital-economy-a-reflection-on-dai-development-matters-roundtables-in-nigeria.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/WomenConnect%20logo%202.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Apply Now to the Women’s Global Development and Prosperity Initiative WomenConnect Challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital technology has revolutionized the world by providing instant access to information, finance, and networks—all of which are necessary for women to reach their full economic potential and create more self-reliant communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, 1.7 billion women in low- and middle-income countries still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/GSMA_The_Mobile_Gender_Gap_Report_2018_32pp_WEBv7.pdf&quot;&gt;do not own mobile phones&lt;/a&gt;. The internet user gender gap is greater than 40 percent in some countries. The persistent gender digital divide is reinforcing—and even exacerbating—existing socioeconomic gaps between men and women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advancing women’s digital connectivity is key to promoting their empowerment in an increasingly digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 08:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Alana McGinty
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-womenconnect-challenge-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-womenconnect-challenge-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
