<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:33:04 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:33:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAI00418.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Navigating Barriers to Digital Inclusion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first began learning about digital development, I thought of it as the new frontier of development. A frontier that could push international development out of its modus operandi by providing individuals, communities, governments, and organizations with access to new sources of information at rapid speeds, enabling new means of collaboration to propel development objectives forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital technology is unique for two reasons. First, digital is &lt;em&gt;informative&lt;/em&gt;—providing users with increased access to new information and opportunities at their fingertips. Second, digital is &lt;em&gt;informed&lt;/em&gt;—enabling users to input information that will conceivably be used by industries and governments to tailor and update their products and benefit their business and economies to improve their customers’ experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;–!more–&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this virtuous circle is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/coffee-cloud-precision-ag-at-the-touch-of-a-button.html&quot;&gt;Coffee Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, an application DAI developed in collaboration with coffee producers, government institutions, and research institutes in response to a decline in coffee production in Central America. Coffee producers input specific information about their crops into the app (&lt;em&gt;digital informed&lt;/em&gt;) and receive customized advice to improve crop management; this information is shared with other coffee farmers as well as the government coffee institute and meteorological services (&lt;em&gt;digital informative&lt;/em&gt;), which in return use the information for predictive modeling that can then be shared back to coffee producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-realities-of-digital&quot;&gt;The Realities of Digital&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While digital development has the potential to transform industries such as coffee and alter the status quo, the more I engage with digital the more I’ve come to see it as an instrument of development. Digital cannot magically leapfrog all the underlying economic dynamics, social norms, and barriers preventing people in developing countries from accessing vital services or improving their economic situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DAI00418.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;DAI00418.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Employees are trained by the Haiti Health Information Systems project. Photo: DAI.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at gender inclusion, or lack thereof, as an example. When you look at global levels of mobile phone access, a common metric for measuring digital inclusion worldwide, it’s clear that more women lack access to mobile phones than men. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/blog/the-mobile-gender-gap-report-2019/&quot;&gt;GSMA 2019 Mobile Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt;, women are 10 percent less likely than men to own a mobile phone (28 percent less in South Asia where the gender gap is the highest) and 23 percent less likely than men to use the mobile internet. Furthermore, the report cites the largest barriers for women are affordability, digital literacy, and perceived lack of relevance, meaning that information is not targeted to their needs and thus they are not compelled to digitally engage. All this is to say, as the world shifts increasingly into the digital space, so too have the gender barriers that have prevented women from contributing to their households, communities, and economies for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;barriers&quot;&gt;Barriers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently visited DAI’s project team is digitizing Haiti’s health systems (through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/haiti-strategic-health-information-system-his-program&quot;&gt;Strategic Health Information System Program&lt;/a&gt;), through the National Unified Health Information System (SISNU) and funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development. The team works with the Ministry of Health and Finance to digitize public and private clinics across the country, enabling staffers to input patient information, track and monitor instances of tuberculosis, HIV, and other diseases, and improve treatment and care. When considering the project goals, the team considered: how do we disaggregate data between men and women? Can the data help analyze how men and women are treated by location? Can disease prevalence, treatment, or visit frequency data be broken out and analyzed by gender? And, what is done with the information?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conversations with the team, I learned that the project has several deliverables focused on gender integration and many of the indicators are indeed disaggregated by sex. While this is critical, getting buy-in from governments and institutions to implement gender-inclusive activities remains a challenge. Even though digital technologies empower the government to access and centralize information from health clinics across Haiti—&lt;em&gt;which is momentous on its own right&lt;/em&gt;—age-old social norms can still hinder true change of equitable access to healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can be done? Social norms, like gender roles, are complex, and digital development provides us with access to new means of communication and sources of data that can help us tell a deeper story. What we choose to learn from and do with that information is powerful and can inform how we develop new technologies, implement policies, distribute resources, and engender inclusive platforms. In the case of health data, disaggregating and reporting on woman’s healthcare experiences in comparison to men’s can be the first step to changing these norms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-magid/">Ariel Magid</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/navigating-barriers-to-digital-inclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/navigating-barriers-to-digital-inclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/DSC_0061.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Understanding Cybersecurity for Healthcare Professionals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in exciting times. The ways in which we store and engage with health data have been transformed with the creation and adoption of digital health technology. Whether it’s using a Fitbit, accessing your vaccine records online, or virtually connecting with your doctor, understanding your health status in real time has never been easier… for some of us. We at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/solutions/global-health&quot;&gt;DAI Global Health&lt;/a&gt; are working tirelessly to increase access to healthcare in low- and middle-income countries by leveraging digital health technologies. The goal is to empower patients and professionals providing care to them to use data to make smart decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/rachel-clad/">Rachel Clad</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-for-health-professionals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-for-health-professionals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Health</category>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        <category>Global Health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/digital-identity-usaid.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>New USAID Guide: How to Create Digital ID for Inclusive Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.usaid.gov%2Fdigital-development%2Fdigital-id%2Fhow-to-guide&amp;amp;data=01%7C01%7CStephanie_Creed%40dai.com%7C1f9cda42f7114bd429d508d71147871e%7C7107113de20b4c20a4ce553cabbf686d%7C0&amp;amp;sdata=hn%2F6OZETU58OZUX59RCvfLdR8UywARdX66Or14vgUok%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;Guide to Creating Digital ID for Inclusive Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity is deeply personal. Issues of identity are complex and tied up with power, privacy, and protection. Yet identifying constituents is often critical to organizing and managing global development projects. Decades of development work have relied on ad hoc identity systems to administer programs, yet today we find that nearly 1 billion people still lack representative identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USAID’s 2017 report &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/15396/IDENTITY_IN_A_DIGITAL_AGE.pdf&quot;&gt;Identity in a Digital Age: Infrastructure for Inclusive Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; documented some of the complexities that arise when we create or use digital ID in development programming. Done well, these systems can provide a unique, trusted, multipurpose ID to everyone, which is key to economic and social development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrissiy/">Chrissy Martin Meier</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shachee-doshi-47358a56/">Shachee Doshi</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/new-usaid-guide-how-to-create-digital-id-for-inclusive-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/new-usaid-guide-how-to-create-digital-id-for-inclusive-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Identity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cs1-9318e9.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Карти, гроші, VPN: кібербезпекові реалії в Україні</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this blog in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cупротив та неузгодженість — напевне, той асоціативний ряд, який спадає на думку, коли уявляємо, що в одній кімнаті мають зустрітися державні управлінці, громадський сектор та представники бізнесу для обговорення тонкощів кібербезпеки. Проте, на Cyber Security Day - серії подій, які команда SocialBoost нещодавно організувала з новим партнером DAI, нам вдалося досягти абсолютно іншого ефекту.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://ua.linkedin.com/in/denisgursky">Denis Gursky</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/cs1.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Cybersecurity Lessons from Ukraine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this blog in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/uroki-kibierbiezpieki-z-ukrayini.html&quot;&gt;Ukrainian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you walk into a room full of government officials, civil society organizations, and private companies discussing cybersecurity, you expect to hear disagreement. The exact opposite happened during the recent DAI- &lt;a href=&quot;http://socialboost.com.ua/&quot;&gt;SocialBoost&lt;/a&gt; Cybersecurity Roundtable and Workshop in Kyiv, Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event started with a panel discussion with representatives from a myriad of government institutions working to address Ukraine’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.eu/article/ukraine-cyber-war-frontline-russia-malware-attacks/&quot;&gt;cybersecurity challenges&lt;/a&gt;. Representatives came from the Ministry of Energy, the Pension Fund of Ukraine, State Service of Special Communications and Information Protection of Ukraine, the Presidential Administration, Ministry of Infrastructure, and National Information Systems. Joining them were representatives from the company Information Systems Security Partners (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.issp.com/&quot;&gt;ISSP&lt;/a&gt;) and the law firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://sk.ua/&quot;&gt;Sayenko Kharenko&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://ua.linkedin.com/in/denisgursky">Denis Gursky</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cybersecurity-lessons-from-ukraine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/LatifaYari.jpg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Digital Gender Divide: Latifa Yari's Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me introduce you to Latifa Yari, a 24-year-old student who will graduate from the Niger &lt;a href=&quot;http://estniger.net/&quot;&gt;Higher School of Telecommunications&lt;/a&gt; (E.S.T.) this year with a degree in computer science. In 2018, Latifa won the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.girlsinict.rw/missgeekafrica&quot;&gt;Miss Geek Africa&lt;/a&gt;* competition with an app called Saro (“security” in Hausa) that connects emergency response services to citizens who have been in accidents. After that win, she founded the startup InnovElle, to develop digital social solutions and coach girls and women in digital technology. Latifa’s accomplishments are impressive and in the context of Niger, where there is a large digital gender divide, they are astounding. This is why during a recent trip to Niger I reached out to Latifa (thanks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/latifa-yari-57460b161/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn!&lt;/a&gt;) to learn her story.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alana-mcginty-04a91657/">Alana McGinty</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-gender-divide-latifa-yaris-story.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-gender-divide-latifa-yaris-story.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Gender Divide</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/https___blogs-images.forbes.com_tatianakoffman_files_2019_06_libra-logo-1200x900.png" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Facebook’s Libra Currency: A Digital Development Perspective</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When Facebook announced its first foray into the digital financial space with its new digital currency &lt;a href=&quot;https://libra.org/en-US/white-paper/&quot;&gt;Libra&lt;/a&gt; last month, the digital development community collectively sighed and Twitter lit up with both praise and concern. While it’s easy to get out the pitchforks for something like this—and in many ways rational, given how Facebook was manipulated to exacerbate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/06/technology/myanmar-facebook.html&quot;&gt;Rohingya crisis&lt;/a&gt;, used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/cambridge-analytica-facebook-privacy-awakening/&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;, and part of a myriad of other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/timeline-facebook-s-privacy-issues-its-responses-n859651&quot;&gt;breaches&lt;/a&gt; of trust in which Facebook has proven itself a questionable steward of its self-built digital nation—I’m not going to take a side on whether Libra is good or bad. Rather, in this blog, I will lay out some key questions and considerations that need to be fully addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Kristen Roggemann
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/facebooks-libra-currency-a-digital-development-perspective.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/facebooks-libra-currency-a-digital-development-perspective.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GSMA.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Mobile Technologies Push Latin America Forward</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Esta entrada también está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html&quot;&gt;Español&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital ecosystem in Latin America is pushing countries to accelerate public-private collaboration on digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobile360series.com/latin-america/agenda/&quot;&gt;GSMA Mobile 360 LATAM conference&lt;/a&gt;, we heard a lot about how 5G networks will bring about a technological, economic, and social revolution around the world. Many speakers—including GSMA CEO Mats Granryd—urged authorities and industry representatives to work jointly to accelerate the adoption of 5G networks in the region so that Latin America is not left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> and <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Internet of Things</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/GSMA.jpeg" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Las Tecnologías Móviles Empujan a América Latina Hacia Adelante</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is also available in &lt;a href=&quot;dai-global-digital.com/mobile-technologies-push-latin-america-forward.html&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El ecosistema digital en la región de América Latina está presionando a los países para acelerar la colaboración público-privada en la transformación digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En la &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobile360series.com/latin-america/agenda/&quot;&gt;conferencia Mobile 360 LATAM de GSMA&lt;/a&gt;, escuchamos constantemente cómo se espera que las redes 5G traigan una revolución tecnológica, económica y social en todo el mundo. La pregunta fue planteada por muchos oradores, entre ellos Mat Granryd, CEO de GSMA, quien instó a las autoridades y la industria a trabajar conjuntamente para acelerar la adopción de redes 5G en la región para que América Latina no se quede atrás.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/galia-nurko/">Galia Nurko</a> y <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/alejandro-solis/">Alejandtro Solis</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/las-tecnologias-moviles-empujan-a-america-latina-hacia-adelante.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Internet of Things</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <media:content url="https://dai-global-digital.com/uploads/PhoneUse.JPG" medium="image" /> 
        <title>Open Source Versus Proprietary Data Management Stack—Which One is Best for Your Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product development team, we spend a lot of time listening to the needs of users, particularly when it comes to their desire to collect and analyze data. And while projects have unique needs, they often ask for a common set of technology solutions. These include the ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Digitally collect and manage data - offline or online as mobile bandwidth permits.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn as much as they can from their data, often through a series a dashboards or reports.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload products and share learnings with a public audience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintain an internal system for data sharing, so that people only have access to certain information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, these tools should be easy to use, and ideally not too expensive to build or maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are reasonable requests. If prioritized, organizations should be able to develop and maintain highly functional data management and analysis solutions. So why do so many organizations struggle to maintain these kinds of systems?
In this article, I’d like to outline two very different routes that organizations can take when trying to build out their systems: 1) completely proprietary solutions v. 2) open source technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/open-source-vs-proprietary-data-management-stack-which-one-is-right-for-your-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open Source Series</category>
        
        <category>Data Management Series</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
