<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital@DAI</title>
    <description>The Digital for Development field has enormous potential—and plenty of room for learning. We launched this blog as part of our own learning process, and we hope to engage the Digital for Development community as we find our way forward</description>
    <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://dai-global-digital.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 14:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 14:33:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apply Now: RFP for an Innovative Partner to Fight Fall Armyworm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, DAI releases a request for proposals for a prize implementation partner to confront fall armyworm head on. This partner will join DAI and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) in designing a results-driven prize to find digital tools and services that help smallholder farmers across sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34880771941_a99698095a_z-089e50.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A farmer in Ethiopia inspects his fall armyworm-infested maize. (Photo Credit: FAO/Tamiru Legesse)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-a-little-background&quot;&gt;First, A Little Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the fall armyworm is marching across the African continent, causing more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cabi.org/Uploads/isc/Dfid%20Faw%20Inception%20Report04may2017final.pdf&quot;&gt;$13 billion&lt;/a&gt; in crop losses. If left unchecked, this insect could continue to cost &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2017/oct/25/invasion-of-maize-eating-caterpillars-worsens-hunger-crisis-in-africa-fall-armyworm&quot;&gt;$6 billion&lt;/a&gt; a year. What makes this pest so devastating to farmers across the region? First of all, it not only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/africa-in-focus/2017/06/07/fall-armyworm-outbreaks-in-the-sadc-region-how-to-respond/&quot;&gt;eats&lt;/a&gt; the vegetative parts of the plants, but also consumes the reproductive portions, completely destroying crops. Secondly, it can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/africa-in-focus/2017/06/07/fall-armyworm-outbreaks-in-the-sadc-region-how-to-respond/&quot;&gt;fly&lt;/a&gt; up to 1,600 kilometers (nearly 1,000 miles), meaning it can easily migrate to surrounding farms and countries. Finally, the insect &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cimmyt.org/press_release/multi-pronged-approach-key-for-effectively-defeating-fall-armyworm-in-africa/&quot;&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt; more than 80 plant species, including maize, which more than 200 million people across sub-Saharan Africa depend upon. Basically, this insect eats fast, travels far, and poses a critical threat to Africa’s food security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, USAID is launching a call for innovative, digital solutions to help smallholder farmers confront fall armyworm and protect their crops. To support this call, DAI’s USAID-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/worldwide-digital-frontiers-df&quot;&gt;Digital Frontiers&lt;/a&gt; project is looking for a prize implementation firm to design, launch, implement, and evaluate a results-driven prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-know&quot;&gt;What to Know&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prize launch:&lt;/strong&gt; Early 2018&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline for proposals:&lt;/strong&gt; January 5, 2018, at 5 p.m. EST&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; DigitalFrontiers@dai.com&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimated award:&lt;/strong&gt; Between $645,000 and $745,000&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/bdk9jR&quot;&gt;See the full RFP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-should-apply&quot;&gt;Who Should Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for an experienced open innovation competition firm to run this prize from start to finish. The ideal partner has wide range of experience, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designing open innovation competitions with USAID&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Working in developing country contexts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designing and running a communications and outreach campaign&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Managing events&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-next&quot;&gt;What Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/bdk9jR&quot;&gt;RFP&lt;/a&gt;. Have the expertise we’re looking for? All applications are due January 5 at 5 p.m. EST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for other ways to help us confront the fall armyworm threat head on? Please share &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/bdk9jR&quot;&gt;the RFP&lt;/a&gt; with your networks and encourage interested firms to apply. Also, make sure to follow @FeedtheFuture for the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="mailto:DigitalFrontiers@dai.com">Yasmine Williams</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-rfp-for-an-innovative-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/apply-now-rfp-for-an-innovative-partner-to-fight-fall-armyworm.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agriculture</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Geekfest2017: A Discussion with Cassandra Mickish Gross</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to GeekFest 2017, a series of interviews featuring ICT4D thought leaders. Our goals for our #geekfest2017 interviews are 1. to highlight the people and organizations who are pushing the field in new directions, 2. feature their work and show how it’s different or new, and 3. to support the overall growth of the ICT4D community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Cassandra%20Mickish%20Gross%20Headshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cassandra Mickish Gross Headshot.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;
This week I’m speaking with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/blog/authors/cassandra-mickish&quot;&gt;Cassandra Mickish Gross&lt;/a&gt; from the Johns Hopkins Center for Communication Programs to discuss the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/&quot;&gt;Knowledge for Health Project&lt;/a&gt;. In this post Cassandra reflects on her experience developing a digital health platform. We explore the choice between an established solution with the potential to scale, versus one that has clear evidence of impact on health outcomes. During the interview, she reflects on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.k4health.org/projects/sub-saharan-africa&quot;&gt;Faster to Zero Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, implemented in partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;http://healthenabled.org/wordpress/&quot;&gt;HealthEnabled&lt;/a&gt;, that aims to support the Ministries of Health of South Africa and Uganda in the scale-up of digital health tools and accelerate the elimination of mother-to-child transmission of HIV.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 14:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Talia Dweck
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest2017-a-discussion-with-cassandra-mickish-gross.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/geekfest2017-a-discussion-with-cassandra-mickish-gross.html</guid>
        
        <category>Geekfest 2017</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Key Takeaways From Our London Digital Inclusion Event</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, we were joined by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panoplydigital.com/our-team/#/alex-tyers-2/&quot;&gt;Alex Tyers&lt;/a&gt; of Panoply Digital, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/saloni-korlimarla-5102685&quot;&gt;Saloni Korlimarla&lt;/a&gt; of the Cherie Blair Foundation (CBF) for Women, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/author/guillaume-touchard&quot;&gt;Guillaume Touchard&lt;/a&gt; from the GSM Association (GSMA)’s Connected Society Team at the delightful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makersacademy.com/&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; space in Shoreditch, United Kingdom, to discuss, debate, and engage around the challenges and opportunities for increasing digital inclusion and access.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 04:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/krista-baptista/">Krista Baptista</a>, <a href="https://dai-global-digital.com/authors/chloe-messenger/">Chloe Messenger</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/frontiers-in-digital-inclusion-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/frontiers-in-digital-inclusion-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DAI Launches 'Lean HCD: A Case Study in Human-Centered Design in the Highlands of Guatemala'</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/HCD%20cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HCD cover.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today DAI launches &lt;strong&gt;Lean HCD: A Case Study in Human-Centered Design in the Highlands of Guatemala&lt;/strong&gt;. This landmark report is the culmination of 18 months of close collaboration between DAI’s ICT team, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/guatemala-nexos-locales&quot;&gt;USAID Nexos Locales&lt;/a&gt; project, and the people of Chiantla, a municipality in the Western Highlands of Guatemala, to design a tool for budget transparency and citizen engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/hcd.pdf&quot;&gt;Download Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 17:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-launches-human-centered-design-whitepaper.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/dai-launches-human-centered-design-whitepaper.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tailored Technology Enhances Resilience Programming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;FHI360 recently hosted its annual Technology for Resilience workshop in Bangkok. In doing so, conference organizers created an opportunity for technologists and development practitioners to learn from active technology projects that promote community resilience, and work together on innovative solutions to what are often seen as intractable problems. In this post, I’ll look at some of the technologies showcased during the conference. But before doing so, let’s define resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Tech%20for%20Resilience%20Poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tech for Resilience Poster.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Greg Maly
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-technology-and-resilience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/reflections-on-technology-and-resilience.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
        <category>Resilience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyber Violence Against Women and Girls Exacerbates Digital Exclusion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Raise your hand if you have experienced online harassment. I am sure the response is a virtual flurry. Although digital technologies have the ability to empower, connect, and liberalise, they can also serve as platforms for marginalisation and abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent news stories such as those from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2017/sep/05/diane-abbott-more-abused-than-any-other-mps-during-election&quot;&gt;UK General Election&lt;/a&gt; have shone a light on the targeting of female politicians and journalists and high-profile cases of cyber bullying of young girls have shocked people world over. Whilst we know well the veracity of online violence, a less prominent issue is how it can exacerbate levels of digital exclusion for already marginalised populations. Let’s take a look at how online violence against women and girls—or “cyber VAWG”—further impedes digital inclusion and prevents women and girls from enjoying digital dividends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Cambodia%20DI%201-c83e49.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cambodia DI 1-c83e49.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Photo from the USAID Development Innovations Cambodia project.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 06:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Chloe Messenger
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-vawg-what-are-the-implications-for-digital-inclusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/cyber-vawg-what-are-the-implications-for-digital-inclusion.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Inclusion</category>
        
        <category>Think Piece</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Podcasts for Human-Centered Designers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In international development, human-centered designer (HCD) is charged with rapidly developing empathy with a specific, targeted marginalized population, a social challenge that group faces, and parlaying that understanding into a local solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/headphones.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;headphones.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so successfully requires one primary skill: &lt;strong&gt;listening.&lt;/strong&gt; That means listening in the traditional sense: to an individual, as DAI does in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://dai-global-digital.com/rwanda-digital-insights.html&quot;&gt;Digital Insights&lt;/a&gt; work. But, more broadly, listening for design in the international development space means listening to an entire population to identify social challenges as well as the cultural, political, and economic dynamics that affect them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The podcasts below are all about people who know how to listen. They’ve expanded my understanding of design and sharpened my ability to listen closely when I’m designing a solution. I hope they’ll do the same for you, should you take the time to &lt;em&gt;listen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Adam Fivenson
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/5-podcasts-for-human-centered-designers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/5-podcasts-for-human-centered-designers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Human-centered design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Insights: Would Haitians use Mobile Money for Banking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In late September, I traveled to Haiti to conduct research on how Haitians engage with financial institutions and mobile technology to explore the feasibility of introducing mobile money as an avenue for the provision of financial services. Together with the team from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/our-work/projects/haiti-finance-inclusive-fininc&quot;&gt;USAID/Haiti Finance Inclusive project&lt;/a&gt;, implemented by DAI, and with support from our sister USAID/Haiti project Finance Pour Tous and two key credit unions—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/CPFRATERNITE/&quot;&gt;Caisse Populaire Fraternite (CPF)&lt;/a&gt; and Socolavim—I visited nine locations through the northern and central provinces of the country to interview 181 credit union customers as they went about their business.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 09:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-would-haitians-use-mobile-money-for-banking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/digital-insights-would-haitians-use-mobile-money-for-banking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Digital Insights</category>
        
        <category>Digital Financial Services</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why a Dashboard Isn’t Just a Dashboard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember an early conversation with colleagues when I began working in digital development in which a peer dismissively waved his hand at the idea of implementing a live data dashboard, saying “A dashboard is a dashboard is a dashboard!” The finality of that line stuck with me. I assumed that the dismissal came from a person who was bored with dashboards, like a kid who opens a birthday present to find he has received yet ANOTHER dashboard. Well, interactive data dashboards—just like automobile dashboards—may not be the newest, hottest, shiniest thing in the ICT4D toolbox, but they’re still important and their often hidden values go unappreciated by many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dashboards.png&quot; alt=&quot;dashboards-81776e&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 14:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <author>Karim Bin-Humam
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/why-a-dashboard-isnt-just-a-dashboard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/why-a-dashboard-isnt-just-a-dashboard.html</guid>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Do’s and Don’ts in Adaptive Management and Learning in ICT4D</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler&quot;&gt;Kate Heuisler&lt;/a&gt;, Chief of Party of DAI’s USAID-funded Cambodia Development Innovations project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.development-innovations.org/&quot;&gt;Development Innovations&lt;/a&gt; supports innovators and boosts the use of information and communication technologies for the overall development of Cambodia. The project is structured to be flexible and adaptive—because we need to. Really, most creative development programs &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; build themselves to be learning organizations, to be ready for big pivots, regardless if you and your partners use digital innovations. The development world is regularly disrupted—by political changes, natural disasters, new technologies such as social media—and is no longer built for static, five-year plans. Donors and funders need partners that can learn by doing, and are not afraid to adapt strategies and implementation plans to continually improve.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 10:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <author><a href="https://www.dai.com/who-we-are/our-team/kate-heuisler">Kate Heuisler</a>
</author>
        <link>https://dai-global-digital.com/adaptive-management-and-learning-in-ict4d-dos-and-donts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dai-global-digital.com/adaptive-management-and-learning-in-ict4d-dos-and-donts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Innovation</category>
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
